<title>GT 4.0: System Administrator's Guide</title>
<titleabbrev>System Administrator's Guide</titleabbrev>

<section id="s-csf-admin-introduction"><title>Introduction</title>
<para>This guide contains advanced configuration information for system administrators
  working with WS MDS Aggregator. It provides references to information on procedures
  typically performed by system administrators, including installation, configuring,
deploying, and testing the installation.</para>
<para>This information is in addition to the basic installation instructions in
  the <ulink url="http://www-unix.globus.org/toolkit/docs/development/4.0-drafts/admin/docbook/">GT 4.0 System Administrator's Guide</ulink>.</para>
</section>


<section id="s-csf-admin-installing"><title>Building and installing</title>
<para>[provide information about building and installing this component (that is
  in addition to the default installation instructions in the <ulink url="http://www-unix.globus.org/toolkit/docs/development/4.0-drafts/admin/docbook/">GT
  4.0 System Administrator's Guide</ulink>).  If no further information is necessary,
  please state as much.]</para>
</section>


<section id="s-csf-admin-configuring"><title>Configuring </title>
<para>[provide information on configuration settings and environment variables  specific
  to this component (that is in addition to any such information in the <ulink url="http://www-unix.globus.org/toolkit/docs/development/4.0-drafts/admin/docbook/">GT
4.0 System Administrator's Guide</ulink>).  If no further information is necessary,
please state as much.]</para>
</section>


<section id="s-csf-admin-deploying"><title>Deploying</title>
<para>[provide information about deploying this component into various containers/environments
  (that is in addition to any such information in the <ulink url="http://www-unix.globus.org/toolkit/docs/development/4.0-drafts/admin/index.html">GT
  4.0 System Administrator's Guide</ulink>). If no further information is necessary,
  please state as much.] </para>
</section>


<section id="s-csf-admin-testing"><title>Testing</title>
<para>[include procedures for how to test the configuration. must include examples
  of the tests ]</para>
</section>


<section id="s-csf-admin-security_considerations"><title>Security considerations</title>
<para><emphasis>Note to writer:</emphasis> do not edit this section - the Security_Considerations_Frag.html
  is embedded below. </para>

&CSF_Security_Considerations_Frag;

</section>


<section id="s-csf-admin-troubleshooting"><title>Troubleshooting</title>
<para>[provide help for common problems sysadmins may experience with this component] </para>
</section>

