<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd"
[

<!ENTITY % xinclude SYSTEM "../../../xinclude.mod" >
%xinclude;

]>

    <chapter id="batchrep-wsdl">
        <title>Services and WSDL</title>
<section><title>Protocol overview</title>
<para>The Batch Replicator provides a set of Resource Properties and SOAP operations to create, manipulate and inspect replication activities. Users will begin by creating a replication resource 
    (AKA &quot;Replicator&quot;) by invoking the create operation and passing it a URL of the replication request file (described in the domain-specific interface section). Users may start, 
    stop, suspend and resume the Replicator when necessary. Typically a user is expected to simply start the resource and allow it to run through completion. During and after the course of 
    replication activities performed by the resource, users may invoke standard &quot;get resource property&quot; and Batch Replicator-specific &quot;find&quot; operations to inspect the state of the 
    resource. When the resource finishes the replication activities and the user has satisfactorily inspected the resource state, the resource should be destroyed using the standard 
    &quot;destroy&quot; operation.</para></section>

<section><title>Operations</title>
    <para>Supported operations include:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
        <listitem><simpara><computeroutput>createReplicator</computeroutput> creates the &quot;Replicator&quot; resource.</simpara>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem><simpara>
                        <computeroutput>[in] InitialTerminationTime</computeroutput> The requested initial termination time for the resource.
                </simpara></listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <simpara>
                        <computeroutput>[in] requestFileRequest</computeroutput> The request-file style request.
                    </simpara>
                    <itemizedlist>
                        <listitem><simpara>
                                <computeroutput>credentialEPR</computeroutput> Endpoint Reference of the user's delegated credential.
                        </simpara></listitem>
                        <listitem><simpara>
                                <computeroutput>options</computeroutput> Replication options which include a set of options pertinent to the transfer stage of the request, such as concurrency, parallel streams, tcp buffer size, etc.
                        </simpara></listitem>
                        <listitem><simpara>
                                <computeroutput>autostart</computeroutput> A Boolean flag indicating whether the resource should be automatically started following resource creation.
                        </simpara></listitem>
                        <listitem><simpara>
                                <computeroutput>requestFileUri</computeroutput> The URI of the request file. Currently supported schemes include http, file, and ftp.
                        </simpara></listitem>
                        <listitem><simpara>
                                <computeroutput>format</computeroutput> The request file format (domain-specific). Currently, the service only supports a simple &quot;Table&quot; format.
                        </simpara></listitem>
                    </itemizedlist>
                </listitem>
                <listitem><simpara>
                        <computeroutput>[out] EPR</computeroutput> The Endpoint Reference of the Replicator resource.
                </simpara></listitem>
                <listitem><simpara>
                        <computeroutput>[fault] fault</computeroutput> Indicates a general failure when attempting to create the Replicator resource.
                </simpara></listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </listitem>

        <listitem><simpara><computeroutput>start</computeroutput> starts the resource.</simpara>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem><simpara>
                        <computeroutput>[fault] invalidStateFault</computeroutput> Indicates the resource is in an invalid state to perform the operation.
                </simpara></listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </listitem>

        <listitem><simpara><computeroutput>stop</computeroutput> stops the resource.</simpara>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem><simpara>
                        <computeroutput>[fault] invalidStateFault</computeroutput> Indicates the resource is in an invalid state to perform the operation.
                </simpara></listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </listitem>

        <listitem><simpara><computeroutput>suspend</computeroutput> suspends the resource.</simpara>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem><simpara>
                        <computeroutput>[fault] invalidStateFault</computeroutput> Indicates the resource is in an invalid state to perform the operation.
                </simpara></listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </listitem>

        <listitem><simpara><computeroutput>resume</computeroutput> resumes the resource.</simpara>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem><simpara>
                        <computeroutput>[fault] invalidStateFault</computeroutput> Indicates the resource is in an invalid state to perform the operation.
                </simpara></listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </listitem>

        <listitem><simpara><computeroutput>findItems</computeroutput> Finds state information for individual replication items.</simpara>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem><simpara>
                        <computeroutput>[in] byUri</computeroutput> Finds by replication URI (currently, this value must be the logical filename, LFN, rather than a properly formed URI). This param is mutually-exclusive with <computeroutput>byStatus</computeroutput>.
                </simpara></listitem>
                <listitem><simpara>
                        <computeroutput>[in] byStatus</computeroutput> Find by status, which includes <computeroutput>Pending</computeroutput>, <computeroutput>Finished</computeroutput>, <computeroutput>Failed</computeroutput>, and <computeroutput>Terminated</computeroutput>. This param is mutually-exclusive with <computeroutput>byUri</computeroutput>.
                </simpara></listitem>
                <listitem><simpara>
                        <computeroutput>[in] offset</computeroutput> An offset into the results set.
                </simpara></listitem>
                <listitem><simpara>
                        <computeroutput>[in] limit</computeroutput> A limit of results to be returned to the client.
                </simpara></listitem>
                <listitem><simpara>
                        <computeroutput>[out] items</computeroutput> An array of items to be returned to the client as a result of the find operation. Each item in the array contains the complete status of the replication item including its identifier, priority, status, error (if any), sources, and destinations.
                </simpara></listitem>
                <listitem><simpara>
                        <computeroutput>[fault] internalErrorFault</computeroutput> Indicates that an internal error occurred.
                </simpara></listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </listitem>

    </itemizedlist>

</section>

    <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="Batchrep_Resource_Properties_Summary_Frag.xml"/>

<section><title>Faults</title>
    <para>Supported faults include:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
        <listitem><simpara><computeroutput>CreateReplicatorFault</computeroutput> Indicates that the service failed to create the Replicator resource.
        </simpara></listitem>
        <listitem><simpara><computeroutput>RequestBodyMissingFault</computeroutput> Indicates that the request body of the create message parameters was missing.
        </simpara></listitem>
        <listitem><simpara><computeroutput>CredentialEprMissingFault</computeroutput> Indicates that the delegated credential EPR was missing from the create message.
        </simpara></listitem>
        <listitem><simpara><computeroutput>InvalidStateFault</computeroutput> Indicates that the requested lifecycle operation (e.g., start, stop, suspend, resume) was performed on a resource that was not in the proper state for the operation to succeed (e.g., performing a resume operation on a non-suspended Replicator resource).
        </simpara></listitem>
        <listitem><simpara><computeroutput>InternalErrorFaultType</computeroutput> Indicates that an internal error occurred (e.g., internal system failure, etc.).
        </simpara></listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
</section>

<section><title>WSDL and Schema Definition</title>
    <para>For more information, please see the <ulink url="http://viewcvs.globus.org/viewcvs.cgi/ws-replica/replicator/common/schema/replica/replicator/replicator_port_type.wsdl?rev=1.2.2.1&amp;only_with_tag=globus_4_0_branch&amp;content-type=text/vnd.viewcvs-markup">Replicator Port Type</ulink> or the complete list of <ulink url="http://viewcvs.globus.org/viewcvs.cgi/ws-replica/replicator/common/schema/replica/replicator/?only_with_tag=globus_4_0_branch">schemas</ulink>.</para>
</section>
</chapter>