<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section><title>Interface introduction</title>
    <para>The DRS domain-specific interface defines the structure and expected contents of a request file used when creating a replication resource. When the client invokes the create operation of the DRS, it will be expected to submit a properly formatted request file. It is important to understand the structure of the request file and to ensure that the file is well-formed.</para>
</section>
<section><title>Syntax of the interface</title>
    <para>For the present release, the DRS request file format is fairly trivial. The request file is structured as a &quot;Table&quot; style of rows and columns of text. 
        Each row represent a requested replication item described in two columns. The first column contains the identifier of the data set which will be discovered and 
        replicated. The identifier must be resolvable by the Replica Location Index (see the JNDI configuration for <computeroutput>defaultIndexUrl</computeroutput>). 
        In most cases, it is expected that the identifier be a Logical Filename (LFN) per the Replica Location Service definition. The second column of the row contains 
        the URL of the &quot;destination&quot; for the replication item. The two columns must be delimited by a <computeroutput>TAB</computeroutput> character 
        and each row must be delimited by an <computeroutput>EOL</computeroutput> character. </para>
        
        <note><simpara>The service will not accept <computeroutput>SPACE</computeroutput> characters as a substitute for the <computeroutput>TAB</computeroutput> 
            character.</simpara></note>
    <para>The following example shows the output of a small request file.</para>
    <screen>
% cat example.req
my-lfn-1        gsiftp://myhost:9001/sandbox/examples/files/my-pfn-1
my-lfn-2        gsiftp://myhost:9001/sandbox/examples/files/my-pfn-2
my-lfn-3        gsiftp://myhost:9001/sandbox/examples/files/my-pfn-3
my-lfn-4        gsiftp://myhost:9001/sandbox/examples/files/my-pfn-4
my-lfn-5        gsiftp://myhost:9001/sandbox/examples/files/my-pfn-5
    </screen>
</section>
