<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section><title>Configuration overview</title>
    <para>The DRS requires certain JNDI settings to be properly configured. The installed JNDI configuration file may be found at 
        <computeroutput>$GLOBUS_LOCATION/etc/globus_wsrf_replicator/jndi-config.xml</computeroutput>. To view the default configuration file 
        (shipped with the GT &shortversion; release) from the Globus CVS repository 
        <ulink url="http://viewcvs.globus.org/viewcvs.cgi/ws-replica/replicator/service/java/source/deploy-jndi-config.xml?tab=globus_4_0_branch&amp;content-type=text/vnd.viewcvs-markup">click 
            here</ulink>.</para>
</section>

<section><title>Syntax of the interface</title>
    <para>The settings are structured as name-value pairs. For example:</para>
    <screen>
    &lt;parameter&gt;
    &nbsp;&nbsp;&lt;name&gt;<emphasis>defaultIndexUrl</emphasis>&lt;/name&gt;
    &nbsp;&nbsp;&lt;value&gt;<emphasis>rls://127.0.0.1:39281</emphasis>&lt;/value&gt;
    &lt;/parameter&gt;
    </screen>
    <para>The following settings must be properly configured:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
        <listitem><simpara><computeroutput>proxyfileDir</computeroutput>: the directory that you would like the DRS to temporarily store user proxies. No setting is necessary. This value may be empty.</simpara></listitem>
        <listitem><simpara><computeroutput>requestfileDir</computeroutput>: the directory that you would like the DRS to temporarily store request files. No setting is necessary. This value may be empty.</simpara></listitem>
        <listitem><simpara><computeroutput>defaultIndexUrl</computeroutput>: the connection URL for your installation of RLS running as a RLI service.</simpara></listitem>
        <listitem><simpara><computeroutput>defaultRegistrationUrl</computeroutput>: the connection URL for your installation of RLS running as a LRC service.</simpara></listitem>
        <listitem><simpara><computeroutput>defaultReliableTransferUrl</computeroutput>: the connection URL for your installation of the RFT ReliableFileTransferFactoryService.</simpara></listitem>
        <listitem><simpara><computeroutput>proxyfileChangePermsCmd</computeroutput>: the platform-dependent command to change file permissions to user-only read-write permissions.</simpara></listitem>
        <listitem><simpara>The rest of the parameter/value pairs may retain the given default values.</simpara></listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
</section>
