<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">


<chapter id="wsmds-migrating-GT3">
    <title>Migrating MDS from GT3</title>
    <para>Although the basic functionality remains the same for MDS in GT4, the architecture has
        changed from OGSI in GT3 to WSRF in GT4. In OGSI, services advertise <emphasis>service
        data</emphasis>; in WSRF, services advertise <emphasis>resource properties</emphasis>.
        Resource Properties and service data are very similar -- both provide a mechanism for
        expressing arbitrary data about grid resources in XML format, as well as query and
        notification/subscription interfaces to that data.</para>

    <para>The GT4 <glossterm>Index Service</glossterm> provides the same functionality as the GT3
        Index Service; however, the GT4 Index Service supports WSRF service group registration and
        resource property query and subscription/notification mechanisms, while the GT3 Index
        Service supported OGSI service group registration and service data query and
        subscription/notification mechanisms.</para>

    <para>The following table shows a mapping of some GT3 concepts/tools to GT4.</para>

    <table>
        <title>Comparison of MDS in GT3 and GT4</title>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <thead>
                <row>
                    <entry>Description</entry>
                    <entry>GT2 Version</entry>
                    <entry>GT4 Version</entry>
                </row>
            </thead>
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>Query Operations</entry>
                    <entry>FindServiceData (to retrieve a single service data element by name or to
                        perform an XPath query against a service's service data elements)</entry>
                    <entry>GetResourceProperty (to retrieve a single resource property by name),
                        GetMultipleResourceProperties (to retrieve multiple resource properties by
                        name), and QueryResourceProperties (to perform an XPath query against a
                        service's resource properties).</entry>
                </row>
                <row>
                    <entry>APIs used for queries</entry>
                    <entry>OGSI (GT3) Core APIs</entry>
                    <entry>WS Core APIs</entry>
                </row>
                <row>
                    <entry>Command-line clients used for queries</entry>
                    <entry>
                        <computeroutput>ogsi-find-service-data</computeroutput>
                    </entry>
                    <entry><computeroutput>wsrf-get-property</computeroutput>,
                            <computeroutput>wsrf-get-properties</computeroutput>,
                            <computeroutput>wsrf-query</computeroutput></entry>
                </row>
                <row>
                    <entry>Available GUIs</entry>
                    <entry>globus-sdb (standalone client) and WebSDB (web interface)</entry>
                    <entry>WebMDS (web interface)</entry>
                </row>
                <row>
                    <entry>Operations for subscription/notification</entry>
                    <entry>OGSI NotificationSource / NotificationSink</entry>
                    <entry>WS-Notification</entry>
                </row>
                <row>
                    <entry>APIs used for subscription/notification</entry>
                    <entry>OGSI (GT3) Core APIs</entry>
                    <entry>WS Core APIs</entry>
                </row>
                <row>
                    <entry>Index registration mechanism</entry>
                    <entry>GT3 services can be configured to publish their service data to index
                        services.</entry>
                    <entry>Index Servers maintain aggregating service groups that include
                        registration information (timeout values, the mechanism to use to acquire
                        information, and additional mechanism-specific parameters) The registration
                        is accomplished by adding an entry to an aggregating service group via the
                            <computeroutput>mds-servicegroup-add</computeroutput> command. In
                        addition, services may be configured to register themselves to the default
                        index server running in the same container.</entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>

    <para>A more detailed mapping of OGSI concepts to WSRF concepts can be found <ulink
            url="http://www-106.ibm.com/developerworks/library/ws-resource/ogsi_to_wsrf_1.0.pdf"
            >here</ulink>.</para>


</chapter>
