<section><title>Programming Model Overview</title>
<para>The Globus FTP Client library provides a convenient way of accessing files
  on remote FTP servers. In addition to supporting the basic FTP protocol, the
  FTP Client library supports several security and performance extensions to
  make FTP more suitable for Grid applications. These extensions are described
  in the Grid FTP Protocol document.</para>
<para>In addition to protocol support for grid applications, the FTP Client library
  provides a plugin architecture for installing application or grid-specific
  fault recovery and performance tuning algorithms within the library. Application
  writers may then target their code toward the FTP Client library, and by simply
  enabling the appropriate plugins, easily tune their application to run it on
  a different grid.</para>
<para>All applications which use the Globus FTP Client API must include the header
  file "globus_ftp_client.h" and activate the GLOBUS_FTP_CLIENT_MODULE.</para>
<para>To use the Globus FTP Client API, one must create an FTP Client handle. This
  structure contains context information about FTP operations which are being
  executed, a cache of FTP control and data connections, and information about
  plugins which are being used. The specifics of the connection caching and plugins
  are found in the "Handle Attributes" section of the API documentation.</para>
<para>Once the handle is created, one may begin transferring files or doing other
  FTP operations by calling the functions in the "FTP Operations" section of the API documentation. In addition to whole-file transfers, the API supports partial file transfers, restarting transfers from a known point, and various FTP directory management commands. All FTP operations may have a set of attributes, defined in the operationattr section, associated with them to tune various FTP parameters. The data structures and functions needed to restart a file transfer are described in the "Restart Markers" section of the API documentation. For operations which require the user to send to or receive data from an FTP <glossterm linkend="server">server</glossterm> they must call the functions described in the "globus_ftp_client_data" section
  of the manual.</para>
<para>The globus_ftp_control library provides low-level services needed to implement
    FTP clients and servers. The API provided is protocol specific. The data transfer
    portion of this API provides support for the standard data methods described
    in the FTP Specification as well as extensions for parallel, striped, and
  partial data transfer. </para>
</section>

<section><title>Component API</title>
<itemizedlist>
  <listitem><simpara><ulink url="http://www.globus.org/api/c-globus-3.9.x/globus_ftp_client/html/index.html">C Client Library API</ulink></simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara><ulink url="http://www.globus.org/api/c-globus-3.9.x/globus_ftp_control/html/index.html">C Control Library API</ulink></simpara></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
<para>For information on the internationalization API, see
    the <ulink url="http://www.globus.org/toolkit/docs/4.0/common/ccommonlib/C_Common_Libraries_Public_Interfaces.html#apis">C
    Common Libraries Public Interface</ulink>. </para>
</section>
