<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">

<chapter id="myproxy-configuring"><title>Configuring </title>
<para>No additional configuration is required to use MyProxy clients after they
  are installed, although you may want to set the MYPROXY_SERVER environment
  variable to the hostname of your myproxy-server in the default user environment
  on your systems.</para>

<para>
To configure the myproxy-server you must 
modify <filename>$GLOBUS_LOCATION/etc/myproxy-server.config</filename>.
<emphasis>If you skip this step, your myproxy-server will not accept
any requests.</emphasis>
The default configuration does not enable any
myproxy-server features to provide the greatest security until you
have configured your server.
To enable all myproxy-server features uncomment the provided sample
policy at the top of the myproxy-server.config config file, as
follows:
</para>
<screen>
#
# Complete Sample Policy
#
# The following lines define a sample policy that enables all
# myproxy-server features.  See below for more examples.
accepted_credentials  "*"
authorized_retrievers "*"
default_retrievers    "*"
authorized_renewers   "*"
default_renewers      "none"</screen>
<para>
Please see below for additional documentation on the
myproxy-server.config options.
</para>
<para>
If you have root access, you can copy your
<filename>myproxy-server.config</filename> file to 
<filename>/etc/myproxy-server.config</filename>
so it is not overwritten by later installations.
</para>

<para>
       The  <filename>myproxy-server.config</filename>  file  sets  the  policy  for
        the <command>myproxy-server(8)</command>, specifying what credentials may be
        stored in the server's repository and who is authorized to retrieve credentials.
        By default, the <command>myproxy-server(8)</command> looks for this file in <filename>/etc/myproxy-server.config</filename>
       and if it is not found there, it looks in <filename>$GLOBUS_LOCATION/etc/myproxy-server.config</filename>.
       The <command>myproxy-server -c</command> option can
       be used to specify an alternative location. The file installed by default
       does not allow any requests.
</para>
<para>
       The file also supports a <command>passphrase_policy_program</command> command
       for specifying an external program for evaluating the quality of users'
       passphrases.   A  sample  program   is   installed   in   <command>$GLOBUS_LOCATION/share/myproxy/myproxy-passphrase-policy</command>  but
       is not enabled by default.
</para>
<para>
       Lines in the configuration file use  limited  regular  expressions  for
       matching  the  distinguished names (DNs) of classes of users.  The 
       limited regular expressions support the  shell-style  characters  '*'
       and '?',  where  '*'  matches  any number of characters and '?' matches
       any single character.
</para>
<para>
       The DN limited regexes should be  delimited  with  double  quotes  ("DN
       regex").
</para>
<para>
       The configuration file has the following types of lines:
</para>
<table><title>myproxy-server.config lines</title>
<tgroup cols="2"><tbody>
<row><entry>   accepted_credentials "DNregex"</entry>
<entry>       Each of these lines allows any clients whose DNs match the given
              limited regex to connect to the myproxy-server and store 
	      credentials  with  it for future retrieval.  Any number of these
	      lines may appear.  For backwards compatibility, these lines can
	      also start with <constant>allowed_clients</constant> instead of
	      <constant>accepted_credentials</constant>.</entry>
</row>

<row><entry>   authorized_retrievers "DN regex"</entry>
<entry>          Each  of  these  lines  allows  the  server administrator to set
              server-wide policies for authorized retrievers. If the client DN
              does not match the given limited regex, the client is not allowed
              to retrieve the credentials previously stored by a  client.   In
              addition  to  the server-wide policy, MyProxy also provides support
  for per-credential policy. The user can specify the regex DN of the allowed
  retrievers of the credential when uploading the credential (using <command>myproxy-init(1)</command>).
  The retrieval client DN must also match the user specified regex. In order
  to retrieve credentials the client also needs to know the name and pass
              phrase  provided by the client when the credentials were stored.
              Any number of these lines may appear.  For backwards compatibility,
  these lines can also start with <constant>allowed_services</constant> instead
              of
              <constant>authorized_retrievers</constant>.</entry>
</row>

<row><entry>   default_retrievers "DN regex"</entry>
<entry>          Each of these lines  allows  the  server  administrator  to  set
              server-wide  default  policies.  The regex specifies the clients
              who can access the credentials. The default retriever policy  is
              enforced  if  a per-credential policy is not specified on upload
              (using <command>myproxy-init(1)</command>).  In other words, the client
              can override this policy for a credential on upload. The per-credential
              policy is enforced in addition to the server-wide policy  specified
              by the <constant>authorized_retrievers</constant> line (which clients can
              not override). Any number of these lines may be present. For backwards
              compatibility, if no <constant>default_retrievers</constant> line is specified,
              the default policy is "*", which allows any client to  pass  the
              per-credential  policy  check.   (The client must still pass the
              <constant>authorized_retrievers</constant> check).</entry>
</row>

<row><entry>   authorized_renewers "DN regex" </entry>
<entry>          Each of these lines  allows  the  server  administrator  to  set
              server-wide  policies  for authorized renewers. If the client DN
              does not match the given limited regex the client is not allowed
              to  renew  the  credentials  previously  stored by a client.  In
              addition to the server-wide policy, MyProxy also  provides  support
  for per-credential policy. The user can specify the regex DN of the allowed
  renewers of the credential on upload (using
              <command>myproxy-init(1)</command>).   The  renewal  client DN must match both
              this regex and the user specified regex. In this case, the client
              must also already have a credential with a DN matching the DN of
              the credentials to be retrieved, to be used in a  second  authorization step (see the <option>-a</option> option for <command>myproxy-logon(1)</command>).</entry>
</row>

<row><entry>   default_renewers "DN regex"</entry>
<entry>          Each of these lines  allows  the  server  administrator  to  set
              server-wide  default  renewer  policies. The regex specifies the
              clients who can renew the credentials. The default renewer  policy
  is enforced if a per-credential policy is not specified on upload (using <command>myproxy-init(1)</command>).
  This is enforced in addition to the server-wide policy specified by the <constant>authorized_renewers</constant>
              line. Any number of these lines may appear.  For backwards  compatibility,
              if no <constant>default_renewers</constant> line is specified, the default
              policy is "*",
              which allows any client to pass the per-credential policy check.
              (The client must still pass the <constant>authorized_renewers</constant> check).</entry>
</row>

<row><entry>   passphrase_policy_program full-path-to-script</entry>
<entry>          This line specifies a program to run whenever  a  passphrase  is
              set  or  changed  for implementing a local password policy.  The
              program is passed the new passphrase via stdin and is passed the
              following  arguments:  username,  distinguished name, credential
              name (if any), per-credential retriever  policy  (if  any),  and
              per-credential  renewal  policy  (if any).  If the passphrase is
              acceptable, the program should exit with status  0.   Otherwise,
              it  should  exit  with non-zero status, causing the operation in
              progress (credential load, passphrase change) to fail  with  the
              error  message provided by the program's stdout.  Note: You must
              specify the full path to the external program.  <envar>$GLOBUS_LOCATION</envar>    can't be used in the <filename>myproxy-server.config</filename> file.</entry>
</row>

<row><entry>   max_proxy_lifetime hours</entry>
<entry>          This line specifies a server-wide maximum lifetime for retrieved
              proxy  credentials.   By  default,  no  server-wide  maximum  is
              enforced.  However, if this option is specified, the server will
              limit the lifetime of any retrieved  proxy  credentials  to  the
              value given.</entry>
</row>
</tbody></tgroup>
</table>
</chapter>