<title> GT 4.0 Index Service: Developer's Guide</title>
<titleabbrev>Developer's Guide</titleabbrev>

<section id="s-index-developer-introduction"><title>Introduction</title>
<para>The WS MDS Index Service collects information about grid
resources and publishes that information as a service group. Client
programs use resource property queries or subscription/notification
to retrieve information from the index. Information can be added to
the index via a number of different mechanisms: since the Index
    Service is implemented using the <glossterm linkend="aggregator-framework">Aggregator Framework</glossterm>, any
    <glossterm linkend="aggregator-source">aggregator source</glossterm> can be used to provide information for the
    index.</para>
    <para>This document describes the programmatic interfaces to the
        Index Service. See also general Globus Toolkit <ulink url="http://www.globus.org/toolkit/docs/development/coding_guidelines.html">coding guidelines</ulink> and
        <ulink url="http://www.globus.org/toolkit/docs/4.0/best_practices.html">GT 4.0 best practices</ulink>.</para>
</section>
<section><title>Before you begin</title>

<section id="s-index-developer-features"><title>Feature summary</title>
&WS_MDS_Index_Feature_Summary_Frag;
</section>
<section id="s-index-developer-platforms"><title>Tested platforms</title>
&WS_MDS_Index_Platform_Summary_Frag;
</section>
<section id="s-index-developer-compatibility"><title>Backward
compatibility summary</title>
&WS_MDS_Index_Compatibility_Summary_Frag;
</section>
<section id="s-index-developer-dependencies"><title>Technology
dependencies</title>
&WS_MDS_Index_Dependencies_Summary_Frag;
</section>
<section id="s-index-developer-security_considerations"><title>
Security considerations</title>
&WS_MDS_Index_Security_Considerations_Frag;
</section>
</section>
<section id="s-index-developer-archdes"><title>Architecture and design
overview</title>
<para>There are essentially two interfaces to the Index Service -- one
for getting information into the index, and one for retrieving
information from the index.</para>
<para>Information is retrieved from the Index Service as service group
entries using the standard WS MDS Core APIs for resource property
    queries or subscription/notification.</para>
    <para>Because the Index is implemented as a WS MDS Aggregator Framework, the programmatic interface for getting information into
        the index is to create an aggregator source, the Aggregator Framework's architecture follows:</para>
    <section><title>Aggregator Framework architecture</title>
        &WS_MDS_Aggregator_Architecture_Frag;
    </section>
</section>
<section id="s-index-developer-pubinterfaces"><title>Public interface</title>
<para>The semantics and syntax of the APIs and WSDL for the component,
along with descriptions of domain-specific structured interface
data, can be found in the <ulink url= "WS_MDS_Index_Public_Interfaces.html">public interface
guide</ulink>.</para>
</section>
<section id="s-index-developer-scenarios"><title>Usage scenarios</title>

<section><title>Retrieving information from an index service</title>
<para>Information is retrieved from the index using the standard Java WS Core API calls for getting resource property information:</para>
    
    <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>Use <computeroutput>GetResourceProperty</computeroutput> to request a single resource property by name</listitem>
        <listitem>Use <computeroutput>GetResourceProperties</computeroutput> to request several resource properties by name,</listitem>
        <listitem>Use <computeroutput>QueryResourceProperty</computeroutput> to perform an XPath query on a resource property document, and the notification/subscription
            mechanism. </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    
    <para>See the <ulink url="../../common/javawscore/developer-index.html">Java WS Core Developer's Guide</ulink> for API details.</para>
    
</section>
    
<section><title>Adding information to an index</title>
Information is added to an index by way of an <emphasis>aggregator
source</emphasis>. The Globus Toolkit distribution includes several
standard aggregator sources (see the <ulink url=
    "http://www.globus.org/toolkit/docs/4.0/info/aggregator/WS_MDS_Aggregator_Sources_Reference.html">Aggregator Sources Reference</ulink> for more details). To create
your own custom information source, see the <ulink url=
    "../aggregator/developer-index.html">WS MDS Aggregator Framework Developer's
Guide</ulink>.
</section>
    
</section>
<section id="s-index-developer-tutorials"><title>Tutorials</title>
    <para>Use of the index service is covered in the <ulink url=
        "http://www-unix.globus.org/toolkit/tutorials/BAS/">Build a Grid Service Tutorial (GlobusWORLD 2005)</ulink>.
        
    </para>
</section>
<section id="s-index-developer-debugging"><title>Debugging</title>
<para>See the <ulink url=
"../../common/javawscore/developer-index.html#debugging">Debug section of
the Java WS Core Developer's Guide</ulink> for general information on
logging, including which files to edit to set logging
properties.</para>
<para>To turn on debug logging for the Index Service, add the
line:</para>
<screen>
log4j.category.org.globus.mds.index=DEBUG
</screen>
<para>to the appropriate properties file. Since the Index Service is
implemented using the aggregator framework, you may also want to
turn on aggregator debugging by adding this line:</para>
<screen>
log4j.category.org.globus.mds.aggregator=DEBUG
</screen>
</section>
<section id="s-index-developer-troubleshooting"><title>
Troubleshooting</title>
<para>General troubleshooting information can be found in the <ulink url=
"../../common/javawscore/developer-index.html#troubleshooting">GT 4.0 Java
WS Core Developer's Guide</ulink>.</para>
</section>
<section id="s-index-developer-relateddocs"><title>Related
Documentation</title>
<para>Specifications for resource properties, service groups, and
subscription/notification are available at <ulink url=
"http://www.globus.org/wsrf/">http://www.globus.org/wsrf/</ulink>.</para>
</section>
