<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">

<section id="rft-features">
  <title>RFT Feature Summary</title>
  <indexterm type="rft"><primary>features</primary></indexterm>
  <para> Features new in GT <replaceable role="entity">version</replaceable>
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <simpara>New in RFT 4.2 is a connection caching feature.  
      This allows internal GridFTP connections to be internally
      cached globally across all service requests.  This has shown
      to be a vast performance increases in the cases where a single
      users wishes to transfer many URLs, but instead of transferring them
      in a single request, they put each in one request.  Cache helps
      this case specifically, and is a general optimization for other
      cases.
      </simpara>
      <simpara>
        The backoff algorithm has been modified.  To start with, all errors
        in communicating with GridFTP servers are considered transient. In
        the past we considered authorization failures and DNS lookup 
        failures, as well as other similar things as fatal.  We have since
        recognized that even those shall pass, and in some environments
        those should be expected as a means of controlling load.
      </simpara>
      <simpara>
       Additionally how we back off is different.  If a failure is detected
       we do not try to communicate with the given GridFTP server for a 
        specified amount of time, <emphasis>or</emphasis> until some
        other transfer completes successfully with that server.  This 
        allows for optimal use of GridFTP servers that only allow a fixed
        number of connections at once, and it helps make optimal use of our 
        connection cache.
      </simpara>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>Supported Features </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <simpara>Delete files: Delete a set of files/directories on a GridFTP server. </simpara>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <simpara>Exponential Backoff: Configurable exponential back off before a failed transfer is
        retried.</simpara>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <simpara>Transfer All or None: If this option is set and one of the transfers in the request
        fails, RFT will stop transferring the remainder of the request and delete the files that
        were already transferred successfully.</simpara>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <simpara>Transfer Permissions: File permissions are restored at the destination once the file
        is transfered successfully. This can be configured to throw a fatal error or a transient
        error depending on whether the GridFTP server supports the MLST command.</simpara>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <simpara>Configurable number of concurrent transfers per container and per request.</simpara>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <simpara>Better error reporting and faults.</simpara>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <simpara>Database purge of the request and transfers after life time expiration.</simpara>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <simpara>Cumulative (aggregate ) Resource Properties on the factory provide some statistical
        information.</simpara>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <simpara>One status Resource Property for the entire transfer.</simpara>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <simpara>Recursive directory transfers and deletes.</simpara>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <simpara>Parallel streams.</simpara>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <simpara>TCP Buffer Size.</simpara>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <simpara>Third-party directory transfers, file transfers and deletes.</simpara>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <simpara>Data channel authentication (DCAU).</simpara>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <simpara>NoTPT option.</simpara>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <simpara>Different subject names for source and destination GridFTP servers for the
        authorization mechanism.</simpara>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <simpara> Support for binary/ASCII type of transfers.</simpara>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <simpara>Configurable number of retries for failed transfers per request.</simpara>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <simpara>Block Size in bytes.</simpara>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>Deprecated Features</para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <simpara> None </simpara>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
</section>
