<glossdiv>
 <title>A</title>

 <glossentry id="axis">
   <glossterm>Apache Axis</glossterm>
   <glossdef>
   <para>
The SOAP engine implementation used within the Globus Toolkit. See the <ulink url="http://ws.apache.org/axis/">Apache Axis website</ulink> for details.
   </para>
   </glossdef>
 </glossentry>

</glossdiv>



<glossdiv>
 <title>C</title>

 <glossentry id="client-config.wsdd">
   <glossterm>client-config.wsdd</glossterm>
   <glossdef>
   <para>
Axis client-side WSDD configuration file. It contains information about the type mappings, the transport and other handlers.
   </para>
   <glossseealso otherterm="axis">Axis</glossseealso>
   <glossseealso otherterm="wsdd">WSDD</glossseealso>
   </glossdef>
 </glossentry>

</glossdiv>



<glossdiv>
 <title>J</title>

 <glossentry id="jndi">
   <glossterm>JNDI</glossterm>
   <glossdef>
   <para>
Java Naming and Directory Interface (JNDI) API are used to access a central transient container registry. The registry is mainly used for discovery of the <emphasis>ResourceHome</emphasis> implementations. However, the registry can also be used store and retrieve arbitrary information. The <emphasis>jndi-config.xml</emphasis> files are used to populate the registry. See the <ulink url="http://java.sun.com/products/jndi/tutorial/">JNDI Tutorial</ulink> for details.
   </para>
   <glossseealso otherterm="jndi-config.xml">jndi-config.xml</glossseealso>
   <glossseealso otherterm="ResourceHome">ResourceHome</glossseealso>
   </glossdef>
 </glossentry>

 <glossentry id="jndi-config.xml">
   <glossterm>jndi-config.xml</glossterm>
   <glossdef>
   <para>
     It is a XML-based configuration file used to populate the container registry accessible via the JNDI API. See the <ulink url="../../common/javawscore/developer-index.html#s-javawscore-developer-JNDIDetails">JNDI details</ulink> for more information.
   </para>
   <glossseealso otherterm="jndi">JNDI</glossseealso>
   <glossseealso otherterm="ResourceHome">ResourceHome</glossseealso>
   <glossseealso otherterm="xml">XML</glossseealso>
   </glossdef>
 </glossentry>

</glossdiv>




<glossdiv>
 <title>G</title>

 <glossentry id="GAR">
   <glossterm>GAR</glossterm>
   <glossdef>
   <para>
     The GAR (Grid Archive) file is a single file which contains all the files and information that the container needs to deploy a service. See <ulink url="../../common/javawscore/developer-index.html#s-javawscore-developer-gardetails">GAR details</ulink> for more information.
   </para>
   </glossdef>
 </glossentry>

</glossdiv>


<glossdiv>
 <title>O</title>

 <glossentry id="OperationProvider">
   <glossterm>operation provider</glossterm>
   <glossdef>
   <para>
     A reusable Java component that implements one or more web service functions. A web service can be composed of one or more operation providers. See <ulink url="../../common/javawscore/developer-index.html#s-javawscore-developer-OperationProvider">Operation Provider</ulink> for more information.
   </para>
   </glossdef>
 </glossentry>

</glossdiv>

<glossdiv>
 <title>R</title>

 <glossentry id="ResourceHome">
   <glossterm>ResourceHome</glossterm>
   <glossdef>
   <para>
The resources are managed and discovered via <emphasis>ResourceHome</emphasis> implementations. The <emphasis>ResourceHome</emphasis> implementations can also be responsible for creating new resources, performing operations on a set of resources at a time, etc. <emphasis>ResourceHome</emphasis>s are configured in JNDI and are associated with a particular web service.
   </para>
   <glossseealso otherterm="jndi">JNDI</glossseealso>
   </glossdef>
 </glossentry>

</glossdiv>



<glossdiv>
 <title>S</title>

 <glossentry id="server-config.wsdd">
   <glossterm>server-config.wsdd</glossterm>
   <glossdef>
   <para>
Axis server-side WSDD configuration file. It contains information about the services, the type mappings and various handlers.
   </para>
   <glossseealso otherterm="axis">Axis</glossseealso>
   <glossseealso otherterm="wsdd">WSDD</glossseealso>
   </glossdef>
 </glossentry>

 <glossentry id="soap">
   <glossterm>SOAP</glossterm>
   <glossdef>
   <para>
SOAP provides a standard, extensible, composable framework for packaging and exchanging XML messages between a service provider and a service requester. SOAP is independent of the underlying transport protocol, but is most commonly carried on HTTP. See the <ulink url="http://www.w3.org/TR/soap/">SOAP specifications</ulink> for details.
   </para>
   </glossdef>
 </glossentry>

</glossdiv>



<glossdiv>
 <title>W</title>

 <glossentry id="wsdd">
   <glossterm>Web Services Deployment Descriptor (WSDD)</glossterm>
   <glossdef>
   <para>
Axis XML-based configuration file.
   </para>
   <glossseealso otherterm="axis">Axis</glossseealso>
   <glossseealso otherterm="client-config.wsdd">client-config.wsdd</glossseealso>
   <glossseealso otherterm="server-config.wsdd">server-config.wsdd</glossseealso>
   <glossseealso otherterm="xml">XML</glossseealso>
   </glossdef>
 </glossentry>

 <glossentry id="wsa">
   <glossterm>WS Addressing (WSA)</glossterm>
   <glossdef>
   <para>
The WS-Addressing specification defines transport-neutral mechanisms to address Web services and messages. Specifically, this specification defines XML elements to identify Web service endpoints and to secure end-to-end endpoint identification in messages. See the <ulink url="http://www.w3.org/2002/ws/addr/">W3C WS Addressing Working Group</ulink> for details.
   </para>
   </glossdef>
 </glossentry>

 <glossentry id="wsn">
   <glossterm>WS Notification (WSN)</glossterm>
   <glossdef>
   <para>
The WS-Notification family of specifications define a pattern-based approach to allowing Web services to disseminate information to one another. This framework comprises mechanisms for basic notification (WS-Notification), topic-based notification (WS-Topics), and brokered notification (WS-BrokeredNotification). See the <ulink url="http://www.oasis-open.org/committees/tc_home.php?wg_abbrev=wsn">OASIS Web Services Notification (WSN) TC</ulink> for details.
   </para>
   </glossdef>
 </glossentry>

 <glossentry id="wsrf">
   <glossterm>WS Resource Framework (WSRF)</glossterm>
   <glossdef>
   <para>
The WS Resource Framework (WSRF) specifications define a generic and open framework for modeling and accessing stateful resources using Web services. This framework comprises mechanisms to describe views on the state (WS-ResourceProperties), to support management of the state through properties associated with the Web service (WS-ResourceLifetime), to describe how these mechanisms are extensible to groups of Web services (WS-ServiceGroup), and to deal with faults (WS-BaseFaults). See the <ulink url="http://www.oasis-open.org/committees/tc_home.php?wg_abbrev=wsrf">OASIS Web Services Notification (WSRF) TC</ulink> for details.
   </para>
   </glossdef>
 </glossentry>

 <glossentry id="wsdl">
   <glossterm>WSDL</glossterm>
   <glossdef>
   <para>
WSDL is an XML document for describing Web services. Standardized binding conventions define how to use WSDL in conjunction with SOAP and other messaging substrates. WSDL interfaces can be compiled to generate proxy code that constructs messages and manages communications on behalf of the client application. The proxy automatically maps the XML message structures into native language objects that can be directly manipulated by the application. The proxy frees the developer from having to understand and manipulate XML. See the <ulink url="http://www.w3.org/TR/wsdl">WSDL 1.1 specification</ulink> for details.
   </para>
   <glossseealso otherterm="xml">XML</glossseealso>
   <glossseealso otherterm="soap">SOAP</glossseealso>
   </glossdef>
 </glossentry>

 <glossentry id="wsibp">
   <glossterm>WS-I Basic Profile</glossterm>
   <glossdef>
   <para>
The <ulink url="http://www.ws-i.org/Profiles/BasicProfile-1.0-2004-04-16.html">WS-I Basic Profile</ulink> specification is a set of recommendations on how to use the different web services specifications such as SOAP, WSDL, etc. to maximize interoperability. 
   </para>
   <glossseealso otherterm="wsdl">WSDL</glossseealso>
   <glossseealso otherterm="soap">SOAP</glossseealso>
   </glossdef>
 </glossentry>

</glossdiv>
            


<glossdiv>
 <title>X</title>

 <glossentry id="xml">
   <glossterm>XML</glossterm>
   <glossdef>
   <para>
Extensible Markup Language (XML) is standard, flexible, and extensible data format. See the <ulink url="http://www.w3.org/XML/">W3C XML site</ulink> for details.
   </para>
   </glossdef>
 </glossentry>

 <glossentry id="xpath">
   <glossterm>XPath</glossterm>
   <glossdef>
   <para>
XPath is a language for finding information in an XML document. XPath is used to navigate through elements and attributes in an XML document. See the <ulink url="http://www.w3.org/TR/xpath">XPath specification</ulink> for details.
   </para>
   </glossdef>
 </glossentry>

</glossdiv>
