<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd"
[

<!ENTITY % myents SYSTEM "../../entities">

%myents;

]>
<section>
<section>
  <title>Permissions of service configuration files</title>
  <para>The service configuration files such as <glossterm>jndi-config.xml</glossterm> or <glossterm>server-config.wsdd</glossterm> (located under <computeroutput>$GLOBUS_LOCATION/etc/&lt;gar&gt;/</computeroutput> directory) may contain private information such as database passwords, etc. Ensure that these configuration files are only readable by the user that is running the container. 
The deployment process automatically sets the permissions of the <computeroutput>jndi-config.xml</computeroutput> and <computeroutput>server-config.wsdd</computeroutput> files as user readable only. However, this might not work correctly on all platforms and this does not apply to any other configuration files.
</para>
</section>
<section>
  <title>Permissions of persistent data</title>
  <para>The services using subscription persistence API or other basic persistence helper API will store all or part of its persistent data under the <filename>~/.globus/persisted</filename> directory. Ensure that the entire <filename>~/.globus/persisted</filename> directory is only readable by the user running the container.
</para>
</section>
<section>
  <title>Invocation of non-public service functions</title>
  <para>
    A client can potentially invoke a service function that is not formally defined in the <glossterm baseform="Web Services Description Language">WSDL</glossterm> but it is defined in the service implementation class. There are two ways to prevent this from happening:
<orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <simpara>Define all service methods in your service class as either <computeroutput>private</computeroutput> or <computeroutput>protected</computeroutput>.</simpara>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <simpara>Configure appropriate <parameter>allowedMethods</parameter> or <parameter>allowedMethodsClass</parameter> parameter in the service deployment descriptor (please see <olink targetdoc="javawscoreAdmin" targetptr="javawscore-admin-configuring"/> for details).</simpara>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
</para>
</section>
</section>