<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd"
[

<!ENTITY % myents SYSTEM "../../entities">

%myents;

]>
<section>
<para>The SweGrid Accounting System (SGAS) is a 100% Java implementation of a resource allocation 
    enforcement and tracking service for the Grid, based on the latest Web services technologies. It runs on 
    all platforms supporting JRE 1.5. SGAS comprises of several subcomponents, presented briefly below.
    
    <itemizedlist>
        <listitem><para><emphasis>Bank</emphasis>: the central service of the accounting system that maintains and enforces allocation quotas.</para></listitem>
        <listitem><para><emphasis>LUTS</emphasis>: The Logging and Usage Tracking Service (LUTS) is a general purpose logging system for 
            tracking resource usage in SGAS. It allows secure publication and query-based retrieval of usage data in the 
            format of GGF UsageRecord XML.</para></listitem>
        <listitem><para><emphasis>JARM</emphasis>: The Job Account Reservation Manager (JARM) is a component responsible for integrating various 
            workload managers, schedulers and local accounting systems deployed at the resource sites with SGAS. JARM is 
            typically used as a callout to the bank during the job submission phase. The bank then issues a time-limited reservation 
            to run the job, based on user, resource and bank policy. After the job has completed the job is logged in LUTS, and if a 
            valid account reservation was made, JARM also charges the account in the Bank, and releases the reservation on behalf 
            of the resource.</para></listitem>
        <listitem><para><emphasis>PAT</emphasis>: The Policy Administration Tool (PAT) component is designed to be used to manage the security policies 
            of all of the SGAS services. It contains a command line tool that can be run in interactive or batch mode for easy scripting.</para></listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
</para>
    <para>More detailed information, publications and presentations of the SGAS effort can currently be obtained at 
        <ulink url="http://www.sgas.se/">http://www.sgas.se/</ulink>.</para></section>