<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<para>Features new in release &shortversion;
<itemizedlist>
<listitem><para>Based on WSRF rather than OGSI
<itemizedlist>
<listitem><simpara>Aggregated data is published through WS-Resource Properties
    mechanisms</simpara></listitem>
    <listitem><simpara>The <glossterm>Aggregator Framework</glossterm> module (basis of the index service)
collects data from monitored resources using WS-Resource Properties
collection mechanisms, including the base WS-Resource Properties
poll operations and WS-Notification.</simpara></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
</para></listitem>
<listitem><simpara>Persistent configuration of aggregations has been refactored.
The service no longer has its own config file for specifying
aggregations. Instead a separate client is used to make appropriate
registrations. This client may be started alongside the container
for the equivalent effect. The client may also be deployed
elsewhere to support resource-side configuration (providing similar
functionality to the GT3.2 RegistryPublishProvider) or at a third
location.</simpara></listitem>
</itemizedlist></para>
<para>Other Supported Features
<itemizedlist>
<listitem><simpara>The index appears as a ServiceGroup (defined in WSRF) which
lists registered resources alongside dynamically collected
information from those resources. This information can be examined
using (for example) XPath queries to discover resources that match
desired constraints.</simpara></listitem>
</itemizedlist></para>
<para>Deprecated Features
<itemizedlist>
<listitem><simpara>Support for Xindice and aggregated data persistence has been
removed.</simpara></listitem>
<listitem><simpara>The ability to specify default aggregations in service config
file has been removed (see item in 'New Features').</simpara></listitem>
<listitem><simpara>Non-ServiceGroupRegistration methods for managing aggregations
have been removed; the equivalent functionality is available
through the ServiceGroupRegistration port type which is available
in both GT3.2 and GT 3.9.3.0 versions of the index service.</simpara></listitem>
</itemizedlist></para>
