<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<title>GT4 Delegation Service User&apos;s Guide</title>
<titleabbrev>User&apos;s Guide</titleabbrev>
<section id="s-delegation-user-introduction">
  <title>Introduction</title>
  <para>The  delegation service can be used when a user wants to delegate rights to a service that is hosted in the same container as the delegation service.  The service accepts a credential      from the user and provides access to that credential to any service that runs in the same container. Upon delegation to the service, an endpoint reference to the delegated credential is returned to the client, which then   can be furnished to other services as a handle to the credential. </para>
  <para>Moreover, the endpoint reference returned on delegation can be used by the client to refresh the credential stored with the delegation service. The service then sends notification to any service that has registered interest with that particular credential.</para>
</section>
<section id="s-delegation-user-commandline">
  <title>Command-line tools</title>
  <para><xref linkend="r-delegation-reference"/></para>
</section>
<section id="s-delegation-user-gui">
  <title>Graphical user interfaces</title>
&WS_AA_Delegation_Service_Interface_GUI_Frag;
</section>
<section id="s-delegation-user-troubleshooting">
  <title>Troubleshooting</title>
  <section>
    <title> AuthorizationException: &quot;test DN&quot; is not authorized to use operation: {http://www.globus.org/08/2004/delegationService}requestSecurityToken</title>
    <para>This exception can occur when  a client whose DN is not in the gridmap file configured for the delegation factory service attempts to delegate (using globus-credential-delegate).</para>
    <note>
      <para>The <emphasis>test user</emphasis> specified in the error message is just a sample and will contain the DN of the user attempting to access the credential.</para>
    </note>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title> AuthorizationException: &quot;test DN&quot; is not authorized to use operation: {http://www.globus.org/08/2004/delegationService}refresh</title>
    <para>This exception can occur when  a client       attempts to refresh a credential it did not delegate (using globus-credential-refresh).</para>
    <note>
      <para>The <emphasis>test user</emphasis> specified in the error message is just a sample and will contain the DN of the user attempting to access the credential.</para>
    </note>
  </section>
</section>
