<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook V4.2//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.3/docbookx.dtd" 
[

<!ENTITY Pre_WS_MDS_Compatibility_Summary_Frag SYSTEM "Pre_WS_MDS_Compatibility_Summary_Frag.xml">
<!ENTITY Pre_WS_MDS_Dependencies_Summary_Frag SYSTEM "Pre_WS_MDS_Dependencies_Summary_Frag.xml">
<!ENTITY Pre_WS_MDS_Feature_Summary_Frag SYSTEM "Pre_WS_MDS_Feature_Summary_Frag.xml">
<!ENTITY Pre_WS_MDS_Overview_Brief_Frag SYSTEM "Pre_WS_MDS_Overview_Brief_Frag.xml">
<!ENTITY Pre_WS_MDS_Platform_Summary_Frag SYSTEM "Pre_WS_MDS_Platform_Summary_Frag.xml">
<!ENTITY Pre_WS_MDS_Release_Notes SYSTEM "Pre_WS_MDS_Release_Notes.xml">
<!ENTITY PreWSMDSFacts SYSTEM "PreWSMDSFacts.xml">

]>

<book>
  <?dbhtml filename="index.html" ?>  <title>GT 4.0 Pre-WS MDS (MDS2)</title>
<para>The GT4 release includes the Pre-WS component, MDS2, for legacy purposes only
  - it will be deprecated at some future time as experience is gained with the
WS implementation. Please use the existing documentation for MDS2 <ulink url="http://www-fp.globus.org/mds/mds2/">here</ulink>.</para>
  <warning>
<simpara>  Please note that in the GT4 pre-WS build, MDS2 is not installed by 
  default. This is because of security concerns with two third-party 
  libraries, Open LDAP v.2.0.22 and Cyrus SASL (v. 1.5.27). That 
  version of OpenLDAP has security vulnerabilities that are no longer 
  being patched due to the age of the version (the current version is 
  2.2.25). This means that anyone who runs MDS2 on their server has a 
  chance of being affected by this, although we have no reported cases 
  of this occurring. A similar situation exists for the version of Cyrus
  SASL we are using although this can be avoided by not using MDS2 in secure-mode.</simpara>
    
 <simpara>   An unsupported, minimally-tested version of MDS2 based on more recent, more secure versions of OpenLDAP and Cyrus SASL 
    is available for download at [link]; however, we strongly recommend that any MDS2 users upgrade their system to use the new WSRF-based 
  MDS4, and we will be happy to work with you to make this possible for your project. Please note that in GT4, MDS2 is a deprecated component, 
  which means that it will not be included in the GT4.2 release, nor supported once GT4.4 exists.</simpara></warning>

   <chapter id="c-prewsmds-Release_Notes">
    <?dbhtml filename="Pre_WS_MDS_Release_Notes.html" ?>
&Pre_WS_MDS_Release_Notes;
  </chapter>
 
  <chapter id="c-prewsmds-PreWSMDSFacts">
    <?dbhtml filename="PreWSMDSFacts.html" ?>
&PreWSMDSFacts;
  </chapter>

</book>









