<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<para>The following changes have occurred for Java WS Core since the last stable release, &previousversion;:</para>

  <section>
    <title>New command line tools</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem><simpara>
       The <computeroutput>globus-validate-descriptors</computeroutput> command line tool is used to validate the Web Services Deployment Descriptor (<computeroutput>.wsdd</computeroutput>) files, JNDI configuration files (<computeroutput>jndi-config.xml</computeroutput>), and security descriptors for all services.
      </simpara></listitem>
      <listitem><simpara>
       The <computeroutput>globus-check-environment</computeroutput> command line tool is used to display component version information and to validate JVM version.
      </simpara></listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
 </section>

 <section>
    <title>New common command line options</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem><simpara>
        <computeroutput>-t, --timeout</computeroutput> option is used to configure the client-side timeout value.
      </simpara></listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
 </section>

 <section>
    <title>Standalone container changes</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem><simpara>
       A new <computeroutput>-i</computeroutput> command line option was added to <computeroutput>globus-start-container</computeroutput> to force the container to bind to the specified network address.
      </simpara></listitem>
      <listitem><simpara>
       <computeroutput>globus-start-container</computeroutput> now performs a JVM version check to ensure that at least Java 1.4 JVM is used to start the container.
      </simpara></listitem>
      <listitem><simpara>
       The <computeroutput>OutOfMemoryError</computeroutput> error handling was improved in the standalone container. All <computeroutput>ResourceHome</computeroutput> caches will now be automatically cleared on <computeroutput>OutOfMemoryError</computeroutput> error.
      </simpara></listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
 </section>

 <section>
    <title>GAR deployment/undeployment changes</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem><simpara>
       <computeroutput>globus-deploy-gar</computeroutput> will NOT overwrite the existing GAR deployment by default now. The existing deployment must be undeployed first or the GAR must be deployed with <computeroutput>-overwrite</computeroutput> option.
      </simpara></listitem>
      <listitem><simpara>  
        During GAR deployment the service configuration files such as <computeroutput>.wsdd</computeroutput> files, <computeroutput>jndi-config.xml</computeroutput> file, and security deployment descriptors will now be automatically validated.
      </simpara></listitem>
      <listitem><simpara>
       Client-side type mapping will now be properly removed during GAR undeployment.
      </simpara></listitem>
      <listitem><simpara>
       Both GAR deployment and undeployment operations now explicitly check if the container is currently running. If so, the operation is aborted. The container must be off before deploying or undeploying GAR files.
      </simpara></listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
 </section>

 <section>
    <title>Simpler local invocation</title>
    <para> 
      It is now easier to make local invocations. Axis' <computeroutput>MessageContext</computeroutput> does not need to be associated with the current thread anymore and the stub does not need to be configured in any way to make local invocations.
    </para>
 </section>

 <section>
    <title>Other changes</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem><simpara>
       A new <computeroutput>MessageContextHelper</computeroutput> helper API were added to help in associating an arbitrary <computeroutput>MessageContext</computeroutput> object with the current thread of execution.
      </simpara></listitem>
      <listitem><simpara>
       <computeroutput>GLOBUS_TCP_SOURCE_PORT_RANGE</computeroutput> environment property is now supported.
      </simpara></listitem>
      <listitem><simpara>
       The test framework was extended to allow for execution of a specific test suite or a specific set of test cases within a test suite (<ulink url="http://bugzilla.globus.org/globus/show_bug.cgi?id=3668">Bug 3668</ulink>).
      </simpara></listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
 </section>

 <section>
    <title>Axis changes</title>
    <para>GT &shortversion; release contains a newer version of Apache Axis. The following changes have been noted in Axis:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem><simpara>
        <computeroutput>xsd:group</computeroutput> handling has changed. A Java Bean will NOT be generated now for a xsd:group type. See <ulink url="https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/AXIS-1525">AXIS-1525</ulink> for more details.
      </simpara></listitem>
      <listitem><simpara>
        The ordering of the parameters of the constructors of the generated Java Beans has changed once again. It is recommended to avoid the full constructors of the generated Java Beans. Use individual setter functions to set the values of the Bean instead.
      </simpara></listitem>
      <listitem><simpara>
        An error will now be raised by <computeroutput>BeanSerializer</computeroutput> when serializing a null value that is not optional or non-nillable. This behavior can be disabled by setting <computeroutput>BeanSerializer.errorOnNullWithNonNillableElement</computeroutput> system property to <computeroutput>false</computeroutput>. Example:
<screen>export GLOBUS_OPTIONS=&quot;-DBeanSerializer.errorOnNullWithNonNillableElement=false&quot;</screen>
      </simpara></listitem>
     <listitem><simpara>
        <computeroutput>WSDL2Java</computeroutput> will not generate Java Beans for certain array objects. The <computeroutput>-w</computeroutput> option must be passed to <computeroutput>WSDL2Java</computeroutput> to force it to generate the Java Beans for such types. This change is transparent to the users of the build scripts provided by Java WS Core.
      </simpara></listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
 </section>
