<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<para>The following changes have occurred for Java WS Core:</para>
<itemizedlist>

 <listitem>
  <simpara>
   <computeroutput>globus-deploy-gar</computeroutput> now supports <computeroutput>-backup</computeroutput> option to create a backup of existing service configuration files during deployment.
  </simpara>
 </listitem>

 <listitem>
  <simpara>
   The standalone container when stopped by pressing <computeroutput>Ctrl-C</computeroutput> will now perform the same cleanup operation as when stopped using the <computeroutput>globus-stop-container</computeroutput> tool.
  </simpara>
 </listitem>

 <listitem>
  <simpara>
   The local UDP ports used for sending out the usage statistics information in Java can now be controlled via the <computeroutput>GLOBUS_UDP_SOURCE_PORT_RANGE</computeroutput> environment variable.
  </simpara>
 </listitem>

 <listitem>
  <simpara>
   Axis notification handling was improved to use a thread pool for firing notifications instead of starting a new thread for each notification. Also, the memory overhead associated with each notification was reduced.
  </simpara>
 </listitem>

 <listitem>
  <simpara>
   The standalone container will now use <computeroutput>~/.globus/persisted/&lt;ip&gt;-&lt;port&gt;/</computeroutput> directory to store its persistent information. Under Tomcat the <computeroutput>~/.globus/persisted/&lt;ip&gt;-&lt;webapp.name&gt;/</computeroutput> directory will be used instead. This change enables to easily run multiple standalone containers as the same user on the same machine without any conflicts or to have multiple deployments of Java WS Core (as different web applications) in the same Tomcat installation.
  </simpara>
 </listitem>

 <listitem>
  <simpara>
   Improved Tomcat deployment and support. Also, <computeroutput>ContainerConfig.getBaseDirectory()</computeroutput> and <computeroutput>ContainerConfig.getSchemaDirectory()</computeroutput> API were defined to return the appropriate directory locations depending on the container type. Also, auto flush functionality was added to the Tomcat HTTPS connector code to enable interoperability between a C client and Tomcat 5.0.x.
  </simpara>
 </listitem>

 <listitem>
  <simpara>
   Proper WS-Addressing headers are now added to the SOAP Fault messages. Please see <ulink url="http://bugzilla.globus.org/globus/show_bug.cgi?id=3614">Bug 3614</ulink> for details.
  </simpara>
 </listitem>

</itemizedlist>

