<title>GT 4.0 Java CoG Kit: System Administrator's Guide</title>
<titleabbrev>System Administrator's Guide</titleabbrev> 

<section id="s-javacog-admin-introduction"><title>Introduction</title>
<para>This guide contains
  installation and configuration information for system administrators installing
  the Java CoG Kit. It explains how to install, configure and test the installation. </para>
    <important>
        <simpara> This information is in addition to the basic Globus Toolkit prerequisite, 
          overview, installation, security configuration instructions in the <ulink url="../../admin/docbook/">GT 4.0 System Administrator's Guide</ulink>.  
          Read through this guide before continuing!</simpara>  
    </important>
</section>
<section id="s-javacog-admin-installing"><title>Building and installing</title>

  <para>Java CoG Kit is distributed as part of a default GT 4.0 installation.
        For basic installation instructions, see the <ulink url="../../admin/docbook/">GT 4.0 System Administrator&apos;s Guide</ulink>. No extra installation steps are required for this component.</para>
  <para>The following are optional instructions for more advanced types of installations.
  These are for those advanced users who want to build the latest code from CVS or are just interested in the Java CoG Kit.</para>
  <section id="s-javacog-admin-buildfromsource">
    <title>Building from source</title>
    <informaltable frame="none">
      <tgroup cols="2">
        <tbody>
          <row valign="top">
            <entry>1.</entry>
            <entry>
              <para>
Obtain the source code for Java CoG Kit:
</para>
              <formalpara>
                <title>From CVS</title>
                <para>
<orderedlist>
                    <listitem>
                      <para>
  To get the latest source from CVS execute:
 <screen> cvs -d :pserver:anonymous@cvs.globus.org:/home/dsl/cog/CVS \
     checkout jglobus</screen>
 </para>
 <para>
 Optionally specify <computeroutput>-r globus_4_0_branch</computeroutput> revision to get the latest source code for GT 4.0.x releases.
 </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                      <para>
  Change into the <computeroutput>jglobus</computeroutput> directory.
 <screen> cd jglobus</screen>
 </para>
                    </listitem>
                  </orderedlist></para>
              </formalpara>
              <formalpara>
                <title>From source distribution</title>
                <para><orderedlist>
                    <listitem>
                      <para>
   Untar or unzip the distribution archive.
   <screen> tar xvfz cog-XXX-src.tar.gz</screen>
 </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                      <para>
  Change into the unpacked distribution directory.
   <screen> cd cog-XXX</screen>
 </para>
                    </listitem>
                  </orderedlist></para>
              </formalpara>
            </entry>
          </row>
          <row valign="top">
            <entry>2.</entry>
            <entry>
              <para>Run:
 <screen> ant all</screen>
 </para>
              <para></para>
            </entry>
          </row>
        </tbody>
      </tgroup>
    </informaltable>
  </section>
  <section id="s-javacog-admin-installcoreonlybinary">
    <title>Installing binary distribution</title>
    <informaltable frame="none">
      <tgroup cols="2">
        <tbody>
          <row valign="top">
            <entry>1.</entry>
            <entry>Untar or unzip the distribution archive. <screen> tar xvfz cog-XXX-tar.gz</screen></entry>
          </row>
          <row valign="top">
            <entry>2.</entry>
            <entry>Change into the unpacked distribution directory. <screen> cd cog-XXX</screen></entry>
          </row>
          <row valign="top">
            <entry>3.</entry>
            <entry>Set the <computeroutput>COG_INSTALL_PATH</computeroutput> environment variable to the unpacked distribution directory. <para>On Windows:
<screen> set COG_INSTALL_PATH=c:\cog-1.2</screen>
</para><para>On Unix/Linux:
<screen> setenv COG_INSTALL_PATH /soft/cog-1.2/</screen> or <screen> export COG_INSTALL_PATH=/soft/cog-1.2/</screen>
</para></entry>
          </row>
        </tbody>
      </tgroup>
    </informaltable>
    <para></para>
  </section>
</section>

<section id="s-javacog-admin-configuring"><title>Configuring</title>

<para>
In general no extra configuration is required to use Java CoG Kit. However, in certain cases additional configuration might be required. The Java CoG Kit configuration file is placed in <computeroutput>$HOME/.globus/cog.properties</computeroutput> on Unix/Linux machines or <computeroutput>%USERPROFILE%\.globus\cog.properties</computeroutput> on Windows machines.
</para>

  <section id="s-javacog-admin-configuring-proxy">
    <title>Proxy file location</title>
    <para>By default Java CoG Kit will try to use the same proxy file as used by the C tools. However, in certain cases Java CoG Kit might fail to determine the right proxy file location. In these cases a proxy file location might need to be specified in the configuration file. To set a specific proxy file location just add the following line to the configuration file:
   </para>
   <screen>proxy=&lt;proxy location&gt;</screen> 
   <para>This has the same effect as setting the <computeroutput>X509_USER_PROXY</computeroutput> environment property or Java system property.</para>
  </section>

  <section id="s-javacog-admin-configuring-ip">
    <title>Public IP address</title>
    <para>Sometimes, especially on machines with DHCP enabled, the local IP
          address of the machine might be incorrectly detected by Java or the wrong
          non-public IP address might be used if behind a NAT router or on VPN.
          To configure the public IP 
          address used by Java CoG Kit, add the following line to the 
          configuration file:</para>
    <screen>ip=&lt;current ip&gt;</screen>
    <para>This has the same effect as setting the <computeroutput>GLOBUS_HOSTNAME</computeroutput> environment property or Java system property.</para>
  </section>

  <section id="s-javacog-admin-configuring-signing-policy">
      <title>Signing Policy Location</title>

      <para>Signing policies are read in from the same directory as
      trusted certiricates. All files with
      &lt;caHash&gt;.signing_policy in the same directory as trusted
      certificates are loaded for processing. By default signing
      policies are NOT enforced. </para>

      <para> Signing policy enforcement can be enabled by setting a
      system property <code>java.security.gsi.signing.policy</code> to
      &quot;yes&quot; or &quot;true&quot;. </para>

      <para> Details on signing policy grammar support is outlined <ulink url="http://dev.globus.org/wiki/Signing_Policy">here</ulink>

  </section>

  <section id="s-javacog-admin-configuring-portrange">
    <title>TCP Port Range</title>
    <para>Sometimes it is necessary to restrict the listening port numbers 
           that Java CoG Toolkit will use. To set the port range in the
           configuration file, just add the following line:</para>
    <screen>tcp.port.range=&lt;min&gt;,&lt;max&gt;</screen>
    <para>This has the same effect as setting the <computeroutput>GLOBUS_TCP_PORT_RANGE</computeroutput> environment property or Java system property.</para>
  </section>


</section>

<section id="s-javacog-admin-deploying"><title>Deploying</title>
<para>This section does not apply to the Java CoG Kit.</para>
</section>

<section id="s-javacog-admin-testing"><title>Testing</title>
<para>There are no tests to test the Java CoG installation. However, the unit tests are available with the source distribution. Since some of the unit tests rely on GT2 services to be running, first make sure that they are running ok. Also, you will need to configure the tests (look for various <computeroutput>test.properties</computeroutput> files) in the source distribution with the appropriate information (for example the right service port, hostname, etc.). Finally, to run the tests do:</para>
<screen>ant test</screen>
</section>

<section id="s-javacog-admin-security_considerations"><title>Security considerations</title>
  &JavaCoG_Security_Considerations_Frag;
</section>

<section id="s-javacog-admin-troubleshooting"><title>Troubleshooting</title>
<para>
  Please see the <ulink url="http://www.globus.org/cog/distribution/1.2/FAQ.TXT">FAQ</ulink> and the <ulink url="http://www.globus.org/cog/java/">web page</ulink> for any problems concerning Java CoG Kit. Also, you can send email describing your problem to the <ulink url="mailto:java@globus.org">java@globus.org</ulink> mailing list (<ulink url="http://www.globus.org/subscriptions.php">must subscribe first</ulink>) or search for the problem in the <ulink url="http://www.globus.org/mail_archive/java/threads.html">archives</ulink>.
</para>
</section>




