<chapter id="gtadmin-basic-setup" xreflabel="Setting Up Basic Services for GT &shortversion;">
	<title>Basic Setup for GT &shortversion;</title>
	<para>This section describes initial setup for basic services that will provide a basic set of Grid services on one machine. 
	The <link linkend="quickstart">Quickstart Guide</link> walks you through setting up basic services on multiple machines.</para>
	
	<!-- charles, if this information already exists in component admin guides, let me know and i'll make them into frags
	that will go in both the component-level guide and here. or something like that... -->
	
	
	<section id="gtadmin-basic-setup-gridftp"><title>Setting Up File Transfers (GridFTP)</title>
        <para>To setup GridFTP, you need a basic security setup.  Then you add GridFTP to either xinetd or inetd.</para>
	<para>See <link linkend="q-gridftp">Setup GridFTP</link> for details.</para>
	</section>
	
	<section id="gtadmin-basic-setup-container"><title>Setting Up the Web Services Container (Java WS Core)</title>
		<para>The container hosts the rest of the <glossterm>web service</glossterm>s like RFT, MDS, and GRAM.
        It requires a basic security setup, and an /etc/init.d entry so it starts at boot time.</para>
		<para>See <link linkend="q-container">Container Setup</link> for details.</para>
	</section>
	
	<section id="gtadmin-basic-setup-rft"><title>Setting Up Large Transfers (RFT)</title>
		<para>RFT monitors and controls GridFTP transfers for added reliability.  It requires the Web Services
        container and a Postgres database.</para>
		<para>See <link linkend="q-rft">RFT Setup</link> for details.</para>
	</section>
	
	<section id="gtadmin-basic-setup-wsgram"><title>Setting Up Job Management (WS GRAM)</title>
		<para>GRAM provides a uniform interface to batch schedulers, coordinates data stage-in/out, and
        monitors jobs with optional notifications.  It requires the Web Services container, and uses RFT for
        staging.
		</para>
                <para>See <link linkedn="q-gram">GRAM Setup</link> for details.</para>
		
	</section>
	
	<section id="gtadmin-advanced-setup-index"><title>Discovering and Monitoring Resources with the Index Service (MDS4)</title>
		<para>MDS4 allows for monitoring and discovery in a Grid environment.  It can be used to monitor
        GRAM and RFT, as well as the associated cluster resources with the help of a monitoring provider like
        Ganglia or Clumon.  An Index Service runs in each container, and they can be configured into a reporting
        hierarchy.</para>
		<para>See <link linkend="q-index">MDS Setup</link> for details.</para>
		
	</section>
	
	<section id="gtadmin-advanced-setup-webmds"><title>Visualizing Resources with WebMDS (MDS4)</title>
		<para>The Index Service contains XML data describing resources.  This XML can be visualized
        in a web browser using WebMDS.  WebMDS runs inside of a Tomcat container.</para>
                <para>See <link linkend="q-webmds">WebMDS Setup</link> for details.</para>
	</section>
	
	<section id="gtadmin-advanced-setup-myproxy"><title>Making Proxy Certificates Available with MyProxy</title>
		<para>MyProxy is an optional service to manage certificates for your site.</para>
                <para>See <link linkend="q-myproxy">MyProxy Setup</link> for details.</para>
	</section>
	
	<section id="gtadmin-advanced-setup-multiple-machines"><title>Setting Up on Multiple Machines</title>
		<para>For information about extending your installation to multiple machines, see
                <link linkend="q-toolkit2">Setting up your second machine</link> for details.</para>
	</section>
	
	<section><title>Where To Go From Here</title>
		<para>For more detail about any component, see the <ulink url="&docpath;toc_all.html">
                master list of documentation.</ulink>
                </para>
		
	</section>
	
</chapter>

