<section id="aggregator-execution_aggregator_source-intro"><title>Introduction</title>

    <para>The execution aggregation source provides a way to aggregate
        data (arbitrary XML information) about a registered resource using an arbitrary local
        executable (such as an external script). The executable will be passed registration information as parameters 
        and is expected to output the gathered data, as detailed below.</para>
    
    <para>A basic example of the use of this API is described in the
        <ulink url="http://www-unix.globus.org/toolkit/docs/4.0/info/aggregator/developer/pingtest.html">
            ping test example for the aggregator execution source</ulink></para>
    
    <para>The execution aggregation source will periodically execute an
        identified executable. The identity of the executable and the
        frequency with which it is to run are specified in the registration
        message.</para>

</section>

<section id="aggregator-execution_aggregator_source-config-registration"><title>Registering</title>
    &aggregator_sources_general_config;
</section>

<section id="aggregator-execution_aggregator_source-config-ExecutionAggregatorSource"><title>Configuration file: parameters for the execution aggregator source</title>
    <para>The configuration block for <constant>ExecutionAggregatorSource</constant> (inside the <constant>Content</constant> block) looks like this: </para>
    <screen>
        &lt;Content xsi:type="agg:AggregatorContent"
        xmlns:agg="http://mds.globus.org/aggregator/types"&gt;
        &lt;agg:AggregatorConfig xsi:type="agg:AggregatorConfig"&gt;
        &lt;agg:ExecutionPollType&gt;
        &lt;agg:<emphasis>PollIntervalMillis</emphasis>&gt;<emphasis>interval_in_ms</emphasis>&lt;/agg:<emphasis>PollIntervalMillis</emphasis>&gt;
        &lt;agg:<emphasis>ProbeName</emphasis>&gt;<emphasis>dummy_namespace</emphasis>:<emphasis>filename</emphasis>&lt;/agg:<emphasis>ProbeName</emphasis>&gt;
        &lt;/agg:ExecutionPollType&gt;
        &lt;/agg:AggregatorConfig&gt;
        &lt;agg:AggregatorData/&gt;
        &lt;/Content&gt;
    </screen>
   
    <para>where:</para>
    <variablelist>  
        <varlistentry>
            <term><constant>PollIntervalMillis</constant></term>
            <listitem><para> This parameter is the poll refresh period in milliseconds. </para></listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
            <term><constant>ProbeName</constant></term>
            <listitem><para> This  parameter specifies the path name to the executable file, relative to the <filename>$GLOBUS_LOCATION/libexec/aggrexec</filename> directory. The path
                name should be specified as the local name part of this QName; the namespace part is ignored.</para></listitem>
        </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
</section>
 <section id="aggregator-execution_aggregator_source-troubleshooting"><title>Troubleshooting</title>
     <para>
        If you've properly configured and registered your script for
        execution but are getting errors from the container because it cannot
        find the specified script, there are two likely causes.  </para>
       
     <para>First, make sure that your script/program is executable and is located in the
        <filename>$GLOBUS_LOCATION/libexec/aggrexec</filename> directory.
        When it's specified in the configuration mentioned above, only specify
        the name of the script/program, without any qualification or path.
        For example, using the <constant>ProbeName</constant> as
        <filename>test-script</filename> will be specifying the file
        <filename>$GLOBUS_LOCATION/libexec/aggrexec/test-script</filename>
        script.
    </para>
    <para>
        The second most likely reason for an error is due to recent security
        updates (that only apply to post 4.0 Globus Toolkit releases).  To
        avoid allowing any user to execute arbitrary code, we've added a
        name/mapping pair, which is a key/value pair that the administrator of
        the running container must specify before starting the services.  To
        configure this, look at the example in the
        <filename>$GLOBUS_LOCATION/etc/globus_wsrf_mds_index/jndi-config.xml</filename>
        file.  It can be viewed under the <constant>configuration</constant>
        section (specifically, it's the
        <constant>executableMappings</constant> section), and extend it (using
        a comma delimiter between each name=value entry added) to include your
        own.  Then you use the aliased/logical name that you've just made up
        as the <constant>ProbeName</constant> as in the above configuration
        example.
    </para>
 </section>
 <section id="aggregator-execution_aggregator_source-executable" xreflabel="Configuring the executable"><title>Configuring the executable</title>
     <section><title>Name of executable</title>
         <para>The executable to run will be
             <filename>$GLOBUS_LOCATION/libexec/aggrexec/&lt;scriptname&gt;</filename>
             with <filename>scriptname</filename> supplied by the <constant>ProbeName</constant> parameter in the configuration file.</para>
     </section>
     <section><title>Input to executable</title>
         <para>Information about the registration will be supplied as
             command line parameters and on stdin.</para>
         <para>A single command line parameter will be supplied to the
             executable. This will be the URL from the EPR of the registered
             service.</para>
         <para>Two XML documents will be sent to stdin, in sequence: </para>
             <orderedlist>
             <listitem>The first document will be the full EPR to the registered service. </listitem>
             <listitem>The second document will be the AggregatorConfig block from the registration message (configuration file).</listitem>
         </orderedlist>
     </section>
     <section><title>Output from executable</title>
         <para>The executable must output a well-formed XML document to stdout. This output document will be delivered into the aggregator framework.</para>
     </section>
 </section>
 
