<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd"
[

<!ENTITY % myents SYSTEM "../entities">

%myents;

]>
<article>
<title> GT &shortversion; Samples for WS MDS</title>
<titleabbrev>Samples for WS MDS</titleabbrev>
<section id="wsmds-samples-DefaultIndexService"><title>Building VOs using the DefaultIndexService</title>

<para>
This example shows how to configure the DefaultIndexService so that it will 
register itself to an upstream DefaultIndexService.  By chaining such upstream 
registrations between hosts, it is possible to build a hierarchical virtual 
organization with a complete aggregate data view at the root level.
</para>
  
  <orderedlist>
  <listitem>
    <simpara>Change to the <computeroutput>$GLOBUS_LOCATION/etc/globus_wsrf_mds_index</computeroutput> directory.</simpara>
  </listitem>
  <listitem>
<simpara>    Open the file <computeroutput>hierarchy.xml</computeroutput> 
    and add one or more upstream entries using the URL to DefaultIndexService(s) you wish to register to.  Example syntax for an upstream entry is as follows:</simpara>
    <screen> &lt;upstream&gt;https://vo-host:8443/wsrf/services/DefaultIndexService&lt;/upstream&gt; </screen>
    <simpara>Please note that if a secure container is targeted, make sure to set the correct service url (https protocol, right port number) in the upstream entry.</simpara>
  <orderedlist>
  <listitem>
<simpara>    (This step is optional) Change the default upstream registration settings (if desired) in the <computeroutput>upstream.xml</computeroutput> file:</simpara> 
    <screen> 
      &lt;ServiceGroupRegistrationParameters
      xmlns="http://mds.globus.org/servicegroup/client&gt;
      
      &lt;!-- Specifies that the registration will be renewed every 600
      seconds (= 10 minutes) --&gt;
      &lt;RefreshIntervalSecs&gt;600&lt;/RefreshIntervalSecs&gt;
      
      &lt;Content xsi:type="agg:AggregatorContent"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:agg="http://mds.globus.org/aggregator/types"&gt;
      
      &lt;agg:AggregatorConfig xsi:type="agg:AggregatorConfig"&gt;
      &lt;agg:GetResourcePropertyPollType
      xmlns:wssg= "http://docs.oasis-open.org/wsrf/2004/06/wsrf-WS-ServiceGroup-1.2-draft-01.xsd" &gt;
      &lt;!-- Specifies that the upstream index should refresh information
      every 10 minutes --&gt;
      &lt;agg:PollIntervalMillis&gt;600000&lt;/agg:PollIntervalMillis&gt;
      
      &lt;!-- specified that the upstream index should collect the
      Entry resource properties from this index --&gt;
      &lt;agg:ResourcePropertyName&gt;wssg:Entry&lt;/agg:ResourcePropertyName&gt;
      
      &lt;/agg:GetResourcePropertyPollType&gt;
      &lt;/agg:AggregatorConfig&gt;
      &lt;agg:AggregatorData/&gt;
      &lt;/Content&gt;
      
      &lt;/ServiceGroupRegistrationParameters&gt;
    </screen>   
    <simpara>The two settings of note here are the <computeroutput>RefreshIntervalSecs</computeroutput> 
    and the <computeroutput>PollIntervalMillis</computeroutput> parameters. </simpara>
    <simpara>
      The <computeroutput>RefreshIntervalSecs</computeroutput> parameter specifies 
      that the local DefaultIndexService will attempt to refresh the registration 
      made to the upstream DefaultIndexService every (n) seconds.  If the upstream 
      DefaultIndexService is a high level or root-level member of a VO hierarchy, or 
      is intended to support a large number of registrants, it may be desirable to 
      set the refresh interval to be a larger value so that the overall amount of 
      registration traffic is reduced.  Note that setting the RefreshIntervalSecs 
      to a larger value will not affect the relative "freshness" of the aggregated 
      data from each registrant; rather, this is controlled by the 
      <computeroutput>PollIntervalMillis</computeroutput> parameter of the 
      GetResourcePropertyPollType element.
    </simpara>
    <simpara>
      The GetResourcePropertyPollType element contained within the AggregatorConfig
      element specifies that the upstream DefaultIndexService should poll the 
      local DefaultIndexService "Entry" resource property every (n) milliseconds,
      based on the value of the <computeroutput>PollIntervalMillis</computeroutput> parameter.  
      Alter this parameter in order to control the interval upon which data from 
      the downstream (local) DefaultIndexService is refreshed in the upstream 
      DefaultIndexService.
    </simpara> 
  </listitem>
  </orderedlist>
  </listitem>
  <listitem>
    <simpara>Start the container by running:</simpara>
    <screen> $ bin/globus-start-container</screen>
    <simpara>
      When the DefaultIndexService is first activated, it will read the contents 
      of the hierarchy.xml file and attempt to make an upstream registration for 
      each upstream entry found within that file.  The service will make each 
      registration according to the parameters found in the <computeroutput>upstream.xml</computeroutput>
      file.  Any errors or warnings during the registration process will be written
      to the container log.  If successful, the "Entry" resource property of the 
      upstream Index will contain a child element for the downstream (local) Index, 
      and a copy of the downstream Index "Entry" resource property will be cached
      within that element.
    </simpara> 
  </listitem>
  </orderedlist>
  
</section>




</article>