<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd"
[

<!ENTITY % xinclude SYSTEM "../../xinclude.mod" >
%xinclude;

]>
<chapter id="gridway-developer-debugging">
	<title>Debugging</title>
	<!-- i changed this to incorporate java ws core debugging info - but if that is irrelevent, let me know and i'll 
	undo the changes. cris-->
	<para>We'll begin with debugging the underlying Java WS Core and then discuss debugging in
		GridWay in particular. For information about sys admin logging, see <olink targetdoc="gridwayAdmin" targetptr="gridway-admin-debugging"/> in the 
		Admin Guide.</para>
	<section id="gridway-developer-debugging-jwscore">
		<title>Debugging in Java WS Core</title>
        <para>As GridWay relies on Globus services, it is assumed that a Globus grid infrastructure has been installed and configured.
        Failures related to Globus services (e.g. GRAM or MDS) can be debugged as described in <olink targetdoc="javawscoreDeveloper"
				targetptr="javawscore-developer-debugging"/>.</para>
		<xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
			href="../../common/javawscore/Java_WS_Core_Logging_Frag.xml"
			xpointer="javawscore-developer-logging-general"/>
	</section>
	<section id="gridway-developer-debugging-gridway">
		<title>Debugging in GridWay</title>
		<para> Due to GridWay's architecture, mainly its MADs components, debugging it is not a
			trivial task. The most obvious way to see what is going on is to monitor what happens in
			the GridWay log files. Here are the files to look into in case of trouble: </para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para><emphasis role="strong"><filename
					>$GW_LOCATION/var/gwd.log</filename></emphasis>: This is the general log file,
					where the gwd daemon logs whatever the Resource, Dispatch, Transfer, Execution,
					Information managers inform it about.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><emphasis role="strong"><filename
					>$GW_LOCATION/var/sched.log</filename></emphasis>: The scheduler is a separate
					process that communicates with the daemon using the standard input/output. It
					writes log information to this file.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><emphasis role="strong"><filename
						>$GW_LOCATION/var/&lt;job_id&gt;/job.log</filename></emphasis>: Each job has
					its own log file, with information regarding its context (input/output files,
					MADs, resource) and it's life cycle. In this folder also reside the
					job.template, the job.env with the environment variable and the standard output
					and error of the wrapper script (stdout.wrapper and stderr.wrapper)</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<para>In order to get the maximum amount of debug information in the <filename
			>gwd.log</filename> file (especially more information about what the MADs are doing),
			you should compile GridWay with the following configure option:
			<screen>./configure --enable-debug</screen></para>
		<para> If there is a problem with GridWay that makes any MAD crash, it will be useful to
			have a coredump. To tell the MADs that they should write to a coredump file when they
			crash, use the following environment variable before you execute your first job:
			<screen>export MADDEBUG=yes</screen> Sometimes it is the daemon (the gwd process) that
			crashes. In order to obtain a coredump of the daemon, run the following command before
			executing the daemon: <screen>ulimit -c unlimited</screen> The coredump file will be
			written to the <filename>$GW_LOCATION/var</filename> directory, with a filename
			corresponding to the process PID, that is,
			<screen>$GW_LOCATION/var/core.&lt;process_pid&gt;</screen></para>
		<para>If you cannot figure out what is wrong, you can always use the mailing list <ulink
				url="http://dev.globus.org/wiki/GridWay#Mailing_Lists">gridway-user</ulink> to get
			support. Please provide a detailed explanation of your problem so the community can
			reproduce it and give advice. Also, send along: </para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para><filename>$GW_LOCATION/var/gwd.log</filename></para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><filename>$GW_LOCATION/var/sched.log</filename></para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><filename>$GW_LOCATION/var/&lt;job_id&gt;/{job.log,stderr.wrapper}</filename>: If relevant. The
					<filename>stderr.wrapper</filename> file is specially useful for debugging; it shows step by step the
					wrapper script being executed.</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
	</section>
</chapter>
