<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section id="authzframe-pip-parameter" xreflabel="Parameter PIP"> <title>Parameter PIP</title>
 
 <section><title>Class name</title>
  <para><filename>org.globus.wsrf.impl.security.authorization.ParameterPIP</filename></para>
 </section>
 
 <section><title>Overview</title>
  <para>This PIP extracts configured parameter element from the
  SOAPMessage. The parameter is added as an action attributes in the
  associated RequestAttribute. </para>
 </section>
 
 <section><title>Configuration</title>

  <variablelist>
   <varlistentry><term><filename>parameterConfig</filename></term>
    <listitem>
  <para>
 Property pointing to configuration file with information about the service, method and parameter to extract as attributes. If configured file name is not
  absolute, an attempt is made to find the file as provided, if not an
  attempt is made to locate it relative to GLOBUS_LOCATION and if that
  fails, an attempt it made to locate it relative to current
  directory.</para>

  <para> The configuration file is read and stored as
  SOAPParameter. This class is used to store a specific parameter
  element path for a given operation for a said service.
  <constant>servicePath operationName ParameterPath</constant></para>

  <para> The parameter path is a list of QNames, where each QName is
  QName of a child element of previous QName element. The
  parameterPath is a string with string representation of each QName,
  in the order it needs to be looked into with semicolon (;) as
  delimiter. For example,
  <emphasis>{http://temp.ns}element1;{http://temp.ns}nextElem2;{http://temp.ns}nextElem3</emphasis>
  would represent the parameter {http://temp.ns}nextElem3. The
  SOAPBody element here is {http://temp.ns}element1, with nextElem2 as
  its child and nextElem3 as its child.</para>
    </listitem>
   </varlistentry>
 </variablelist>
 </section>
 
 <section><title>Attributes Collected</title>
  <para>This PIP collects two attributes described in the following tables:</para>
  
  <table><title>Attribute I</title>
   <tgroup cols='2'>
    <tbody>
     <row><entry>Description of attribute</entry><entry>Configured parameter if it occurs in that operation. The value is an object of type org.w3c.dom.Node and represents the parameter of the operation.</entry></row>
     <row><entry>Identity attribute</entry><entry>Identity attribute</entry></row>
     <row><entry>Attribute ID</entry><entry>Parameter path as described in previous section.</entry></row>
     <row><entry>Datatype</entry><entry>Constants.PARAMETER_PATH_DATA_TYPE</entry></row>
     <row><entry>Issuer</entry><entry>Container</entry></row>
     <row><entry>Validity from</entry><entry>Current time</entry></row>
     <row><entry>Validity to</entry><entry>Infinity</entry></row>
    </tbody>
   </tgroup>
  </table>
  
 </section>
 
 <section><title>Related interceptors</title>
  <para> This PIP can be used in tandem with ResourcePropertiesPDP to parameter-based authorization for resource property access.</para>
 </section>
</section>
