<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="authzframe-error-codes"><title>Error Messages</title>
 <indexterm type="authzframe">
  <primary>errors</primary>
 </indexterm>
 
 <table frame='all' id="authzframe-errors-table"><title>WS A&amp;A Authorization Framework Error Messages</title>
<tgroup cols='3' align='left' colsep='1' rowsep='1'>
<colspec colname='c1' />
<colspec colname='c2' />
<colspec colname='c3' />
<thead>
<row>
  <entry>Error Code</entry>
  <entry>Definition</entry>
  <entry>Possible Solutions</entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody>
<row>
  <entry><code>Authorization failed</code></entry>
  <entry>fixme - possible reasons</entry>
  <entry>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis role="strong">Using self authorization</emphasis>: Ensure that the client is running with the same 
         credentials as the effective server-side credential (resource, service, container credential, in the order of occurrence).</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis role="strong">Using host authorization</emphasis>: <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Ensure that the effective server-side credential (resource, service, container credential, in the order of occurrence) 
               is the host credential of the machine on which the service is running. </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>Ensure that the client is not using 127.0.0.1 as the host address to access the service, but the actual host name.</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis role="strong">Using identity authorization</emphasis>: Ensure that the DN matches the server&apos;s DN exactly. 
         If using the command line interface quotes might have to be placed around the DN string for spaces to be maintained.</para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
  </entry>
</row>
  <row>
  <entry><code>No authorization with delegation fails</code></entry>
  <entry>When using GSI Secure Conversation delegation of credentials cannot be done if no authorization of the server is done (that is, 
   if client side authorization is set to none). </entry>
  <entry>
Use any other form of authorization while delegating. Alternatively, <olink targetdoc="delegation">Delegation Service</olink> can be used 
   to delegate credentials in scenarios where delegated credentials are required but no authorization of the server is required.
       <important>
      <para>Delegating credentials without authorizing server is not recommended since a malicious server can obtain the client&apos;s credential.</para>
    </important>
  </entry>
</row>
 <row>
  <entry><code>No grid map file</code></entry>
  <entry>The gridmap file is missing or mis-configured.</entry>
  <entry>
Check to ensure that a <glossterm>grid map file</glossterm> name is configured as shown in 
   <olink targetdoc="wsaajava" targetptr="wsaajava-secdesc-other-defaultGridMap"/> and that the security descriptor with grid map file 
   information is configured correctly.
  </entry>
</row>
<row>
  <entry><code>Authorization failed. Peer is anonymous</code></entry>
  <entry>If an anonymous client is used, only some authorization schemes can authorize them. Self authorization, identity authorization, 
   gridmap authorization and host authorization will fail if anonymous clients are used.</entry>
  <entry>
Ensure that an appropriate authorization scheme is used if anonymous clients are allowed.
  </entry>
</row>
  <row>
  <entry><code>&quot;org.globus.ogsa.security.authorization&quot; property must be of &quot;org.globus.ogsa.impl.security.authorization.Authorization&quot; type</code></entry>
  <entry>Developers see this error on the client side if the authorization instance set on the stub does not implement interface <constant>org.globus.ogsa.impl.security.authorization.Authorization</constant>. A common error is importing authorization classes from <constant>org.globus.gsi.gssapi.auth</constant> rather than from <constant>org.globus.ogsa.impl.security.authorization</constant>.</entry>
  <entry>
 It is recommended that client security descriptors be used to set these properties, so the right classes and properties are setup by the framework.
  </entry>
</row>
 <!-- just copy the <row> block above for each row you need to add -->
</tbody>
</tgroup>
   </table>
 
</section>
