<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<para>The following features have been added to the WS MDS Aggregator component:</para>
<itemizedlist>
<listitem>Two additional configuration options have been added to the AggregatorConfiguration JNDI bean type that allow administrators more control over when notifications are sent out to listeners that have subscribed to the service group 'Entry' resource property.  These changes consist of two boolean parameters, "notifyOnEntryLifetimeExtension" and "notifyOnEntryContentChange".  By default, if the parameters are not supplied, "notifyOnEntryLifetimeExtension" is set to TRUE and "notifyOnEntryContentChange" is set to FALSE.  The "notifyOnEntryLifetimeExtension" parameter causes a notification to be generated whenever a service group entry is added, removed, or refreshed.  The "notifyOnEntryContentChange" causes a notification to be generated whenever an entry has is aggregate content updated. The syntax for specifying these configuration parameters is as follows: 
 <para>
    <screen>
      &lt;resource name="configuration"
                type="org.globus.mds.aggregator.impl.AggregatorConfiguration"&gt; 
      ...
                      
      &lt;parameter&gt;
	&lt;name&gt;notifyOnEntryLifetimeExtension&lt;/name&gt;
	&lt;value&gt;true&lt;/value&gt;
      &lt;/parameter&gt;  
      &lt;parameter&gt;
	&lt;name&gt;notifyOnEntryContentChange&lt;/name&gt;
	&lt;value&gt;false&lt;/value&gt;
      &lt;/parameter&gt;
      
      ...
      &lt;/resource&gt;
    </screen>
  </para>
 </listitem>
    
    
<listitem>
 An additional configuration option has been added to the AggregatorConfiguration JNDI bean type to allow adminstrators to configure the interval in milliseconds at which the the service group's sweeper thread purges out stale registrant entries.  The syntax for specifying the sweeper interval is:
  <para>  
   <screen> 
    &lt;resource name="configuration"
                 type="org.globus.mds.aggregator.impl.AggregatorConfiguration"&gt; 
    ...
                            
    &lt;parameter&gt;
      &lt;name&gt;entrySweeperInterval&lt;/name&gt;
      &lt;value&gt;120000&lt;/value&gt;
    &lt;/parameter&gt;
    
    ...
    &lt;/resource&gt;    
   </screen> 
  </para>
</listitem>   

<listitem>
 An additional configuration option has been added to the AggregatorConfiguration JNDI bean type to allow adminstrators to specify a developer supplied callback function that will be invoked when a service group entry is removed from the service group.  See the API documentation for the AggregatorServiceGroupEntryRemovedCallback interface for implementation details.
  <para>
   <screen>
    &lt;resource name="configuration"
                 type="org.globus.mds.aggregator.impl.AggregatorConfiguration"&gt; 
    ...
                    
    &lt;parameter&gt;
      &lt;name&gt;entryRemovedCallback&lt;/name&gt;
      &lt;value&gt;org.globus.mds.aggregator.impl.SampleAggregatorRemoveCallback&lt;/value&gt;
    &lt;/parameter&gt;
    
    ...
    &lt;/resource&gt;          
   </screen> 
  </para>  
 </listitem>         
</itemizedlist>

