<title>GT 4.0 Reliable File Transfer (RFT) Service: System Administrator's Guide</title>
<titleabbrev> System Administrator's Guide</titleabbrev> 

<section id="s-rft-admin-introduction"><title>Introduction</title>
<para>This guide contains advanced configuration information for system administrators
  working with RFT. It provides references to information on procedures
  typically performed by system administrators, including installation, configuring,
deploying, and testing the installation.</para>
    <important>
        <simpara> This information is in addition to the basic Globus Toolkit prerequisite, 
          overview, installation, security configuration instructions in the <ulink url="http://www.globus.org/toolkit/docs/4.0/admin/docbook/">GT 4.0 System Administrator's Guide</ulink>.  
          Read through this guide before continuing!</simpara>  
    </important>
<para>RFT is used to perform third-party transfers across GridFTP servers. It
  uses a database to store its state periodically
  so the transfers can be recovered from any failures. RFT uses
  standard grid security mechanisms for authorization and authentication
  of the users. In order to effectively use RFT you should have
  installed and configured a database with RFT database schemas and have
  the necessary security infrastructure in place to perform a 3rd party
  transfer.</para>
</section>

<section id="s-rft-admin-installing"><title>Building and Installing</title>
<para>RFT is built and installed as part
      of a default GT 4.0 installation. For basic installation instructions,
  see the <ulink url="http://www.globus.org/toolkit/docs/4.0/admin/docbook/">GT 4.0 System Administrator's
      Guide</ulink>. No extra installation steps
are required for this component.</para>
<para>The following are specialized instructions for advanced
  developers who want to deploy latest code from CVS:</para>
<orderedlist><title>Build RFT from CVS:</title>
      <listitem><para>Configure your CVSROOT to point to the globus CVS location.</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Run:</para>
          <screen>cvs co ws-transfer</screen></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Run:</para>
          <screen>cd ws-transfer/reliable</screen></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Set GLOBUS_LOCATION to point to your globus installation.</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Run:</para>
          <screen>ant deploy </screen></listitem>
</orderedlist>
</section>

<section id="s-rft-admin-configuring" xreflabel="Configuring RFT"><title>Configuring </title>
&RFT_Interface_Config_Frag;

</section>
<section id="s-rft-admin-mysql"><title>Using MySQL</title>
<para> RFT in 4.0.1 works with MySQL database. A MySQL schema file is provided at $GLOBUS_LOCATION/share/globus_wsrf_rft/rft_schema_mysql.sql. You will need to download MySQL drivers (MySQL connector/J 3.1 and not 3.0) from <ulink url="http://dev.mysql.com/downloads/connector/j/3.1.html">here</ulink> and copy the driver jar to $GLOBUS_LOCATION/lib.You will also need to make following changes :</para>
<orderedlist>
<listitem><para>
Create a RFT Database and populate it with mysql schema.</para>
<screen>mysqladmin -h hostname create rftDatabse -p

mysql -h hostname -D rftDatabase

source share/globus_wsrf_rft/rft_schema_mysql.sql

</screen>
<para> <emphasis>Note: If you are using older ( earlier than 4.1 ) versions of mysql you will need to use $GLOBUS_LOCATION/share/globus_wsrf_rft/rft_schema_mysql_pre4.0.sql schema to make RFT work. See <ulink url="http://bugzilla.globus.org/globus/show_bug.cgi?id=3633">Bug 3633</ulink> for more details.</emphasis></para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para> Edit $GLOBUS_LOCATION/etc/globus_wsrf_rft/jndi-config.xml and change values of connectionString to jdbc:mysql:///rftDatabase from jdbc:postgresql://host/rftDatabase and driverName to com.mysql.jdbc.Driver from org.postgresql.Driver and userName and password to whatever was set during creation of users for mysql.</para>
</listitem>
</orderedlist>
</section>
<section id="s-rft-admin-deploying"><title>Deploying</title>
<para>RFT is deployed as part of a standard toolkit installation. Please refer to the <ulink url="../../admin/docbook/">System Administrator's Guide</ulink> for details.</para>

<section id="s-rft-admin-deploying-tomcat"><title>Deploying into Tomcat</title>
  <para> RFT has been tested to work without any additional setup when deployed into Tomcat. Please follow these <ulink url="http://www.globus.org/toolkit/docs/4.0/common/javawscore/admin-index.html#javawscore-admin-tomcat-deploying">basic instructions</ulink> to deploy GT4 services into Tomcat. Note: you need to configure the GT4 install with the needed RFT configuration (like database configuration, etc) before you deploy into Tomcat.</para>
</section>
</section>

<section id="s-rft-admin-testing"><title>Testing</title>
<orderedlist><title>RFT Testing</title>
      <listitem>
      <para>Set <computeroutput> $GLOBUS_LOCATION </computeroutput> to point to your Globus install.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
      <para>Start a gridftp server on the machine you are running the
tests on the default port. This can be done by running: </para>
      <screen>$GLOBUS_LOCATION/sbin/globus-gridftp-server -p 2811 &amp;</screen>
      </listitem>
      <listitem><para>Start the container with RFT deployed in it.</para></listitem>
      <listitem>
      <para>Edit $GLOBUS_LOCATION/share/globus_wsrf_rft_test/test.properties. Put in appropriate values for properties like authzValue (self or host), HOST (host ip of container), PORT (port on which the container is listening), sourceHost and destinationsHost (hostnames of gridftp servers). The default values will work fine if you are running the tests with a standard stand-alone container started with user credentials (self authorization is done in this case). If the container is started using host credentials, change authzVal to host. If the gridftp servers you are using for your testing are started as user, you need to supply subject names of the users in sourceSubject and destinationSubject for authorization with gridftp servers. If both the source and destination servers are started as one user, you can just fill in the user's subject in the subject field of test.properties. <emphasis>If you are getting Authentication/Authorization Failures because of mismatched subject names then your authzVal and authType (uses transport security by default) need to be changed, depending on how you start the container. If you started the container with the -nosec option then you need to change authType to GSI_MESSAGE, PROTOCOL to http and PORT to 8080. </emphasis> </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
      <para>The *.xfr files in  $GLOBUS_LOCATION/share/globus_wsrf_rft_test/ are the transfer files that will be used in the tests. Again, the default values work fine if you followed the instructions so far.</para>
      </listitem>
    <listitem>
    <para>Run the following command, which will run all the RFT unit tests:</para>
    <screen>ant -Dtests.jar=$GLOBUS_LOCATION/lib/globus_wsrf_rft_test.jar -f share/globus_wsrf_rft_test/runtests.xml</screen>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
    <para>Run the following command to generate the test reports in html form:</para>
    <screen> ant -f  share/globus_wsrf_rft_test/runtests.xml generateTestReport</screen>
    </listitem>
</orderedlist>
</section>


<section id="s-rft-admin-security_considerations"><title>Security Considerations </title>
&RFT_Security_Considerations_Frag;
</section>

<section id="s-rft-admin-troubleshooting"><title>Troubleshooting</title>
<section><title>PostgreSQL not configured</title>
  <para><emphasis>Problem:</emphasis> If RFT is not configured properly to talk to a PostgreSQL
  database, you will see this message displayed on the console when you start
the container:</para>
<screen>"Error creating RFT Home: Failed to connect to database ... 
Until this is corrected all RFT request will fail and all GRAM jobs that require staging will fail". </screen>
<para><emphasis>Solution:</emphasis> The usual cause is that Postmaster is not accepting TCP connections, which means that you must restart Postmaster with the -i option (see <xref linkend="s-rft-admin-postgresql"/>).</para>
</section>
  
  <section><title>More verbose error messages</title>
  <para><emphasis>Problem:</emphasis> Make RFT print more verbose error messages</para>
<para><emphasis>Solution:</emphasis> Edit $GLOBUS_LOCATION/container-log4j.properties 
and add the following line to it: 
<computeroutput>log4j.category.org.globus.transfer=DEBUG</computeroutput>. For more verbosity add
<computeroutput>log4j.category.org.globus.ftp=DEBUG</computeroutput>, which will print out Gridftp
messages too.
</para></section>
    &RFT_Recovery_Frag;


</section>

<section id="s-rft-admin-usage"><title>Usage statistics collection by the Globus Alliance </title>
&RFT_Usage_Statistics_Frag;
</section>



