<chapter id="common-key"><?dbhtml filename="Key_Concepts.html" ?>
          <title>Key Concepts for Common Runtime Components</title>
           <titleabbrev>Key Concepts</titleabbrev>

  <section id="common-key-overview"><?dbhtml filename="Key_Concepts_Overview.html" ?>
  <title>Overview</title>
<para>The common runtime components provide GT4 web and pre-web
services with a set of libraries and tools that allows these services
to be platform independent, to build on various abstraction layers
(threading, io) and to leverage functionality lower in the web services
stack (WSRF, WSN, etc).</para>

<para>
These components are architecturally diverse and it is thus hard to
identify a overarching theme. Instead a few sub-themes have been
identified and elaborated on in the below.
</para>
</section>

  <section id="common-key-details"><?dbhtml filename="Key_Concepts_Details.html" ?>
    <title>Conceptual Details</title>

<section><title>Web Services</title>
<para>We introduce basic concepts relating to Web services and their use
and implementation within GT4, in particular within the "WS Core"
(Java &amp; C) components.</para>
<section><title>GT4, Distributed Systems, and Web Services</title>
<para>GT4 is a set of software components for building distributed
systems: systems in which diverse and discrete software agents interact
via message exchanges over a network to perform some tasks. Distributed
systems face particular challenges relating to sometimes high and
unpredictable network latencies, the possibility of partial failure,
and issues of concurrency. In addition, system components may be
located within distinct administrative domains, thus introducing issues
of decentralized control and negotiation.</para>
<para>GT4 is, more specifically, a set of software components that (with
some exceptions) implement Web services mechanisms for building
distributed systems. Web services provide a standard means of
interoperating between different software applications running on a
variety of platforms and/or frameworks.</para>
<para>A Web service is a software system designed to support
interoperable machine-to-machine interaction over a network. It has an
interface described in a machine-processable format (specifically
WSDL). Other systems interact with the Web service in a manner
prescribed by its description using SOAP messages, typically conveyed
using HTTP with an XML serialization in conjunction with other
Web-related standards.<!--<ulink url="#ws-arch">*</ulink>--></para>
<para>
Web services standardize the messages that entities in a distributed
system must exchange in order to perform various operations. At the
lowest level, this standardization concerns the protocol used to
transport messages (typically HTTP), message encoding (SOAP), and
interface description (WSDL). A client interacts with a Web service by
sending it a SOAP message; the client may subsequently receive response
message(s) in reply. At higher levels, other specifications define
conventions for securing message exchanges (e.g., WS-Security), for
management (e.g., WSDM), and for higher-level functions such as
discovery and choreography. Figure 1 presents a view of these different
component technologies; we discuss specific specifications below in <xref linkend="s-key-Web_Services_Specifications"/>.</para>

<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
      <imagedata entityref="WSStack"/>
  </imageobject>
  <textobject>
      <phrase>Figure 1: An abstract view of the various specifications that define the Web services architecture</phrase>
  </textobject>
  <caption>
      <para>Figure 1: An abstract view of the various specifications that define the Web services architecture</para>
  </caption>
</mediaobject>
  
</section>

<section><title>Service Oriented Applications and Infrastructure</title>
<para>
Web services technologies, and GT4 in particular, can be used to build
both service-oriented applications and service-oriented infrastructure.
Deferring discussion of the sometimes controversial term
"service-oriented" to later in <xref linkend="s-key-Service_Oriented_Architecture"/>,
we note that a service-oriented
application is constructed via the composition of components defined by
service interfaces (in the current context, Web services): for example,
a financial or biological database, an options pricing routine, or a
biological sequence analyzer. Many descriptions of Web services and SOAP
focus on the task of defining interfaces to such components, often
illustrating their discussion with examples such as a "stock quote
service" (the "hello world" of Web services).</para>
<para>Particularly when servicing many such requests from a distributed
community, we face the related problem of orchestrating and managing
numerous distributed hardware and software components. Web services can
be used for this purpose also, and thus we introduce the term
service-oriented infrastructure to denote the resource management and
provisioning mechanisms used to meet quality of service goals for
components and applications. Many GT4 features are concerned with
enabling the construction of service-oriented infrastructure.</para>
</section>

<section><title>Web Services Implementation</title>
<para>From the client perspective, a Web service is simply a
network-accessible entity that processes SOAP messages. Things are
somewhat more complex under the covers. To simplify service
implementation, it is common for a Web services implementation to
distinguish between:</para>
<orderedlist>
  <listitem><simpara>the hosting environment (or container), the
(domain-independent) logic used to receive a SOAP message and identify
and invoke the appropriate code to handle the message, and potentially
also to provide related administration functions, and:</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara>the Web service implementation, the (domain-specific) code that
handles the message.</simpara></listitem>
</orderedlist>
<para>
This separation of concerns means that the developer need only provide
the domain-specific message handling code to implement a new service.
It is also common to further partition the hosting environment logic
into that concerned with transporting the SOAP message (typically via
HTTP, thus an "HTTP engine" or "Web server"-sometimes termed an
"application server") and that concerned with processing SOAP messages
(the "SOAP engine" or "SOAP processor"). Figure 2 illustrates these
various components.</para>

<mediaobject>
<imageobject>
<imagedata entityref="WSContainer"/>
<!-- height="289" width="606"-->
</imageobject>
  <textobject>
    <phrase>Figure 2: WS Container. High-level picture of functional components commonly
      encountered in Web service implementations, showing the path taken by
      requests and responses.</phrase>
  </textobject>
  <caption><para><emphasis>Figure 2: WS Container. </emphasis> High-level picture of functional components commonly
encountered in Web service implementations, showing the path taken by
requests and responses.</para>
</caption>
</mediaobject>

<para>Many different containers exist, with different performance
properties,
supported Web services implementation languages, security support, and
so forth. We mention below those used in GT4.</para>
</section>

<section id="s-key-Web_Services_Specifications"><title>Web Services
Specifications</title>
<para>We provide pointers to the Web services specifications that
underlie GT4. These comprise the core specifications that define the
Web
services architecture (XML, SOAP, WSDL); WS-Security and other
specifications relating to security; and the WS-Addressing, WSRF, and
WS-Notification specifications used to define, name, and interact with
stateful resources. We also speak briefly to emerging specifications
that are likely to be important in future GT evolution. An important
source of information on the requirements that motivate the use and
development of these specifications is the Open Grid Services
Architecture.</para>
</section>

<section><title>XML, SOAP, WSDL</title>
<para>XML is used extensively within Web services as a standard, flexible,
and extensible data format. In addition to XML syntax, other important
specifications are XML Schema and XML Namespaces. Note that
while current Web services tools typically adopt a textual
serialization, a binary encoding is also possible and may provide
higher efficiency.</para>

<para>SOAP 1.2 provides a standard, extensible, composable framework for
packaging and exchanging XML messages between a service provider and a
service requester. SOAP is independent of the underlying transport
protocol, but is most commonly carried on HTTP.</para>
<para>WSDL 1.1 is an XML document for describing Web services.
Standardized binding conventions
define how to use WSDL in conjunction with SOAP and other messaging
substrates. WSDL interfaces can be compiled
to generate proxy code that constructs messages and manages
communications on behalf of the client application. The proxy
automatically maps the XML message structures into native language
objects that can be directly manipulated by the application. The proxy
frees the developer from having to understand and manipulate XML.</para>
</section>

<section><title>WS-Security and Friends</title>
<para>
The WS-Security family of specifications addresses a range of issues
relating to authentication, authorization, policy representation, and
trust negotiation in a Web services context. GT4 uses a number of
these specifications plus other related specifications, notably
Security Authorization Markup Language (SAML), to address message
protection, authentication, delegation, and authorization, as follows:</para>
<itemizedlist>
  <listitem><simpara>TLS (transport-level) or WS-Security and WS-SecureConversation
(message
level) are used as message protection mechanisms in combination with
SOAP.</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara>X.509 End Entity Certificates or Username and Password are used
as
authentication credentials.</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara>X.509 Proxy Certificates and WS-Trust are used for delegation.</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara>SAML assertions are used for authorization.</simpara></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
</section>

<section><title>WS-Addressing, WSRF, and WS-Notification</title>
<para>A number of related specifications provide functionality important
for
service oriented infrastructure in which we need to be able to
represent and manipulate stateful entities such as physical resources
of various kinds, logical components such as software licenses, and
transient activities such as tasks and workflows.</para>
<para>The WS-Addressing specification defines transport-neutral
mechanisms to address Web services and messages. Specifically, this
specification defines XML elements to identify Web service endpoints
and to secure end-to-end endpoint identification in messages.</para>
<para>The WS Resource Framework (WSRF) specifications define a generic and
open framework for modeling and accessing stateful resources using Web
services. This framework comprises mechanisms to describe
views on the state (WS-ResourceProperties), to support management of
the state through properties associated with the Web service
(WS-ResourceLifetime), to describe how these mechanisms are extensible
to groups of Web services (WS-ServiceGroup), and to deal with faults
(WS-BaseFaults).</para>

<para>The WS-Notification family of specifications define a pattern-based
approach to allowing Web services to disseminate information to one
another. This framework comprises mechanisms for basic
notification (WS-Notification), topic-based notification (WS-Topics),
and brokered notification (WS-BrokeredNotification).</para>

<para>We note that the Web services standards space is in some turmoil due
to
competing proposed specifications. In particular, Microsoft and others
recently proposed WS-Transfer, WS-Eventing, and WS-Management, which
define similar functionality to WSRF, WS-Notification, and
WSDM (discussed below), respectively, but using different syntax. We
hope that these differences will be resolved in the future.</para>
</section>

<section><title>Other Relevant Specifications</title>
<para>The WS-Interoperability (WS-I) organization has produced a
number
of profiles that define ways in which existing Web services
specifications can be used to promote interoperability among different
implementations. The WS-I Basic Profile speaks to messaging and service
description: primarily XML, SOAP, and WSDL. The WS-I Basic Security
Profile speaks to basic security mechanisms. Other profiles are under
development.</para>
<para>Web services distributed management (WSDM) specifications under
development within OASIS are likely to play a role in future GT
implementations as a means of managing GT components.</para>

<para>WS-CIM specifications under development within DMTF are likely
to
play a role in future GT implementations as a means of representing
physical and virtual resources.</para>

<para>The Global Grid Forum's Open Grid Services Architecture (OGSA)
working
group has completed a document that provides a high-level description
of the functionality required for future service-oriented
infrastructure and applications, and a framework that suggests how this
functionality can be factored into distinct specifications. The
OGSA working group is now proceeding to define OGSA Profiles that, like
WS-I profiles, will identify technical specifications that can be used
to address specific Grid scenarios.</para>
</section>

<section id="s-key-Service_Oriented_Architecture"><title>Service Oriented
Architecture</title>
<para>We provide some additional discussion concerning the term service
oriented architecture (SOA), which is used widely but not necessarily
consistently within the Web services community. One common usage is
simply to indicate the use of Web services technologies. However, the
intention of those who coined the term seems to be rather to contrast
two different styles of building distributed systems. Distributed
object systems are distributed systems in which the semantics of object
initialization and
method invocation are exposed to remote systems by means of a
proprietary or standardized mechanism to broker requests across system
boundaries, marshal and unmarshal method argument data, etc.
Distributed objects systems typically (albeit not necessarily) are
characterized by objects maintaining a fairly complex internal state
required to support their methods, a fine grained or "chatty"
interaction between an object and a program using it, and a focus on a
shared implementation type system and interface hierarchy between the
object and the program that uses it.</para>
<para>In contrast, a Service Oriented Architecture (SOA) is a form of distributed systems architecture that is typically
characterized by the following properties:
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem><simpara>Logical view: The service is an abstracted, logical view of
actual
programs, databases, business processes, etc., defined in terms of what
it does, typically carrying out a business-level operation.</simpara></listitem>
    <listitem><simpara>Message orientation: The service is formally defined in terms
of the messages
exchanged between provider agents and requester agents, and not the
properties of the agents themselves. The internal structure of an
agent, including features such as its implementation language, process
structure and even database structure, are deliberately abstracted away
in the SOA: using the SOA discipline one does not and should not need
to know how an agent implementing a service is constructed. A key
benefit of this concerns so-called legacy systems. By avoiding any
knowledge of the internal structure of an agent, one can incorporate
any software component or application that can be "wrapped" in message
handling code that allows it to adhere to the formal service
definition.</simpara></listitem>
    <listitem><simpara>Description orientation: A service is described by
machine-processable metadata. The description supports the public
nature of the SOA: only those details that are exposed to the public
and important for the use of the service should be included in the
description. The semantics of a service should be documented, either
directly or indirectly, by its description.</simpara></listitem>
    <listitem><simpara>Granularity: Services tend to use a small number of operations
with
relatively large and complex messages.</simpara></listitem>
    <listitem><simpara>Network orientation: Services tend to be oriented toward use
over a
network, though this is not an absolute requirement.</simpara></listitem>
    <listitem><simpara>Platform neutral: Messages are sent in a platform-neutral,
standardized
format delivered through the interfaces. XML is the most obvious format
that meets this constraint.</simpara></listitem>
  </itemizedlist><!--<ulink url="#ws-arch">*</ulink>-->
</para>
<para>It is argued that these features can allow service-oriented
architectures to cope more effectively with issues that arise in
distributed systems, such as problems introduced by latency and
unreliability of the underlying transport, the lack of shared memory
between the caller and object, problems introduced by partial failure
scenarios, the challenges of concurrent access to remote resources, and
the fragility of distributed systems if incompatible updates are
introduced to any participant.</para>
<para>Web services technologies in general, and GT4 in particular, can be
used to build both distributed object systems and service-oriented
architectures. The specific design principles to be followed in a
particular setting will depend on a variety of issues, including target
environment, scale, platform heterogeneity, and expected future
evolution.</para>
</section>
</section>
  </section>
  <section id="common-key-relateddocs"><?dbhtml filename="Key_Concepts_Related_Docs.html" ?><title>Related Documents</title>
<section><title>Web Services</title>
<itemizedlist>
<listitem><simpara><!--<ulink name="ws-arch"></ulink>--><ulink url="http://www.w3.org/TR/2003/WD-ws-arch-20030808/">
Booth, D., Haas, H., McCabe, F., Newcomer, E., Champion, M.,
Ferris, C. and Orchard, D. Web Services Architecture. W3C, Working
Draft</ulink></simpara></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
</section>
</section>
</chapter>