<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<section><title>Programming Model Overview</title>
<para>The aggregator framework module consists of an Aggregating
ServiceGroup framework which supports plugins as detailed below, as
well as a number of standard plugins.</para>
</section>
<section><title>The Aggregating ServiceGroup framework</title>
<para>The aggregating servicegroup framework is designed to facilitate
the collecting of information from or about WS-Resources (via
    plugin <glossterm linkend="aggregator-source">aggregator sources</glossterm>) and the feeding of that information to
plugin aggregator sinks.</para>
<para>The framework provides for over-the-wire management of the list
of registered resources (through a WS-ServiceGroup interface) and a
Java API for connecting sources and sinks together.</para>
<para>In general (although this is not a hard requirement), aggregator
sinks will be tied into a specific service implementation, while
aggregator sources are more independent. (For example, the trigger
and index services act as sinks)</para>
</section>
<section><title>The standard plugins</title>
<para>A number of standard aggregator sources are provided, which
implement the aggregator source API. These provide for collecting
information from/about a WS-Resource by:
<itemizedlist>
<listitem><simpara>WS-ResourceProperties poll operations</simpara></listitem>
<listitem><simpara>WS-Notification subscription</simpara></listitem>
<listitem><simpara>Execution of arbitrary executables</simpara></listitem>
</itemizedlist></para>
    <para>See <xref linkend="aggregator-sources"/> for more information about standard aggregator sources for GT 4.0.</para>
</section>
<section><title>Component API</title>
<para>There are two main Java interfaces in the aggregator
framework.
<itemizedlist>
<listitem><simpara><ulink url=
    "http://www-unix.globus.org/api/javadoc-4.0.0/globus_wsrf_mds_aggregator/org/globus/mds/aggregator/impl/AggregatorSink.html">
AggregatorSink</ulink> - which is implemented by sinks that can receive
data from the aggregator framework.</simpara></listitem>
<listitem><simpara><ulink url=
    "http://www-unix.globus.org/api/javadoc-4.0.0/globus_wsrf_mds_aggregator/org/globus/mds/aggregator/impl/AggregatorSource.html">
AggregatorSource</ulink> - which is implemented by sources that can
feed data into the aggregator framework.</simpara></listitem>
</itemizedlist></para>
<para>
In addition, the AggregatorContent class is used when configuring an aggregator service
programmatically, and to represent the data published in the aggregator's
<constant>Entry</constant> resource property.
All aggregator classes and interfaces are documented in the
<ulink url="http://www-unix.globus.org/api/javadoc-4.0.0/globus_wsrf_mds_aggregator/">aggregator Java API documentation</ulink>
</para>
</section>
