<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<para>The Aggregator Framework does not have its own service side configuration, although services which are based on the framework
  have their own service side configuration options (such as <link linkend="index">MDS Index</link> and <link linkend="trigger">MDS Trigger"</link>) which are documented in the per-service documentation.</para>
  
  <para>Registrations to a working Aggregator Framework are configured
    for the <xref linkend="mds-servicegroup-add"/> tool. This tool takes an XML configuration file listing
    registrations, and causes those registrations to be made.</para>
    
    <para> In general, configuration of aggregator services involves configuring the service to get information from one or more sources in a Grid. 
      The mechanism for doing this is defined by (inherited from) the Aggregator Framework and described in this section.</para>
    <!-- 
    [summarize the technical stuff  'servicegroup'/aggregatorcontent object
  -->
  
<section><title>Configuration overview</title>
<para>Configuring an Aggregating Service Group to perform a data
aggregation is performed by specifying an AggregatorContent object
as the content parameter of a ServiceGroup <emphasis><emphasis>add</emphasis></emphasis> method
invocation. An AggregatorContent object is composed of two
xsd:any arrays: AggregatorConfig and AggregatorData:</para>
<itemizedlist>
  <listitem><simpara>The AggregatorConfig xsd:any array is used to specify parameters that are to be
passed to the underlying AggregatorSource when the ServiceGroup
<emphasis>add</emphasis> method is invoked. These parameters are
generally type-specific to the implementation of the
AggregatorSource and/or AggregatorSink being used.</simpara></listitem>
<listitem><simpara>The AggregatorData xsd:any array is used as the storage
location for aggregated data that is the result of message
deliveries to the AggregatorSink. Generally, the
AggregatorData parameter of the AggregatorContent is not populated
when the ServiceGroup <emphasis><emphasis>add</emphasis></emphasis> method is invoked, but
rather is populated by message delivery from the
AggregatorSource.</simpara></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
</section>
<section><title>Syntax of the interface</title>
<section id="aggregator-configuring_source"><title>Configuring the Aggregator Sources</title>
<para>The following links provide information for configuring the three types of aggregator sources provided by the Globus Toolkit:</para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem><simpara><xref linkend="aggregator-sources-execution"/></simpara></listitem>
    <listitem><simpara><xref linkend="aggregator-sources-query"/></simpara></listitem>
    <listitem><simpara><xref linkend="aggregator-sources-subscription"/></simpara></listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
</section>
<section id="aggregator-configuring_aggregatorsink"><title>Configuring the Aggregator Sink</title>
  
  <para>An aggregator sink may require sink-specific configuration (the MDS <glossterm>Trigger Service</glossterm> requires sink-specific configuration; the MDS <glossterm>Index Service</glossterm> does not). See the documentation for the specific <glossterm baseform="aggregator services">aggregator service</glossterm> being used for details on sink-specific
  documentation.</para>
  
</section>
</section>