<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<table><title>Globus standard environment variables</title>
<tgroup cols="4"><tbody>
<row>
 <entry><emphasis>Name</emphasis></entry>
 <entry><emphasis>Value</emphasis></entry>
 <entry><emphasis>Description</emphasis></entry>
 <entry><emphasis>Comments</emphasis></entry>
</row>

<row>
 <entry>GLOBUS_LOCATION</entry>
 <entry>&lt;path&gt;</entry>
 <entry>The &lt;path&gt; is the root location of the Java WS Core installation. 
     Must be an absolute path.
 </entry>
 <entry>Required</entry>
</row>

<row>
 <entry>GLOBUS_TCP_PORT_RANGE</entry>
 <entry>&lt;min,max&gt;</entry>
 <entry>The &lt;min,max&gt; is the minimum and maximum port range for TCP server sockets (useful for systems behind firewalls). For example, if set, the 
  notification sink on the client will be started within that port range.
 </entry>
 <entry>Optional</entry>
</row>

<row>
 <entry>GLOBUS_TCP_SOURCE_PORT_RANGE</entry>
 <entry>&lt;min,max&gt;</entry>
 <entry>The &lt;min,max&gt; is the minimum and maximum port range for TCP outgoing sockets (useful for systems behind firewalls).
 </entry>
 <entry>Optional</entry>
</row>


<row>
 <entry>GLOBUS_UDP_SOURCE_PORT_RANGE</entry>
 <entry>&lt;min,max&gt;</entry>
 <entry>The &lt;min,max&gt; is the minimum and maximum port range for UDP outgoing sockets (useful for systems behind firewalls). 
 </entry>
 <entry>Optional</entry>
</row>

<row>
 <entry>GLOBUS_HOSTNAME</entry>
 <entry>&lt;host&gt;</entry>
 <entry>The &lt;host&gt; is either a hostname or ip address. The host ip address under which the container and services will be exposed.
 </entry>
 <entry>Optional</entry>
</row>

</tbody></tgroup>
</table>



<table><title>Launch script specific environment variables</title>
<tgroup cols="4"><tbody>
<row>
 <entry><emphasis>Name</emphasis></entry>
 <entry><emphasis>Value</emphasis></entry>
 <entry><emphasis>Description</emphasis></entry>
 <entry><emphasis>Comments</emphasis></entry>
</row>

<row>
 <entry>GLOBUS_OPTIONS</entry>
 <entry>&lt;arguments&gt;</entry>
 <entry>
   The &lt;arguments&gt; are arbitrary arguments that can be passed to the JVM.
   See below for a detailed list of supported options.</entry>
 <entry>Optional</entry>
</row>

<row>
 <entry>JAVA_HOME</entry>
 <entry>&lt;path&gt;</entry>
 <entry>The &lt;path&gt; is the root location of the JVM installation. If set, the JVM from that installation will be used. Otherwise, the first one found in path will be used.
 </entry>
 <entry>Optional</entry>
</row>

<row>
 <entry>CLASSPATH</entry>
 <entry>&lt;classpath&gt;</entry>
 <entry>This environment property is ignored by launch scripts.
 </entry>
 <entry>Ignored</entry>
</row>
</tbody></tgroup>
</table>


   <table><title>Options supported by the <computeroutput>GLOBUS_OPTIONS</computeroutput> environment property</title>
<tgroup cols="3"><tbody>
   <row>
     <entry><emphasis>Name</emphasis></entry>
     <entry><emphasis>Value</emphasis></entry> 
     <entry><emphasis>Description</emphasis></entry>
   </row>
   
   <row>
     <entry>-Dorg.globus.wsrf.proxy.port</entry>
     <entry>int</entry>
     <entry>This property specifies the port number of the proxy server. The proxy server must run on the same machine as the container. This setting will cause the service 
      address to have the port of the proxy instead of the container (only applies to code that uses the <computeroutput>ServiceHost</computeroutput> or 
      <computeroutput>AddressingUtils</computeroutput> API.</entry>
   </row>

   <row>
     <entry>-Dorg.globus.wsrf.container.server.id</entry>
     <entry>string</entry>
     <entry>This property specifies the server id. The server id is used to uniquely identify each container instance. For example, each container gets its own persistent directory based on the server id. By default the standalone container will store the persistent resources under the <computeroutput>~/.globus/persisted/&lt;ip&gt;-&lt;containerPort&gt;</computeroutput> directory. While in Tomcat the <computeroutput>~/.globus/persisted/&lt;ip&gt;-&lt;webApplicationName&gt;</computeroutput> directory will be used instead. This property overwrites the default server id and therefore indirectly controls which storage directory is used by the container. If set, the container will store the persisted resources under <computeroutput>~/.globus/persisted/&lt;server.id&gt;/</computeroutput> instead. Note, that if somehow multiple containers running as the same user on the same machine end up with the same server id / persistent directory they might overwrite each other's persistent data.
     </entry>
   </row>

   <row>
     <entry>-Dorg.globus.wsrf.container.persistence.dir</entry>
     <entry>directory</entry>
     <entry>This property specifies the base directory that will be used for storing the persistent resources. This property overwrites the default (<computeroutput>~/.globus/persisted/</computeroutput>) base directory assumed by the container.</entry>
   </row>

</tbody></tgroup>
</table>

<para>Any JVM options can also be passed using the <computeroutput>GLOBUS_OPTIONS</computeroutput> environment property.</para>






