<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
                    "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd"
[
      <!ENTITY % myents SYSTEM "../../entities">
      
      %myents; 

]>


<book><title>Documentation Primer</title><?dbhtml filename="index.html" ?>
	<!-- Based on OpenACS documentation here: http://openacs.org/doc/current/docbook-primer.html  -->
	
	<!-- cris needs to make two different versions of this doc - one for 4.0 and one for development/4.2-drafts/ (since they are structurally different) -->
	
	<chapter  id="overview" xreflabel="Overview of Globus Toolkit Documentation"><title>Overview of Globus Toolkit Documentation</title>
		
		<para>This document includes the policies and guidelines behind the documentation for GT distributions, requirements for documents and help for using
			the DocBook XML Schema for common documentation elements.</para>
		
		<para>Our goal is to provide comprehensive documentation in a clear concise manner and in language that is not too technical or obscure. To that 
			end, we encourage all feedback, suggestions and comments for improving our documentation and finding ways to make the information more easily 
			understandable. For broken links and other simple technical issues with using the docs online, send an email to <ulink url="mailto:webmaster@globus.org">
				webmaster@globus.org</ulink>. For everything else, file a bug in <ulink url="http://www.globus.org/toolkit/docs/development/bugzilla.html">
					Bugzilla</ulink> (use the <emphasis role="strong">Documentation</emphasis> project).</para>
		
		<para>We thank you ahead of time for your help.</para>
		
	</chapter>
	
	<chapter  id="strategy" xreflabel="Globus Toolkit Documentation Strategy"><title>Globus Toolkit Documentation Strategy</title>

	<para>Starting with GT 4.0, we use templates of the minimum required topics for each project. During the development process, 
		more and more information is added and refined with each release. This process is facilitated by
		the <ulink url="mailto:cristina@isi.edu">Documentation Coordinator</ulink> and Technical Product Manager. With each development release, 
		the documentation becomes more and more complete. This iterative process allows the documentation to be built up over time instead of in a
		rush right before final release. When development for the next major version begins, we copy the existing documentation to a
		<computeroutput>docs/development/[version]-drafts/</computeroutput> directory and then the Project Chairs build on those docs.</para>
	
	<section id="fragments" xreflabel="Fragments"><title>Fragments</title>
		
		<para>To reduce duplication and make sure we have a single source for all information, 
			we also utilize 'fragments' of frequently used information. For example, a brief overview
			of the project is stored in <computeroutput>[project_name]_Overview_Brief_Frag.xml</computeroutput> 
			and embedded wherever such a description is needed. Thus, any update to the Overview fragment is updated in each
			place it has been embedded and remains standard throughout the documentation. 
			As you can guess from this example, such frags have the following naming convention: 
			<computeroutput>[project_name]_[description]_Frag.xml</computeroutput></para>
		<warning><para>Fragments are most useful for small chunks of information that would be embedded within a section. If the content expands to
			include subsections to which you want to link (using ids), DocBook generates errors if it is embedded more than once, as that creates duplicate ids. 
		In such situations, it is better to make the information a <link linkend="new-docs">standalone page</link>.</para>
			</warning>
	</section>
	
	<section><title>Standard organization</title>
		
		<para>Our templates provide a standard organization for all system administrator, user and developer guides for all projects of the 
			Globus Toolkit. If a section does not apply for a project, there will be a statement to the effect: "This section does not apply 
			for this project." For example, if a project does not have a GUI interface, then the 
			<filename>[project]_Interface_GUI_Frag.xml</filename> file should explicitly
			say so. The benefit is that the reader will know the project does not have a GUI interface instead of looking for GUI information
			and wondering if it was simply left out.</para>
		
		<para>From time to time, there will be information that is not compatible with the standard organization.
			In these cases, you have the option of creating 
			standalone pages covering the topic. These standalone pages are represented in the table of contents as an 
			appendix item (see <xref linkend="new-docs"/>.</para>
	</section>
		
	<section><title>Release cycle for documentation</title>
		
		<para>The following list outlines what happens with documentation in a typical GT release cycle:</para>
		
		<orderedlist>
			<listitem><para>Once development begins for the next major release (we'll use 4.2 as an example release), 
				a new folder is added to the development docs directory: 
				<filename>toolkit/docs/development/4.2-drafts/</filename>.</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>Documentation Coordinator updates files for the upcoming release (changes version numbers, etc.)</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>Developers start updating documents in this development directory for the upcoming release.</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>For each development release leading up to the stable release:</para>
				<orderedlist>
					<listitem><para>After source code freeze, a corresponding directory is added to the development docs directory - for example, 
						<filename>../toolkit/docs/development/4.1.5</filename>.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para>The drafts directory is frozen and copied over to the new directory. </para></listitem>
					<listitem><para>Documentation Coordinator updates references to release numbers.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para>Documentation Coordinator and Technical Product Manager go over development documentation for 
						any other necessary revisions.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para>Release notes are completed and the development release is announced.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para>Freeze is lifted for drafts directory.</para></listitem>
				</orderedlist>
			</listitem>
			<listitem><para>Before final stable release:</para>
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem><para>A new directory is added to the docs directory - for example, <filename>.../toolkit/docs/4.2/</filename>.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para>After source code freeze, the drafts directory is frozen and copied over to the new directory.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para>Documentation Coordinator updates references to release numbers.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para>Documentation Coordinator and Technical Product Manager go over development documentation for 
						any other necessary revisions.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para>Release notes are completed and the final release is announced.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para>After final stable release, the drafts directory is removed.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para>The final stable release documentation is used for all subsequent incremental releases as well.</para></listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
			</listitem>
		</orderedlist>
		<!-- update with following:
		
		New directory
		BEN: copy to new 4.1.0 directory
		ME: update custom_html.xls, entities, catalog, Makefile with new dir
		
		Let dev people know to search through to make sure all things that reference version numbers use the entity reference (&version; or &shortversion;)
		
		calls for testing pages: 
		LISA: provide date range, 
		ME: add date range to individual pages and add list to testing/calls/
		
		Development release notes:
		ME: finish hooking up releasenotes/development/4.1.0/
		LISA: write intro paragraphs
		go to: alliance/toolkit/releasenotes/development/4.1.0/
		edit this section in the file index.xml:
		<section id="rn-intro"><title>Introduction</title>
		
		<para>The GT development team is pleased to 
		make its newest development release available 
		for download. This release, with a version 
		number of &version;, is the Alpha release for 
		GT 4.2. Highlights of this release include:</para>
		
		<itemizedlist>
		<listitem>[FIXME: list highlights]</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		
		<para>We invite you to experiment with our latest work, 
		as we believe it represents a significant step toward 
		our goal of delivering a toolkit release of the highest
		quality.</para>
		
		</section>
		
		At the point final release candidate is approved: 
		
		Access to online docs:
		someone needs to add links to these pages:
		alliance/toolkit/docs/development/index.html
		alliance/toolkit/releasenotes/index.html
		
		API docs
		Mike Link can generate the doxygen docs for C code
		Laura can generate javadocs for java code
		and then someone needs to update links at:
		alliance/toolkit/api/index.html
		
		TODOS for 4.1.[whatever the next one]
		* "freeze is over" email, we need to say "Tag CVS with globus_4_1_0 before making a commit to HEAD"
		* put config frags in admin guide only and link to it from public interface guides
		* choose between top-level commandlines index and individual project 
		* figure out xsl to show different levels of tocs for different elements (book, part, chapter, etc)
		* look into making api docs automated
		* gtmanuals-dev - guidelines per jen (more of a decision-making guide than the primer) - in wiki, add 'how to contribute to docs' page
		* change term from 'project' to 'project'?
		* on commit - run xmllint first and if errors, kick it back out of CVS and don't run make? otherwise, need to set up individual testing alternatives for individuals
		*make infrastructure changes to allow us to just branch per release
		
		-->
	</section>
	</chapter>
	

	<chapter id="requirements" xreflabel="Requirements for Release Manuals"><title>Requirements for Release Manuals</title>	
		
	<section id="general-reqs" xreflabel="Globus Toolkit General Documentation Requirements"><title>Globus Toolkit General Documentation Requirements</title>
		
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem><para>Clarity in presentation.</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>Use best practices learned from the print world, web, and other media, about use of grammar, space, writing style, etc:</para>
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem><para>Consistency. It's important to be consistent in the use of terms and names for your project. For example, make sure 
						that when you name a project, you consistently use the same name throughout documentation to avoid confusion.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para>Use standardized language. Consider international readers by not using slang or colloquial terms - many
						of your readers use English as a second language. This also helps make translation easier for anyone interested in translating 
						the documentation for internationalization efforts.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para>All jargon used in documentation needs to be defined (using the <link linkend="glossary">glossary feature</link>). 
						Use standardized terms when available, avoiding implicit understanding of specific Globus Toolkit terms.</para></listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
			</listitem>
			<listitem><para>Single source - This practice significantly reduces obsolescence in writing and the burden of maintaining 
				up-to-date documentation:
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem><para>Show where to find information instead of duplicating information - use a <link linkend="links">cross-reference</link>
						or create fragments using <link linkend="system-entities">system entities</link> - as long as there are no subsections with ids, you can 
						embed them anywhere in the set of release manuals. </para></listitem>
					<listitem><para>If the information is not found elsewhere, then create one place for it where others can refer to it (contact the 
						Documentation Coordinator if you have any doubts about how to do so).</para> </listitem>
				</itemizedlist></para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem><para>Consider Globus Toolkit documentation as a set of books (an encyclopedic set organized like an atlas) that 
				contains volumes (books). Each book contains parts, chapters and sections, 
				where each chapter is a web page. This designation helps create Globus Toolkit books in PDF, and helps new 
				readers visualize how the documentation is organized.</para></listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		
	</section>
		
	<section id="key-concepts" xreflabel="Requirements for Key Concepts"><title>Key Concepts</title>
		
		<para>Key Concepts guides are at the 'family' level (common/, data/, execution/, info/, and security/) and explain important concepts about the technologies within
			that family.</para>
		<para>There is a very basic outline for key concepts but they should be customized for the specific technology they're describing.</para>
		<para>We encourage the use of graphics to demonstrate your key concepts!</para>
		<para>As necessary, we also encourage adding standalone files if you have a large amount of information you want to break down into separate files.</para>
		<para>TODO: add guidelines for writing key concepts: heavy use of graphics, should describe each component in the family (for example, 
			security does a great job of describing cryptology and such, but does not mention how the underlying components are related).</para>
		
		<para>The Key Concepts Guide has the following required topics:</para>
		
		<orderedlist>
			<listitem><para><emphasis role="strong">Overview</emphasis>: Provides high-level overview of the features of the component, as well as a description of 
				the problem space of relevance to the component. The discussion should be aimed at readers who are non-experts.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem><para><emphasis role="strong">Conceptual Details</emphasis>: The bulk of this guide, includes several paragraphs outlining the fundamental concepts 
				that underly the component.</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para><emphasis role="strong">Related Documents</emphasis>: Link to other documents (internal or external, whitepapers, presentations, etc.) that 
				supplement the Overview.</para></listitem>
		</orderedlist>

	</section>
		
	<section id="user-guides" xreflabel="Requirements for User Guides"><title>User's Guides</title>
		
		<para>This guide is for the most challenging audience for our documentation: end users. Please 
			always keep in mind that end users may have little technical background/knowledge for your project.</para>

	<para>The User's Guide has the following required topics:</para>
		
		<orderedlist>
			<listitem><para><emphasis role="strong">Introduction</emphasis>: Introduces the project to end users and references to the (upcoming) Toolkit-level User's Guide 
				where they can find general end user-oriented information (proposing a top-level User's Guide much like his quickstart guide).</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem><para><emphasis role="strong">Command-line tools</emphasis>: Links to the standalone 
				<link linkend="command-ref">commandline reference</link> page.</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para><emphasis role="strong">Graphical user interface</emphasis>: Describes how the UI works including  browser/interface strengths and 
				limitations.</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para><emphasis role="strong">Troubleshooting</emphasis>: Describes user-friendly help on common problems they may encounter.</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>PROPOSED: user how-to's (add "if you want to..." topics)</para></listitem>
		</orderedlist>
	</section>
		
	<section id="admin-guides" xreflabel="Requirements for System Administrators Guides"><title>System Administrators Guides</title>
		
		<para>The System Administrators Guide at the project-level picks up where the top-level Installation Guide leaves off and has the following required topics:</para>

		<orderedlist>
			<listitem><para><emphasis role="strong">Introduction</emphasis>: Introduces the guide to sysadmins and points them to the top-level Installation Guide 
				for comprehensive basic installation/configuration info.</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para><emphasis role="strong">Building and installing</emphasis>: Includes information about building and installing your project that is not 
				covered in the top-level Installation Guide.</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para><emphasis role="strong">Configuring</emphasis>: Embeds the 
				<link linkend="frag-config"><filename>[project]_Interface_Configuring_Frag.xml</filename></link> fragment for full information on 
				configuration settings [cris: should we also embed environmental variables frag?].</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para><emphasis role="strong">Deploying</emphasis>: Includes deploying information (into various containers/environments) for your project that is not 
				covered in the top-level Installation Guide.</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para><emphasis role="strong">Testing</emphasis>: Includes procedures for how to test the configuration that is not 
				covered in the top-level Installation Guide. Must include examples of the tests.</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para><emphasis role="strong">Security Considerations</emphasis>: Embeds the <link linkend="frag-security">
				<filename>Security Considerations frag</filename></link>.</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para><emphasis role="strong">Troubleshooting</emphasis>: Describes help for common problems sysadmins may experience.</para></listitem>
		</orderedlist>
	</section>
		
		
	<section id="dev-guides" xreflabel="Requirements for Developers Guides"><title>Developer's Guides</title>
		
		<para>Keep in mind the following when you edit Developer's Guides:</para>
		
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem><para> This documentation should be written for ongoing reference by developers.</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>List practical development and diagnostics tools and methodologies.</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>List/link to Globus Toolkit development resources, API docs, schema files, etc.. Remember you can
				use ViewCVS to link to the latest versions of schema, WSDL, and other files.</para></listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		
		<para>The Developer's Guide has the following required topics:</para>
		
		<orderedlist>
			<listitem><para><emphasis role="strong">Introduction</emphasis>: Introduces the project to developers (people who use the programmatic public interfaces of GT).</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para><emphasis role="strong">Before you begin</emphasis>: Collects information useful to developers before they start working with the 
				technology. Embeds the following fragments: <link linkend="frag-features">Features Summary</link>, 
				<link linkend="frag-platform">Tested Platforms</link>, <link linkend="frag-compatibility">Backward Compatibility</link>,
				<link linkend="frag-dependencies">Tech Dependencies</link> and <link linkend="frag-security">Security Consideration</link>.</para></listitem>
			
			<listitem><para><emphasis role="strong">Architecture and design overview</emphasis>:  Describes the architecture and design at a high-level with 
				links to architecture and design docs. Diagrams are strongly encouraged. </para></listitem>
			
			<listitem><para><emphasis role="strong">Public interfaces</emphasis>: Describes the semantics and syntax of the APIs and WSDL for the component, 
				along with descriptions of domain-specific structured interface data, by embedding the following fragments: <link linkend="frag-api">API</link>, 
				<link linkend="frag-commandline">Commandline</link> (linked, not embedded), <link linkend="frag-config">Config</link> (linked, not embedded), 
			<link linkend="frag-domain">Domain</link>, <link linkend="frag-envvar">Environment Variables</link>, <link linkend="frag-gui">GUI</link>, 
				<link linkend="frag-protocol">Protocol</link> and <link linkend="frag-wsdl">WSDL</link>.</para></listitem>
			
			<listitem><para><emphasis role="strong">Usage scenarios</emphasis>: Describes how to use the programmatic interfaces of the project and provides examples.</para></listitem>
			
			<listitem><para><emphasis role="strong">Tutorials</emphasis>: Links to any developer tutorials. Tutorials do not conform to a template, but they are strongly 
				encouraged. The files can be in any format as long as they are available online. You can add the files to your project's doc CVS repository or 
				on your own web space. Keep in mind the following when writing them:</para>
					
					<itemizedlist>
						<listitem><para>Use cross references to Developers Guide instead of duplicating information.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para>List suggestions for installing and setting up a development environment; these can be annotated links to the 
							top-level Installation Guide.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para>Provide working examples.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para>Include general rules to follow for stability, scalability.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para>Include a summary of important links used by developers.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para>Note any deprecated tools and methods by linking to prior versions instead of describing them in current docs.</para></listitem> 
						<listitem><para>If there are no tutorials, write "There are no tutorials available at this time."</para></listitem>
					</itemizedlist>
			</listitem>
			<listitem><para><emphasis role="strong">Debugging</emphasis>: Provides information for debugging the project.</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para><emphasis role="strong">Troubleshooting</emphasis>:  Describes help for common problems developers may experience.</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para><emphasis role="strong">Related Documentation</emphasis>: Links to PDFs and whitepapers about protocols, etc., about the project.</para></listitem>
		</orderedlist>
	</section>
		
	<section id="command-ref" xreflabel="Requirements for Commandline References"><title>Commandline References</title>
		<para>We use the DocBook element <filename>&lt;refentry&gt;</filename> to document our commandline tools; this code is found in the 
			<link linkend="frag-commandline">Commandline Frag</link>. 
			For more information, read the DocBook documentation <ulink url="http://docbook.org/tdg/en/html/refentry.html">here</ulink>. </para>
	</section>
		
	<section id="pub-interface-guides" xreflabel="Requirements for Public Interface Guides"><title>Public Interfaces Guides</title>
		<para>Identifies the public interfaces for the project and includes the following topics: </para>
			
		<orderedlist>
			<listitem><para><emphasis role="strong">Semantics and syntax of APIs</emphasis> (embeds the <link linkend="frag-api">API</link> frag)</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para><emphasis role="strong">Semantics and syntax of the WSDL</emphasis> (embeds the 
				<link linkend="frag-wsdl">WSDL</link> frag)</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para><emphasis role="strong">Semantics and syntax of non-WSDL protocols</emphasis> (embeds the 
				<link linkend="frag-protocol">Protocol</link> frag)</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para><emphasis role="strong">Command-line tools</emphasis> (links to the 
				<link linkend="frag-commandline">Commandline</link> frag)</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para><emphasis role="strong">Overview of Graphical User Interface</emphasis> (embeds the 
				<link linkend="frag-gui">GUI</link> frag)</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para><emphasis role="strong">Semantics and syntax of domain-specific interface</emphasis> (embeds the 
				<link linkend="frag-domain">Domain</link> frag)</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para><emphasis role="strong">Configuration interface</emphasis> (links to the <link linkend="frag-config">Config</link> frag)</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para><emphasis role="strong">Environment variable interface</emphasis> (embeds the 
				<link linkend="frag-envvar">Environment Variables</link> frag)</para></listitem>
		</orderedlist>
	</section>
		
	<section id="release-notes" xreflabel="Requirements for Release Notes"><title>Release Notes</title>
		<para>Describes implementation details to existing and potential users of a project distributed as part of a new stable release.</para>
			<para>Release notes include the following topics:</para>
			
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem><para><emphasis role="strong">Component Overview</emphasis> (embeds the 
					<link linkend="frag-overview">Overview</link> frag)</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><emphasis role="strong">Feature Summary</emphasis> (embeds the 
					<link linkend="frag-features">Features</link> frag)</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><emphasis role="strong">Changes Summary</emphasis> (embeds the 
					<link linkend="frag-change">Change Summary</link> frag)</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><emphasis role="strong">Bug Fixes</emphasis> (links to the 
					<link linkend="frag-fixed-bugs">Fixed Bugs</link> frag)</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><emphasis role="strong">Known Problems</emphasis> (embeds the 
					<link linkend="frag-known-problems">Known Problems</link> frag)</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><emphasis role="strong">Technology Dependencies</emphasis> (embeds the 
					<link linkend="frag-dependencies">Dependencies</link> frag)</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><emphasis role="strong">Tested Platforms</emphasis> (links to the 
					<link linkend="frag-platform">Platform Summary</link> frag)</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><emphasis role="strong">Backward Compatibility Summary</emphasis> (embeds the 
					<link linkend="frag-compatibility">Compatibility</link> frag)</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><emphasis role="strong">Associated Standards</emphasis> (embeds the 
					<link linkend="frag-standards">Standards</link> frag)</para></listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		
	</section>
		
	<section id="quality-profiles" xreflabel="Requirements for Quality Profiles"><title>Quality Profiles</title>
		 
		<para>Presents any current reports available on test coverage, resource and memory leak analysis, bounds checking, and performance profiles.</para>
		<para>Quality Profiles include the following required topics.</para>
		<orderedlist>
			<listitem><para><emphasis role="strong">Test coverage reports</emphasis></para></listitem>
			<listitem><para><emphasis role="strong">Code analysis reports</emphasis></para></listitem>
			<listitem><para><emphasis role="strong">Outstanding bugs</emphasis> (embeds the 
				<link linkend="frag-known-bugs">Known Bugs</link> frag)</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para><emphasis role="strong">Bug Fixes</emphasis> (embeds the 
				<link linkend="frag-fixed-bugs">Fixed Bugs</link> frag)</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para><emphasis role="strong">Performance reports</emphasis></para></listitem>
		</orderedlist>
	</section>
		
	<section id="fact-sheets" xreflabel="Requirements for Fact Sheets"><title>Fact Sheets</title>
		
		<para>TODO - moved to 4.2-drafts/marketing/ dir. How will we use these now?</para>
		
	</section>
		
	<section id="migrating-guides" xreflabel="Requirements for Migrating Guides"><title>Migrating Guides</title>
		
		<para>TODO - do we need to update the versions we're covering?</para>
		
		<orderedlist>
			<listitem><para><emphasis role="strong">Migrating from GT2</emphasis>  (embeds the 
				<link linkend="frag-migrate-gt2">Migrating GT2</link> frag)</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para><emphasis role="strong">Migrating from GT3</emphasis>  (embeds the 
				<link linkend="frag-migrate-gt3">Migrating GT3</link> frag)</para></listitem>
		</orderedlist>
		
	</section>
		
	<section id="samples" xreflabel="Requirements for Samples"><title>Samples</title>
		
		<para>Samples do not conform to a template; however, they are strongly encouraged. Samples provide test code for a project, which makes it far 
			easier to start developing with a project. Include your code in the [project]_Samples.xml file and notify the Doc Coordinator (who will include it 
			in the <ulink url="&docpath;toolkit-samples.html">top-level Samples guide</ulink>).</para>
		
	</section>
		</chapter>
		
	<chapter id="why" xreflabel="Why Docbook"><title>Why DocBook?</title>
		
		<para>All Globus Toolkit documentation will be marked up to conform to the DocBook XML DTD. Theoretically, any strict DTD would have been sufficient. 
			However, DocBook is a publishing standard based on XML with similar goals to the Globus Toolkit Documentation project. 
			Some specific reasons why we are using DocBook:</para>
		
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem><para> It is open-source.</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>A growing community surrounds DocBook (has mailing lists).</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>A number of free and commercial <link linkend="tools">tools</link> are available for editing and publishing DocBook 
				documents.</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>It enables us to publish in a variety of formats (HTML, PDF, etc.)</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>XML separates content from presentation: It relieves each contributor of the burden of presentation, freeing each writer to focus on content and 
				sharing knowledge.</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>It is well tested technology. (It has been in development since the early 1990's). </para></listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		
		<para>The following DocBook primer walks you through the basics, and should cover the needs for 95 percent of the documentation we produce. 
			Remember to:</para>
		
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem><para>Always close your tags with corresponding end-tags and to not use other tag minimization.</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>Write all elements and attributes in lowercase.</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>Quote all attributes.</para></listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		
	</chapter>
	
	<chapter id="setting-up" xreflabel="Setting Up DocBook"><title>Setting Up DocBook</title>
		
		<para>There are many ways to work with the DocBook documentation. At its simplest, you need 
			<ulink url="http://dev.globus.org/wiki/How_to_edit_docs">CVS access</ulink>, then if you know how the code 
		works, you can edit the XML files in a text editor. However, many people are more comfortable setting up a separate test environment, you'll
		need some things to duplicate the processing that occurs to the files when producing the HTML/PDF output.</para>
		
		<para>The following can help you with the Globus Toolkit Docbook XML documentation:</para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem><para><ulink url="http://docbook.org/xml/4.4/">Docbook XML DTD version 4.4</ulink> - The document type definition for XML. 
				You can find an RPM or DEB package or you can download a zip file from the site linked from here.</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para><ulink url="http://sourceforge.net/project/showfiles.php?group_id=21935&amp;package_id=16608&amp;release_id=348591">XSL Stylesheets 
				version 1.69.1</ulink> (docbook-xsl) - The stylesheets to convert to HTML. We have been using a stylesheet based upon NWalsh's <filename>&quot;chunk.xsl&quot;</filename>.</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>xsltproc - The processor that will take an XML document and, given a xsl stylesheet, convert it to HTML. It needs libxml2 and libxslt (available 
				in RPM and DEB formats or from <ulink url="http://xmlsoft.org/">xmlsoft.org</ulink>). It comes with xmllint, which will be very useful for 
				debugging.</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para id="tools" xreflabel="DocBook Tools">Some editing tool. Some options are
				<ulink url="http://www.oxygenxml.com/">Oxygen XML Editor</ulink>, 
				<ulink url="http://www.syntext.com/products/serna/index.htm">Syntext Serna (WYSIWYG)</ulink>, 
				and Emacs with the psgml mode. You can compare these and other editing tools 
				<ulink url="http://wiki.docbook.org/topic/DocBookAuthoringTools">here</ulink>.</para></listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		
		<para>For more information about how to set up a test environment, see <ulink url="http://dev.globus.org/wiki/How_to_edit_docs">the dev.globus wiki</ulink>.</para>
	</chapter>
	
	<chapter id="cvs" xreflabel="Accessing Documentation via CVS"><title>Accessing Documentation via CVS</title>
		
		<para>Please read the dev.globus Wiki page: <ulink url="http://dev.globus.org/wiki/How_to_edit_docs">How to edit docs</ulink> for the most 
			up to date information.</para>

	</chapter>
	
	<chapter id="new-project" xreflabel="If You're A New project..."><title>If You're A New Project...</title>
		
		<para>If you're a new project to the Globus Toolkit distribution, then you will need to contact the <ulink url="mailto:cristina@isi.edu">Documentation Coordinator</ulink>.
			You'll receive the templates in DocBook XML for all the documents needed for your project.</para>
		
		<para>FYI, if you are a technical preview or contributor, most likely we will only request a small set of docs. If you are an official project of
			the Globus Toolkit, then you will be required to fill out a full set of doc templates.</para>
		
		<para>TODO - check with jen to see how this should fit into the incubator/protoproject process</para>
		
	</chapter>
	
	<chapter id="convert-from-html" xreflabel="Converting existing HTML docs to DocBook"><title>Converting existing HTML docs to DocBook</title>
		
		<para>Discuss how to use the sed file. [TODO - need Charles' help]</para>
		
	</chapter>
	
	<chapter id="new-docs" xreflabel="Creating New Docs/Appendix"><title>Creating New Docs/Appendix</title>
		
		<para>For the most part, you only need to edit existing DocBook files. However, the following information is helpful if you need to create a 
			new standalone doc.</para>
		
		<note>
			<simpara>We only encourage standalone docs to supplement information that is already in the templates for standard documentation or for
			information that does not fit within the template's structure. If you're not sure, contact the <ulink url="mailto:cristina@isi.edu">Documentation Coordinator</ulink>.
			</simpara>
		</note>
		
		<section id="new-docs-writing" xreflabel="Writing New Docs/Appendix"><title>Writing New Docs/Appendix</title>
			<para>First, you need to define a title for your document. Try to use
			a title that is as informative as possible using the fewest amount of words possible. Also, try to compose a title with certain 'keywords' that will
			catch the attention of readers who are looking for this information.</para>
			
		<para>Then start thinking about the possible sections and subsections you will have in your document. Make sure you coordinate with the 
			<ulink url="mailto:cristina@isi.edu">Documentation Coordinator</ulink> to make sure you're not writing something that someone else has already written.</para>
		</section>
		
		<section id="new-docs-adding" xreflabel="Adding New Docs/Appendix to Your Release Manuals"><title>Adding New Docs/Appendix to Your Release Manuals</title>
		<para>Make sure your XML is properly named - you should use the project name that prepends other files in your directory (for example Java_WS_Core) and then 
			one or two words describing the contents. Note that as an appendix, your DocBook code will start with the <filename>&lt;appendix&gt;</filename> element. When hooking up with 
			your documentation, however, the <filename>&lt;appendix&gt;</filename> element (with id and xreflabel and even title) will be in the [project]/index.xml file.</para>
			
		<orderedlist>
			<listitem><para>Make sure new file is added to CVS in your project's directory.</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>Add a <link linkend="system-entities">system entity</link> reference to the entities file. To do this, download the following from CVS 
				([path to doc version]/entities) and look for your project's list of entities. Then add yours in alpha order. For example, if GridFTP was adding an 
				appendix on named GridFTP_Special_Topic.xml, this would be the new line to add:
			<screen>&lt;!ENTITY GridFTP_Special_Topic SYSTEM "data/gridftp/GridFTP_Special_Topic.xml"&gt;</screen>
			Commit change to CVS.</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>Add entity reference to your project's index.xml file (using the example in the previous step, that would be 
				<filename>&amp;GridFTP_Special_Topic;</filename>. 
			You should follow how other chapters and appendixes are added in your index.xml file - but here's an example of what GridFTP would add (make sure 
			it is added:

<screen>&lt;appendix id="gridftp-special-topic" xreflabel="GridFTP Special Topic"&gt;&lt;title&gt;GridFTP Special Topic&lt;/title&gt;
	&amp;GridFTP_Special_Topic;
&lt;/section&gt;</screen>			
			And commit this change to CVS.</para></listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		<para>Look at the existing files in your project (or checkout another project and look at their code) to see how the code is used in practice.</para>
		</section>
	</chapter>
	
	<chapter id="structure" xreflabel="Structure of a DocBook Set"><title>Structure of a DocBook Set</title>
		
		<para>For each version, release manuals are essentially one long XML file with the root node <filename>&lt;set&gt;</filename>. Below that we use a two-tiered basic directory where a 
			family of projects (for example data/) starts with the <filename>&lt;book&gt;</filename> element and below that each project starts with the <filename>&lt;part&gt;</filename> element. (and there may 
			be further subdirectories as necessary for the project).</para>
		
		<para>Focusing on the project-level, which is the only level most writers will need to worry about, each <filename>&lt;part&gt;</filename> is structured as follows (we'll use GridFTP as 
			an example, which can be found in <filename>.../toolkit/docs/4.0/data/gridftp/</filename>):</para>
		
		<screen>set (the top element - includes all code for all docs within a version)
|
+--book (this element includes doc code for a family of projects, such as common/ or data/)
	|
	+--part (includes doc code for one project, such as common/javawscore/)
		|
		+--chapter (each chapter element is output as one HTML page)
			|
			---------+------------------------------------------------------
			|
			+--section (sections divide content underneath a chapter)
			|
			+--section
			|
				+--section (a nested section element becomes a subsection)
				|
		+--refentry (for commandline documentation)
			
		+--appendix
			|
			+--section
			|
			+--section
		</screen>
		
		<note><simpara>Note that we use <filename>&lt;section&gt;</filename> tags recursively - simply nest section tags to make subsections.</simpara></note>
		
		<para>The following is some DocBook code representing how the above info 'nests':</para>
		
		<screen>&lt;part&gt; &lt;title&gt;GridFTP Release Manuals&lt;/title&gt;
	&lt;chapter&gt;&lt;title&gt;GridFTP Developer's Guide&lt;/title&gt;
	
		&lt;section&gt;&lt;title&gt;Introduction&lt;/title&gt;
		&lt;para&gt;[content]&lt;/para&gt;
		&lt;/section&gt;
	
		&lt;section&gt;&lt;title&gt;Architecture and design&lt;/title&gt;
			&lt;section&gt;&lt;title&gt;Design Overview&lt;/title&gt;
			&lt;para&gt;[content]&lt;/para&gt;
			&lt;/section&gt;	
		&lt;/section&gt;			
	
	&lt;/chapter&gt;
&lt;/part&gt;</screen>
		
		<para>In the implementation, the code is broken up into several modular XML files (see the next chapter, <xref linkend="guide-to-files"/>). Each chapter is output as 
			a single web page (this also applies to <filename>&lt;reference&gt;</filename>, <filename>&lt;appendix&gt;</filename>, and 
			<filename>&lt;article&gt;</filename> elements). Many of these pages embed fragments (which are separate XML files (as described in <xref linkend="fragments"/>).
		</para>
		
		<para>Take a look at the files of existing DocBook documents, or see <link linkend="guide-to-files">the following chapter</link> to get an idea of how they are tied 
			together.</para>
	</chapter>
	
	<chapter id="guide-to-files" xreflabel="Guide to XML files"><title>Guide to XML files</title>
		<para>The following is the default list of DocBook XML files required for each project. This may not be a complete list for each project as there may be 
			further standalone documentation necessary for that technology.</para>
		<section id="guide-to-files-frags" xreflabel="Fragments List"><title>Fragments List</title>
			<para>The list of fragments is provided in alphabetical order with a description of the contents as well as a list of the docs it is embedded in by default.</para>
			
			<!-- turning this list into a table for easier reference -->
			
			<informaltable frame="all">
				<tgroup cols="3">
					<thead>
						<row>
							<entry>File name</entry>
							<entry>Description</entry>
							<entry>Appears in...</entry>
						</row>
					</thead>
					<tbody>
						<row id="frag-standards">
							<entry><filename>[projectName]_Associated_Standards_Frag.xml</filename></entry>
							<entry>Lists any standards associated with this technology.</entry>
							<entry>Release Notes</entry>
						</row>
						<row id="frag-change">
							<entry><filename>[projectName]_Change_Summary_Frag.xml</filename></entry>
							<entry>(add release notes number for clarity?) High level description of changes made to technology since previous release.</entry>
							<entry>Release Notes</entry>
						</row>
						<row id="frag-compatibility">
							<entry><filename>[projectName]_Compatibility_Summary_Frag.xml</filename></entry>
							<entry>Lists protocol changes, API, exception and schema changes since previous version.</entry>
							<entry>Developer's Guide and Release Notes</entry>
						</row>
						<row id="frag-dependencies">
							<entry><filename>[projectName]_Dependencies_Summary_Frag.xml</filename></entry>
							<entry>Lists any other GT projects and third-party software on which this project depends.</entry>
							<entry>Developer's Guide and Release Notes</entry>
						</row>
						
						<row id="frag-features">
							<entry><filename>[projectName]_Feature_Summary_Frag.xml</filename></entry>
							<entry>Lists new features, supported features and deprecated features since previous version.</entry>
							<entry>Developer's Guide and Release Notes</entry>
						</row>
						<row id="frag-fixed-bugs">
							<entry><filename>[projectName]_Fixed_Bugs_Frag.xml</filename></entry>
							<entry>(add release notes number for clarity?) Lists bugs fixed since previous release.</entry>
							<entry>Quality Profile and Release Notes</entry>
						</row>
						<row id="frag-api">
							<entry><filename>[projectName]_Interface_API_Frag.xml</filename></entry>
							<entry>Describes API programming and provides links to API documentation.</entry>
							<entry>Developer's Guide and Public Interfaces Guide</entry>
						</row>
						<row id="frag-commandline">
							<entry><filename>[projectName]_Interface_Commandline_Frag.xml</filename></entry>
							<entry>Documents commandline tools for the technology using a specific <link linkend="command-ref">refentry</link> format.</entry>
							<entry>Standalone page linked to from the Developer's Guide, Public Interfaces Guide, and User's Guide.</entry>
						</row>
						<row id="frag-config">
							<entry><filename>[projectName]_Interface_Config_Frag.xml</filename></entry>
							<entry>Describes and provides details about configuring this technology. </entry>
							<entry>Admin Guide, Developer's Guide and Public Interfaces Guide. (Proposal: only embed in Admin Guide and link to there from 
								other guides)</entry>
						</row>
						<row id="frag-domain">
							<entry><filename>[projectName]_Interface_Domain_Frag.xml</filename></entry>
							<entry>Identifies the domain-specific interface data of the project.</entry>
							<entry>Developer's Guide and Public Interfaces Guide</entry>
						</row>
						<row id="frag-envvar">
							<entry><filename>[projectName]_Interface_Env_Frag.xml</filename></entry>
							<entry> Identifies the interface to environmental variables for this project.</entry>
							<entry>Developer's Guide and Public Interfaces Guide</entry>
						</row>
						<row id="frag-gui">
							<entry><filename>[projectName]_Interface_GUI_Frag.xml</filename></entry>
							<entry>Describes any Graphical User Interface for the technology.</entry>
							<entry>Developer's Guide, Public Interfaces Guide and User's Guide</entry>
						</row>
						<row id="frag-protocol">
							<entry><filename>[projectName]_Interface_Protocol_Frag.xml</filename></entry>
							<entry>Describes any non-WSDL protocols.</entry>
							<entry>Developer's Guide and Public Interfaces Guide</entry>
						</row>
						<row id="frag-wsdl">
							<entry><filename>[projectName]_Interface_WSDL_Frag.xml</filename></entry>
							<entry>Describe any WSDL protocols.</entry>
							<entry>Developer's Guide and Public Interfaces Guide</entry>
						</row>
						<row id="frag-known-bugs">
							<entry><filename>[projectName]_Known_Bugs_Frag.xml</filename></entry>
							<entry>(add release notes number for clarity?) Lists and links to existing bugs at the time of release. </entry>
							<entry>Embedded in the Known Problems Frag and appears in Release Notes and the Quality Profile.</entry>
						</row>
						<row id="frag-known-problems">
							<entry><filename>[projectName]_Known_Problems_Frag.xml</filename></entry>
							<entry>(add release notes number for clarity?) High level descriptions of any limitations (followed by list of Known Bugs).</entry>
							<entry>Release Notes</entry>
						</row>
						<row id="frag-migrate-gt2">
							<entry><filename>[projectName]_Migrating_GT2_Frag.xml</filename></entry>
							<entry>Describes how to migrate the technology from GT2 to current release.</entry>
							<entry>Migrating Guide</entry>
						</row>
						<row id="frag-migrate-gt3">
							<entry><filename>[projectName]_Migrating_GT3_Frag.xml</filename></entry>
							<entry>Describes how to migrate the technology from gt3 to current release.</entry>
							<entry>Migrating Guide</entry>
						</row>
						<row id="frag-overview">
							<entry><filename>[projectName]_Overview_Brief_Frag.xml</filename></entry>
							<entry>Provides a brief overview of the technology (1-2 sentences). </entry>
							<entry>Release Notes and the (optional) Call for Testing page</entry>
						</row>
						<row id="frag-platform">
							<entry><filename>[projectName]_Platform_Summary_Frag.xml</filename></entry>
							<entry>Summarizes the platforms on which this technology has been tested.</entry>
							<entry>Developer's Guide and Release Notes</entry>
						</row>
						<row id="frag-rps">
							<entry><filename>[projectName]_Resource_Properties_Summary_Frag.xml</filename></entry>
							<entry>Lists and describes resource properties for this technology.</entry>
							<entry>Embedded in WSDL Frag and appears in Developer's Guide and Public Interface Guide.</entry>
						</row>
						<row id="frag-security">
							<entry><filename>[projectName]_Security_Considerations_Frag.xml</filename></entry>
							<entry>Describes any security considerations admin/dev should know for this technology. </entry>
							<entry>Admin Guide and Developer's Guide</entry>
						</row>
						<row id="frag-usability">
							<entry><filename>[projectName]_Usability_Summary_Frag.xml</filename></entry>
							<entry>Describes improvements in usability since previous release.</entry>
							<entry>Fact Sheets (in marketing/ directory)</entry>
						</row>
						<row id="frag-usage-stats">
							<entry><filename>[projectName]_Usage_Statistics_Frag.xml</filename></entry>
							<entry>(optional) Only for those projects who can publish usage statistics. Describes what information is 
								published and links to more detailed information, including how to opt-out.</entry>
							<entry>Admin Guide and User's Guide</entry>
						</row>
					</tbody>
				</tgroup>
			</informaltable>
			
		</section>
		
		<section id="guide-to-files-standalone" xreflabel="Standalone Pages List"><title>Standalone Pages List</title>
			<para>This section describes the pages that are made up of Fragments (see previous section) as well as other sections. 
				The following standalone pages are the default list. Others may be added as <link linkend="new-docs">appendices</link> as necessary.</para>
			<informaltable frame="all">
				<tgroup cols="3">
					<thead>
						<row>
							<entry>File name</entry>
							<entry>Description</entry>
							<entry>Edit?</entry>
						</row>
					</thead>
					<tbody>
						<row>
							<entry><filename>index.xml</filename></entry>
							<entry>The home page. This is the first 'page' of documentation for this project and acts as the table of contents - 
								it compiles all the doc code for this technology.</entry>
							<entry>Usually no editing is necessary unless you are adding a <link linkend="new-docs">standalone page</link>.</entry>
						</row>
						<row>
							<entry><filename>[projectName]_Call_for_Testing.xml</filename></entry>
							<entry>(optional) Call for Testing page. Identifies key aspects of a GT development release that warrant wide testing. If you would like a Call for Testing for your page, 
								contact the <ulink url="mailto:cristina@isi.edu">Documentation Coordinator</ulink>.</entry>
							<entry>You will also need to edit this file to include a date range for testing, the cvs tag and any particular items you would like tested.</entry>
						</row>
						<row>
							<entry><filename>[projectName]_Migrating_Guide.xml</filename></entry>
							<entry>Migrating Guide. Includes information about migrating from previous major versions of GT.</entry>
							<entry>No editing needed.</entry>
						</row>
						<row>
							<entry><filename>[projectName]_Public_Interfaces.xml</filename></entry>
							<entry>Public Interfaces Guide. Includes information about all public interfaces for this project. </entry>
							<entry>No editing needed.</entry>
						</row>
						<row>
							<entry><filename>[projectName]_Quality_Profile.xml</filename></entry>
							<entry>Quality Profile. Includes links to various reports and bug information.</entry>
							<entry>You need to update links to test coverage, code analysis and performance reports.</entry>
						</row>
						<row>
							<entry><filename>[projectName]_Release_Notes.xml</filename></entry>
							<entry>Release Notes. Compiles information about the project for this release. </entry>
							<entry>No editing needed.</entry>
						</row>
						<row>
							<entry><filename>admin/index.xml</filename></entry>
							<entry>System Administrator's Guide. Includes information about installing, building and deploying that is outside of the 
								top-level Admin Guide.</entry>
							<entry>You need to update information about building and installing, deploying, testing, and troubleshooting.</entry>
						</row>
						<row>
							<entry><filename>developer/index.xml</filename></entry>
							<entry>Developer's Guide. Includes information useful to developers of this project. </entry>
							<entry>You need to update information about architecture and design, tutorials, usage scenarios, debugging, troubleshooting, 
								and any related documents.</entry>
						</row>
						<row>
							<entry><filename>user/index.xml</filename></entry>
							<entry>User's Guide. Includes information for end users of your project. </entry>
							<entry>You need to update information about troubleshooting, and add anything useful to end users.</entry>
						</row>
					</tbody>
				</tgroup>
			</informaltable>
			
		</section>
		
		
	</chapter>
	
	<chapter id="system-entities" xreflabel="Using System Entities"><title>Using System Entities</title>
		
		<para>System entities is DocBook's way of mapping 'nicknames' to locations of all these separate, modular files.
			In essence, we use a central file for all system entities within a version's documentation: <filename>[path to doc version]/entities</filename>.</para>
		
		<para>For example, the system entity for:</para>
		
		<screen><filename>[path to doc version]/data/gridftp/GridFTP_Overview_Brief_Frag.xml</filename></screen>
		
		<para>is</para> 
		
		<screen><filename>GridFTP_Overview_Brief_Frag</filename></screen>
		
		<para>The following is an example of how this is expressed in the <filename>entities</filename> file:</para>
	
		<screen>&lt;!ENTITY GridFTP_Overview_Brief_Frag SYSTEM "data/gridftp/GridFTP_Overview_Brief_Frag.xml"&gt;</screen>
		
		<para>Anywhere in a version's documentation you want the information in that file to appear, type the following code:</para>
		
		<screen>&amp;GridFTP_Overview_Brief_Frag;</screen>
		
		<para>The <filename>entities</filename> file contains such mappings for every xml file/fragment used in a version's DocBook code.</para>
		
		<section id="text-entities" xreflabel="Text entities"><title>Text entities</title>
			<para>Similar to system entities, text entities map a 'nickname' to a string of text. There are a few in particular that you should use in your 
				documentation:</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem><para><filename>&amp;docpath;</filename> - Maps to the url to this version's doc. Useful if you need to use a 
					<link linkend="links"><computeroutput>&lt;ulink&gt;</computeroutput></link> within a version's doc but 
				do not want to update with each version. For example, for 4.2-drafts/, <computeroutput>&amp;docpath;</computeroutput> equals 
					<filename>&docpath;</filename>.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><filename>&amp;version;</filename> - Maps to the current 3-digit version number (for example, 4.1.0). Useful for referencing the 
					current version in your docs without having to update for each version.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><filename>&amp;shortversion;</filename> - Maps to the current 2-digit version number (for example, 4.2). Useful for referencing 
					the current version in your docs without having to update for each version.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><filename>&amp;previousversion;</filename> - Maps to the previous 2-digit version number (for example, 4.0). Useful for referencing 
					the previous version without having to update for each version.</para></listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			
		</section>
		
	</chapter>
	
	<chapter id="paragraphs" xreflabel="Paragraphs"><title>Paragraphs (&lt;para&gt; and &lt;simpara&gt;)</title>
		
		<para>Not surprisingly, the paragraph tag, <filename>&lt;para&gt;</filename>, is the most used tag in our documentation. Not only can you use it
			to separate your text into separate paragraphs, it may also contain block level structures (lists, figures, and so on).</para> 
		
		<para>But there is another, similar tag that is also used - <filename>&lt;simpara&gt;</filename>. This tag also separates content into separate paragraphs,
		however, it is more restrictive in that it can only contains text characters.</para>
		
		<important>
			<para>You also need <filename>&lt;para&gt;</filename> or <filename>&lt;simpara&gt;</filename> tags around text in the following elements: 
				<link linkend="lists"><filename>&lt;listitem&gt;</filename></link>, <link linkend="important"><filename>&lt;important&gt;</filename></link>
				<link linkend="note"><filename>&lt;note&gt;</filename></link>, <link linkend="tip"><filename>&lt;tip&gt;</filename></link>, and 
				<link linkend="warning"><filename>&lt;warning&gt;</filename></link>.</para>
			
			<para>For example, if you are using an <link linkend="lists">itemizedlist</link>, you need to write the code as follows:</para>
			<screen>&lt;itemizedlist&gt;
	&lt;listitem&gt;&lt;para&gt;your text here&lt;/para&gt;&lt;/listitem&gt;
&lt;itemizedlist&gt;</screen>
		</important>
		
		<section id="brackets" xreflabel="Brackets"><title>Brackets</title>
			
			<para>Brackets (<filename>&lt;</filename> and <filename>&gt;</filename>) used within the flow of text (ie, within <filename>&lt;para&gt;</filename> or 
				<filename>&lt;simpara&gt;</filename> elements) must be represented in code as follows: 
				the opening bracket is represented as <computeroutput>&amp;lt;</computeroutput> (short for &quot;less than&quot;) 
				and the closing bracket is represented as <computeroutput>&amp;gt;</computeroutput> (short for &quot;greater than&quot;.</para>
			
		</section>
		
	</chapter>

	
	<chapter  id="heading" xreflabel="Headings and Sections"><title>Headings and Sections</title>
		
		<para>Headings are determined by DocBook elements as follows:</para>
		
		
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem><para>Heading 1 -  <filename>&lt;set&gt;</filename>, <filename>&lt;book&gt;</filename>, <filename>&lt;part&gt;</filename></para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>Heading 2 - <filename>&lt;chapter&gt;</filename>, <filename>&lt;appendix&gt;</filename>, <filename>&lt;article&gt;</filename>, 
				<filename>&lt;refentry&gt;</filename></para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>Heading 3+ - <filename>&lt;section&gt;</filename> (Sections nest recursively to make subsections - each section will correspond to a 
				heading level in the HTML/PDF output.)</para></listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		
		<para>Each of the abovementioned elements must also have two attributes (<computeroutput>id</computeroutput> and 
		<computeroutput>xreflabel</computeroutput>) and be followed by a <computeroutput>&lt;title&gt;</computeroutput> tag.</para>
		
		<section id="id" xreflabel="id attribute"><title>id attribute</title>
			<para>The first attribute, <computeroutput>id</computeroutput>, is standard and can be used with 
				all elements. It comes in very handy when cross-referencing between documents (more about this when talking about <xref linkend="links"/>).
				The value of <computeroutput>id</computeroutput> must be unique throughout a version's documentation (throughout the 
				<filename>&lt;set&gt;</filename>).</para>
			
			<para>When it comes to creating unique ids for your <filename>&lt;section&gt;</filename>s, please use the following naming convention:</para>
			
			<screen>[name of your project folder]-[short name for doc]-[short term related to this section]</screen>
			
			<para>For example, this would be a unique id for the "Introduction" section of the GridFTP System Administrator's Guide: 
				<filename>gridftp-admin-intro</filename></para>

		</section>
			
		<section id="xreflabel" xreflabel="xreflabel attribute"><title>xreflabel attribute</title>
			
			<para>The other attribute is <computeroutput>xreflabel</computeroutput>. The value of this attribute becomes the link title of any cross-
				references to the section.</para>
			
			<para>For example, the <computeroutput>xreflabel</computeroutput> for this section is "xreflabel attribute" and a cross-reference to this section 
				will look like this: <xref linkend="xreflabel"/>.</para>
		
		</section>
			
		<section id="title" xreflabel="title tag"><title>&lt;title&gt; tag</title>
			
			<para>The opening <filename>&lt;section&gt;</filename> tag is followed by the <filename>&lt;title&gt;</filename> tag. 
				The value of the <filename>&lt;title&gt;</filename> tag is usually the same as the xreflabel attribute and
				becomes the text of the heading for the section in the HTML/PDF output. </para>
				
			<para>For example, the value of the <filename>&lt;title&gt;</filename> tag for this section is "Headings and Sections", which is the heading above. 
				The level of the heading (h1, h2, etc) depends on how deeply the section is nested.
			</para>
			
		</section>
		
		<section><title>Example</title>
			
			<para>For example, the topic you are reading right now looks like this in the DocBook XML file:</para>
			
			<screen>&lt;section id="heading" xreflabel="Headings and Sections"&gt;
	&lt;title&gt;Headings and Sections&lt;/title&gt;
	
	...
	
&lt;/section&gt;</screen>
			
		<para>Inside this section, you can further nest <filename>&lt;section&gt;</filename> tags, each with the same requirements: 
			<computeroutput>id</computeroutput> and <computeroutput>xreflabel</computeroutput> attributes, and a <filename>&lt;title&gt;</filename> tag.</para>
		
		</section>
		
	</chapter>
	
	<chapter id="code" xreflabel="Documenting Code"><title>Documenting Code (&lt;computeroutput&gt; and &lt;filename&gt;)</title>
		
		<para>For displaying a snippet of code, a filename or anything else you just want to appear as a part of a sentence, we normally use the <computeroutput>&lt;computeroutput&gt; </computeroutput>
			or <filename>&lt;filename&gt;</filename> elements. They take the place of the <filename>&lt;code&gt;</filename> or <filename>&lt;tt&gt;</filename> HTML tags.</para>
		
		<para>For bigger chunks of code, use the <filename>&lt;screen&gt;</filename> tag. Just wrap your code block in it, mono-spacing with indents, and DocBook takes care of it 
			automatically.</para>
		
		<important>
			<simpara>Brackets inside the <filename>&lt;screen&gt;</filename> tag must be represented in code: opening bracket is represented as 
				<computeroutput>&amp;lt;</computeroutput> and the closing bracket is represented as <computeroutput>&amp;gt;</computeroutput>.</simpara>
		</important>
				
	</chapter>
	
	<chapter  id="links" xreflabel="Links and Cross-references"><title>Links and Cross-references </title>
						
			<para>Linking falls into two different categories: inside the version's set of books (for example, everything underneath
				&docpath;) and any links outside of the set.</para>
						
		<section><title>Cross-referencing within a version's docs (&lt;link&gt; and &lt;xref&gt;)</title>
				
				<para>By having unique <link linkend="id">id's</link>, you can cross-reference any section within a version's doc with a simple tag, 
					regardless of where that section is.</para>
				
				<note>
					<simpara>The 4.0 docs were set up differently; in those docs, you can only use this method of internal linking within the same book (project).</simpara>
				</note>
				
			<section id="xref" xreflabel="Using xref"><title>Using &lt;xref&gt;</title>	
				
				<para>The following is an example of a cross-reference (using the <filename>&lt;xref&gt;</filename> tag):</para>
				
				<screen>&lt;para&gt;Find information about headings in &lt;xref linkend="heading" /&gt;.&lt;/para&gt;</screen>
				
				<para>And the HTML/PDF output looks like the following:</para>
				
				<para>Find information about headings in <xref linkend="heading"/>.</para>
				
				<para>Note that this is an empty tag, you must either:</para>
				
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem><para>Provide the end-tag, <filename>&lt;/xref&gt;</filename>, or</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para>Put a slash before the ending-bracket: <filename>&lt;xref linkend="blahblah"/&gt;</filename> </para></listitem>
					<listitem><para>If you want the section's title in the link, make sure you add the <xref linkend="xreflabel"/>.</para></listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
				<para>The <filename>&lt;xref&gt;</filename> tag is really only useful if there is an <xref linkend="xreflabel"/> in the target element. If in doubt, 
					or if you want to use your own wording as the link text, you'll need to use the <filename>&lt;link&gt;</filename> tag 
					(as described below).</para>
			</section>
				
			<section id="link" xreflabel="Using link"><title>Linking internally with &lt;link&gt;</title>
				
				<para>The following is an example of a link (using the <filename>&lt;link&gt;</filename> tag):</para>
				
				<screen>&lt;para&gt;Find information about headings by clicking &lt;link linkend="heading"&gt;here&lt;/link&gt;.&lt;/para&gt;</screen>
				
				<para>And the HTML/PDF output looks like the following:</para>
				
				<para>Find information about headings by clicking <link linkend="heading">here</link>.</para>
				
			</section>
				
				
			</section>
		
			<section><title>Linking outside a version's docs with &lt;ulink&gt;</title>
				
				<para>If you are linking outside of your version's documentation, use the <filename>&lt;ulink&gt;</filename> tag:</para>
				
				<screen>&lt;ulink url="http://www.oracle.com"&gt;Oracle Corporation&lt;/ulink&gt;</screen>
				
				<para>The output will create a hyper-link to Oracle in the HTML-version of the documentation: 
					<ulink url="http://www.oracle.com">Oracle Corporation</ulink>.
				</para>
				
				<important>
					<simpara>Do NOT use ampersands in your hyper links. These are reserved for referencing entities; instead, use the
						following code for ampersand: <computeroutput>&amp;amp;</computeroutput> .</simpara>
				</important>
				
			</section>
		
	</chapter>
	
	<chapter id="graphics" xreflabel="Graphics"><title>Graphics (&lt;figure&gt;)</title>
		
		<note><simpara>Currently this section only takes HTML output into consideration - not a PDF version.</simpara></note>
		
		<para>To insert a graphic we use the <filename>&lt;figure&gt;</filename>,  <filename>&lt;mediaobject&gt;</filename>, and 
			<filename>&lt;imageobject&gt;</filename> elements. 
				<!-- We're not using print-ready tags yet - but might consider it in the future (we just don't seem to need it enough right now. 
				[The news is that you have to provide two 
				versions of all your graphics - one for the Web (probably a GIF or a JPEG) and one for print (EPS).] -->
			You should also provide a brief description wrapped in <filename>&lt;textobject&gt;</filename> - in HTML this will be the ALT text. 
			If you want a caption to appear below the graphic, use the <filename>&lt;caption&gt;</filename> element with a <filename>&lt;para&gt; </filename>tag.</para>
		
		<screen>&lt;figure id="webmds-developer-Webmds_info_flow"&gt;&lt;title&gt;WebMDS Information Flow&lt;/title&gt;
	&lt;mediaobject&gt;
		&lt;imageobject&gt;
			&lt;imagedata fileref="../../info/webmds/Webmds_info_flow.jpg" format="JPEG" align="center"/&gt;
		&lt;/imageobject&gt;
		&lt;textobject&gt;
			&lt;phrase&gt;This is an image of the flow in WebMDS&lt;/phrase&gt;
		&lt;/textobject&gt;
		&lt;caption&gt;
			&lt;para&gt;This is an image of the flow in WebMDS&lt;/para&gt;
		&lt;/caption&gt;
	&lt;/mediaobject&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;</screen>	
	
		<note><para>The path to the graphic should start from the root of the documentation set. The one exception is if you are using a graphic
		 outside of your 'family' (data/, info/, etc), you need to start from your directory, go back up 2 levels (../../) and then use the path to the graphic from there.</para></note>
		
		<para>The HTML output looks like this:</para>
		
		
		<figure><title>WebMDS Information Flow</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata fileref="../../info/webmds/Webmds_info_flow.jpg" format="JPEG" align="center"/>
				</imageobject>
				<textobject>
					<phrase>This is an image of the flow in WebMDS</phrase>
				</textobject>
				<caption>
					<para>This is an image of the flow in WebMDS</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>	
			
		<para>In addition to using the above code, do the following:</para>
		
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem><para>In general, put your graphics in the same directory as the document.</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>Keep the width of the graphic no greater than 700px (500px is best).</para></listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
	
	</chapter>
	
	<chapter id="lists" xreflabel="Lists"><title>Lists</title>
		
		<para>In general, making a list in DocBook is similar to doing the same thing in HTML - except in DocBook, <filename>&lt;li&gt;</filename> 
			becomes <filename>&lt;listitem&gt;</filename> and the text in each <filename>&lt;listitem&gt;</filename>
			must be wrapped in in either a <filename>&lt;para&gt;</filename> or <filename>&lt;simpara&gt;</filename> element.</para>
								
		<para>The following sections describe how to make the DocBook equivalent of the three usual HTML lists: unordered lists, ordered lists and definition lists.</para>
		
			
		<section><title>How to make an unordered list (&lt;itemizedlist&gt;)</title>
			
<screen>&lt;itemizedlist&gt;
	&lt;listitem&gt;&lt;para&gt;Stuff goes here&lt;/para&gt;&lt;/listitem&gt;
	&lt;listitem&gt;&lt;para&gt;More stuff goes here&lt;/para&gt;&lt;/listitem&gt;
&lt;/itemizedlist&gt;</screen>
			
			<para>The HTML/PDF output looks like this:</para>
			
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem><para>Stuff goes here</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para>More stuff goes here</para></listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		
		</section>
		
		<section><title>How to make an ordered list (&lt;orderedlist&gt;)</title>
												
<screen>&lt;orderedlist&gt;
	&lt;listitem&gt;&lt;para&gt;Stuff goes here&lt;/para&gt;&lt;/listitem&gt;
	&lt;listitem&gt;&lt;para&gt;More stuff goes here&lt;/para&gt;&lt;/listitem&gt;
&lt;/orderedlist&gt;</screen>
			
			<para>The HTML/PDF output looks like this:</para>
		
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem><para>Stuff goes here</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para>More stuff goes here</para></listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		
		</section>
		
		<section><title>How to make a definition list (&lt;variablelist&gt;)</title>
			
			<para>This kind of list is called a "variable list" in DocBook and is a little more complex than the previous lists. 
				These are the tags you'll need to make it happen: 
				<filename>&lt;variablelist&gt;</filename>, <filename>&lt;varlistentry&gt;</filename>, <filename>&lt;term&gt;</filename> and 
				<filename>&lt;listitem&gt;</filename>:</para>
														
<screen>&lt;variablelist&gt;
	&lt;varlistentry&gt;
	&lt;term&gt;Definition term goes here&lt;/term&gt;
	&lt;listitem&gt;&lt;para&gt;And definition/description goes here&lt;/para&gt;&lt;/listitem&gt;
	&lt;/varlistentry&gt;
	&lt;varlistentry&gt;
		&lt;term&gt;Another term goes here&lt;/term&gt;
		&lt;listitem&gt;&lt;para&gt;And more stuff goes here&lt;/para&gt;&lt;/listitem&gt;
	&lt;/varlistentry&gt;
&lt;/variablelist&gt;</screen>
		
			<para>The HTML/PDF output looks like this:</para>
		
			<variablelist>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Definition term goes here</term>
					<listitem><para>And definition/description goes here</para></listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Another term goes here</term>
					<listitem><para>And more stuff goes here</para></listitem>
				</varlistentry>
			</variablelist>
			
			<para>Remember, each <filename>&lt;listitem&gt;</filename>
				must be wrapped in in either a <filename>&lt;para&gt;</filename> or <filename>&lt;simpara&gt;</filename> element.</para>
		
		</section>

	</chapter>
	
	<chapter id="tables" xreflabel="Tables"><title>Tables (&lt;informaltable&gt;)</title>
														
		<para>DocBook supports several types of tables, but in most cases, the <ulink url="http://docbook.org/tdg/en/html/informaltable.html">&lt;informaltable&gt;</ulink> 
			is enough:</para>
															
<screen>&lt;informaltable&gt;
	&lt;tgroup cols="3"&gt;
		&lt;thead&gt;
			&lt;row&gt;
				&lt;entry&gt;header1&lt;/entry&gt;
				&lt;entry&gt;header2&lt;/entry&gt;
				&lt;entry&gt;header3&lt;/entry&gt;
			&lt;/row&gt;
		&lt;tbody&gt;
			&lt;row&gt;
				&lt;entry&gt;a1&lt;/entry&gt;
				&lt;entry&gt;b1&lt;/entry&gt;
				&lt;entry&gt;c1&lt;/entry&gt;
			&lt;/row&gt;
			&lt;row&gt;
				&lt;entry&gt;a2&lt;/entry&gt;
				&lt;entry&gt;b2&lt;/entry&gt;
				&lt;entry&gt;c2&lt;/entry&gt;
			&lt;/row&gt;
			&lt;row&gt;
				&lt;entry&gt;a3&lt;/entry&gt;
				&lt;entry&gt;b3&lt;/entry&gt;
				&lt;entry&gt;c3&lt;/entry&gt;
			&lt;/row&gt;
														
		&lt;/tbody&gt;
	&lt;/tgroup&gt;
&lt;/informaltable&gt;</screen>
		
		<para>The output is a simple HTML table:</para>
		
		<informaltable frame="all">
			<tgroup cols="3">
				<thead>
					<row>
						<entry>header1</entry>
						<entry>header2</entry>
						<entry>header3</entry>
					</row>
				</thead>
				<tbody>
					<row>
						<entry>a1</entry>
						<entry>b1</entry>
						<entry>c1</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>a2</entry>
						<entry>b2</entry>
						<entry>c2</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>a3</entry>
						<entry>b3</entry>
						<entry>c3</entry>
					</row>
							
				</tbody>
			</tgroup>
		</informaltable>
		
		<para>If you want cells to span more than one row or column, it gets a bit more complicated - check out 
			<ulink url="http://docbook.org/tdg/en/html/table.html">&lt;table&gt;</ulink> for more information.</para>
	
	</chapter>
	
	<chapter id="emphasis" xreflabel="Italics and Bold"><title>Italics and Bold (&lt;emphasis&gt;)</title>
		
		<para>Our documentation uses two flavors of emphasis - italics and bold type. DocBook uses one - 
			<filename>&lt;emphasis&gt;</filename>.</para>
																	
		<para>The <computeroutput>&lt;emphasis&gt;</computeroutput> tag defaults to italics when parsed. If you want to emphasize with bold type, 
			use <computeroutput>&lt;emphasis role="strong"&gt;</computeroutput>.</para>
		
		<para><emphasis>This little sentence uses just the <computeroutput>&lt;emphasis&gt;</computeroutput> tag.</emphasis></para>
		
		<para><emphasis role="strong">This little sentence uses the <computeroutput>&lt;emphasis role="strong"&gt;</computeroutput> tag.</emphasis></para>
	
	</chapter>
	
	<chapter id="admonitions" xreflabel="Calling attention to text"><title>Calling attention to text</title>
		
		<para>DocBook provides a few elements that can be very useful for calling attention to certain information by setting them off from the text: 
			<filename><ulink url="http://www.docbook.org/tdg/en/html/caution.html">&lt;caution&gt;</ulink></filename>, 
			<filename><ulink url="http://www.docbook.org/tdg/en/html/important.html">&lt;important&gt;</ulink></filename>, 
			<filename><ulink url="http://www.docbook.org/tdg/en/html/tip.html">&lt;tip&gt;</ulink></filename>, and 
			<filename><ulink url="http://www.docbook.org/tdg/en/html/warning.html">&lt;warning&gt;</ulink></filename>.</para>
		
		<section id="caution" xreflabel="Caution"><title>&lt;caution&gt;</title>
	<para>The following are examples of each type (using the DocBook examples):</para>
		
<screen>&lt;caution&gt;&lt;title&gt;No User Servicable Parts Inside&lt;/title&gt;
	&lt;para&gt;
		Breaking this seal voids all warranties.
	&lt;/para&gt;
&lt;/caution&gt;</screen>
		
		
		<caution><title>No User Servicable Parts Inside</title>
			<para>
				Breaking this seal voids all warranties.
			</para>
		</caution></section>

		<section id="important" xreflabel="Important"><title>&lt;important&gt;</title>		
<screen>&lt;important&gt;
	&lt;para&gt;
		No user-servicable parts inside. Breaking this seal voids all warranties.
	&lt;/para&gt;
&lt;/important&gt;</screen>
		
		<important>
			<para>
				No user-servicable parts inside. Breaking this seal voids all warranties.
			</para>
		</important></section>

<section id="note" xreflabel="Note"><title>&lt;note&gt;</title>
<screen>&lt;note&gt;&lt;title&gt;Upcoming Changes&lt;/title&gt;
	&lt;para&gt;
	Future versions of this feature may not be backward-compatible.
	Consider implementing the revised interface now.
	&lt;/para&gt;
&lt;/note&gt;</screen>
		
		<note><title>Upcoming Changes</title>
			<para>
				Future versions of this feature may not be backward-compatible.
				Consider implementing the revised interface now.
			</para>
		</note>
</section>	

<section id="tip" xreflabel="Tip"><title>&lt;tip&gt;</title>		
<screen>&lt;tip&gt;
	&lt;para&gt;
		If you tie your shoelaces, you're less likely to trip and 
		fall down.
	&lt;/para&gt;
&lt;/tip&gt;</screen>
		
		<tip>
			<para>
				If you tie your shoelaces, you're less likely to trip and 
				fall down.
			</para>
		</tip>
</section>

<section id="warning" xreflabel="Warning"><title>&lt;warning&gt;</title>
<screen>&lt;warning&gt;
	&lt;para&gt;
		Striking your thumb with a hammer may cause severe pain and discomfort.
	&lt;/para&gt;
&lt;/warning&gt;</screen>
		
		<warning>
			<para>
				Striking your thumb with a hammer may cause severe pain and discomfort.
			</para>
		</warning>
	</section>	
	</chapter>
	
	<chapter  id="glossary" xreflabel="Glossary"><title>Glossary</title>
		<para>The glossary for each version's release manuals is found online at [path to doc version]/glossary.html For example, we'll use the (current) 
			development docs directory: <ulink url="&docpath;glossary.html">&docpath;glossary.html</ulink>.</para>
		
		<para>Every project should make sure that any jargon or special terms appear in this list. To do so you need to add some markup in two places:</para>
		<orderedlist>
			<listitem><simpara><filename>[path to doc version]/glossary.xml</filename> - This file acts as the centralized glossary database. 
				Terms are added in <computeroutput>&lt;glossdiv&gt;</computeroutput> tags that 
				correspond to the appropriate letter of the alphabet. For example, if you wanted to add the term 
				<emphasis>&quot;proxy certificate&quot;</emphasis>, you would 
				open <filename>glossary.xml</filename>, look for the <computeroutput>&lt;glossdiv&gt;P&lt;/glossdiv&gt;</computeroutput> 
				section and add the following markup in alpha order with the other terms:</simpara>

	<screen>&lt;glossentry id="proxy-cert"&gt;&lt;glossterm&gt;proxy certificate&lt;/glossterm&gt;
	&lt;glossdef&gt;
		&lt;para&gt; A short lived certificate issued using a EEC. 
		A proxy certificate typically has the same effective subject 
		as the EEC that issued it and can thus be used in its place. 
		GSI uses proxy certificates for single sign on and delegation 
		of rights to other entities.&lt;/para&gt;
	&lt;/glossdef&gt;
&lt;/glossentry&gt;</screen>
			</listitem> 
			<listitem><simpara>Next, within your project's documentation, add the <filename>&lt;glossterm&gt;</filename> tag to each instance you want that 
				term linked to the glossary:</simpara>
				<screen>&lt;glossterm&gt;proxy certificate&lt;/glossterm&gt;</screen>
				<important><simpara>If the term in your documentation varies at all from the value of <filename>&lt;glossterm&gt;</filename> in 
					<filename>glossary.xml</filename>, you'll need to 
					add a <filename>baseform</filename> attribute that matches the value:</simpara>
					<screen>&lt;glossterm baseform="proxy certificate"&gt;proxy certificates&lt;/glossterm&gt;</screen>
				</important>
			</listitem>
			
		</orderedlist>
		
		<para>When using an automatic glossary database, there are problems with using the available <filename>&lt;glosssee&gt;</filename> (See) and 
			<filename>&lt;glossseealso&gt;</filename> (See also) tags. Instead, if you want to refer to another glossary term within the database, add 
			something like this (using <filename>&lt;ulink&gt;</filename>):</para>
		
		<screen>See also &lt;ulink url=&quot;&amp;docpath;glossary.html#rli&quot;&gt;RLI&lt;/ulink&gt;.</screen>
		
		<para>where the text after the pound sign (#) is equal to the <filename>id</filename> attribute in the <filename>&lt;glossentry&gt;</filename> tag in 
			<filename>glossary.xml</filename>.</para>
		
		<note><para>Note that <filename>&amp;docpath;</filename> is a system entity that maps to the url of the path to the docs.</para></note>
		
	</chapter>
	
	<chapter id="indexing" xreflabel="Indexing"><title>Indexing</title>
		
		<note><para>This is a very new feature in documentation and will probably not be fully implemented until final release of 4.2. 
		The Documentation Coordinator will be sending emails to <filename>gtmanuals-dev@globus.org</filename> on this subject.</para></note>
		
		<para>You should mark up words in your documents that you would like to see show up in an index (which appears at the
		end of a project's table of contents). We are working on using specialized indexes to consolidate certain
		information (such as &quot;how tos&quot;).</para>
																		
		<para>Use <filename><ulink url="http://docbook.org/tdg/en/html/indexterm.html">&lt;indexterm&gt;</ulink></filename>, 
		<filename><ulink url="http://docbook.org/tdg/en/html/primary.html">&lt;primary&gt;</ulink></filename> and 
		<filename><ulink url="http://docbook.org/tdg/en/html/secondary.html">&lt;secondary&gt;</ulink></filename> for this. See these links for an explanation.</para>
		
	</chapter>
	<chapter><title>Troubleshooting</title>
		<para>TODO - need to show common XML (xmllint) and CVS errors and how to fix them</para>
		<para>What are the most common errors people come across?</para>
		</chapter>
	<!-- 
	<chapter id="convert-to-html" xreflabel="Converting to HTML"><title>Converting to HTML (?)</title>
		
		<note><simpara>This section is quoted almost verbatim from the LDP Author Guide. [need charles to verify/tweak - or
			is this even necessary?]</simpara></note>
																			
		<para>Once you have the Docbook Tools installed, you can convert your xml documents to HTML or other formats.</para>
																			
		<para>With the DocBook XSL stylesheets, generation of multiple files is controlled by the stylesheet. If you want to generate a single file, you call one stylesheet. 
		If you want to generate multiple files, you call a different stylesheet.</para>
																		
		<para>To generate a single HTML file from your DocBook XML file, use the command:</para>
																			
		<screen>bash$  xsltproc -o outputfilename.xml /usr/share/sgml/DocBook/stylesheet/xsl/nwalsh/html/html.xsl filename.xml</screen>
																			
		<note><simpara>This example uses Daniel Veillard's xsltproc command available as part of libxslt from 
		<ulink url="http://www.xmlsoft.org/XSLT/">http://www.xmlsoft.org/XSLT/</ulink>. If you are using other XML 
		processors such as Xalan or Saxon, you will need to change the command line appropriately.</simpara></note>
																			
		<para>To generate a set of linked HTML pages, with a separate page for each &lt;chapter&gt;, &lt;section&gt; or &lt;appendix&gt; tag, use the following command:</para>
																				
		<screen>bash$  xsltproc /usr/share/sgml/DocBook/stylesheet/xsl/nwalsh/html/chunk.xsl filename.xml</screen>
																				
		<para>You could also look at a Makefile (found in most project directories) for examples of how these documents are generated.</para>

	</chapter>
	-->

</book>

