<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<title>GT4 Message &amp; Transport Level Security Developer&apos;s Guide</title>
<titleabbrev>Developer&apos;s Guide</titleabbrev>
<section id="message-developer-introduction"><title>Introduction</title>
  <para>This component contains mainly framework level code and as such
  developing services and clients utilizing this component does in
  general involve either programmatically or declaratively driving the
  framework level security code. Now, what does this entail? On the
  programmatic side of things it involves acquiring credentials, passing
  these credentials on to the framework and setting various
  authentication and protection related flags, either in a descriptor or 
  as properties on a stub object. On the declarative side it involves 
  setting up security descriptors, both client and service side, to 
  prescribe the security policy used to drive the security framework code. </para>
</section>
<section id="message-developer-beforeyoubegin"><title>Before you begin</title>
  <section id="message-developer-features"><title>Feature summary</title>
&WS_AA_Message_Level_Feature_Summary_Frag;
  </section>
  <section id="message-developer-platforms"><title>Tested platforms</title>
&WS_AA_Message_Level_Platform_Summary_Frag;
  </section>
  <section id="message-developer-compatibility"><title>Backward compatibility summary</title>
&WS_AA_Message_Level_Compatibility_Summary_Frag;
  </section>
  <section id="message-developer-dependencies"><title>Technology dependencies</title>
&WS_AA_Message_Level_Dependencies_Summary_Frag;
  </section>
  <section id="message-developer-security_considerations"><title>Security considerations </title>
    &WS_AA_Message_Level_Security_Considerations_Frag;
  </section>
</section>
<section id="message-developer-archdes"><title>Architecture and design overview</title>
  <section><title>Transport Security</title>
    <para>Our implementation of transport security is based on HTTP over SSL, also known as HTTPS, with modifications to path validation to enable X.509 <glossterm baseform="proxy certificate">Proxy Certificate</glossterm> support. In contrast to the GT3 implementation of transport security this implementation does not support delegation of proxy certificates as part of the security handshake.</para>
    <para>Transport security is implemented by layering on top of the <emphasis>GSISocket</emphasis> class provided in JGlobus. This class deals with the security related aspects of connection establishment as well as message protection. The socket interface serves as a abstraction layer that allows the HTTP protocol handling code to be unaware of the underlying security properties of the connection.</para>
    <para> Container-level credentials are required and, irrespective
    of security settings on the service being accessed, these
    credentials are used for handshake.</para>
    <section><title>Server Side Security</title>
      <para>On the server side transport security is enabled by simply switching a non-secure socket implementation with the <emphasis>GSISocket</emphasis> implementation. In addition to this change some code was added to propagate authentication information and message protection settings to the relevant security handlers, in particular the authorization and security policy handlers.</para>
    </section>
    <section> <title>Client Side Security</title>
      <para>On the client side transport security is similarly enabled by  switching a non-secure socket implementation with the <emphasis>GSISocket</emphasis> implementation and registering a protocol handler for HTTPS that uses the secure socket implementation. In practice this means that any messages targeted at a HTTPS endpoint will, irregardless of any stub properties, be authenticated and protected. It also means that any messages sent to a HTTP endpoint will not be secured, again irregardless of any stub properties. Stub properties are only used to communicate the desired message protection level, i.e. either integrity only or integrity and privacy.</para>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section><title>Message Level Security</title>
    <section><title>Server Side Security</title>
      <para>This section aims to describe the message flow and processing that occurs for a security-enabled service. The figure below shows the JAX-RPC handlers that are involved in security related message processing on a server.</para>
      
      <figure id="ServerSideSec"><title>The new certificate is signed by the owner, rather than a CA.</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="security/message/ServerSideSec-Resized.jpg" format="JPEG"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      
      <para>GT4 provides two mechanisms, GSI Secure Conversation and GSI Secure Message security, for authentication and secure communication.</para>
      <para>In the GSI Secure Conversation approach the client establishes a context with the server before sending any data. This context serves to authenticate the client identity to the server and to establish a shared secret using a collocated GSI Secure Conversation Service. Once the context establishment is complete the client can securely invoke an operation on the service by signing or encrypting outgoing messages using the shared secret captured in the context.</para>
      <para>The GSI Secure Message approach differs in that no context is established before invoking an operation. The client simply uses existing keying material, such as an X509 <glossterm>End Entity Certificate</glossterm>, to secure messages and authenticate itself to the service.</para>
      <para>Securing of messages in the GSI Secure Conversation approach, i.e. using  a shared secret, requires less computational effort than using existing keying material in the GSI Secure Message approach. This allows the client to trade off the extra step of establishing a context to enable more computationally efficient messages protection once that context has been established.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Message Processing</title>
      <para>When a message arrives from the client the SOAP engine invokes several security related handlers.</para>
      <para>The first of these handlers, the WS-Security handler, searches the message for any WS-Security headers. From these headers it extracts any keying material, which can be either in the form of an X509 certificate and associated certificate chain or a reference to a previously established secure conversation session. It also checks any signatures and/or decrypts elements in the SOAP body.  The handler then populates a peer JAAS subject object with principals and any associated keying material whose veracity was ascertained during the signature checking or decryption step.</para>
      <para>The next handler that gets invoked, the security policy handler, checks that incoming messages fulfill any security requirements the service may have. These requirements are specified, on a per-operation basis, as part of a security descriptor during service deployment. The security policy handler will also identify the correct JAAS subject to associate with the current thread of execution. Generally this means choosing between the peer subject populated by the WS-Security handler, the subject associated with the hosting environment and the subject associated with the service itself. The actual association is done by the pivot handler, a non-security handler not shown in the figure that handles the details of delivering the message to the service.</para>
      <para>The security policy handler is followed by an authorization handler. This handler verifies that the principal established by the WS-Security handler is authorized to invoke the service. The type of authorization that is performed is specified as part of a deployment descriptor. More information can be found in there <ulink url="&docpath;security/authzframe/developer/">authorization framework documentation</ulink>.</para>
      <para>Once the message has passed the authorization handler it is finally handed off to the actual service for processing (discounting any non security related handlers, which are outside the scope of this document). Replies from the service back to the client are processed by two outbound handlers: the GSI Secure Conversation message handler and the GSI Secure Message handler. The GSI Secure Conversation message handler deals with encrypting and signing messages using a previously established security context, whereas the GSI Secure Message handler deals with messages by signing or encrypting the messages using X509 certificates. The operations that are actually performed depend on the message properties associated with the message by the inbound handlers, i.e. outbound messages will have the same security attributes as inbound messages. That being said, a service has the option of modifying the message properties if so desired. These handlers are identical to the client side handlers described in the following section.</para>
    </section>
    <section><title>Client Side Security</title>
      <para>This section describes the security related message processing for Java-based GT4 clients. 
        In contrast to the server side, where security is specified via deployment descriptors, client side security configuration 
        is handled by the application. This means that a client side application has to explicitly pass information to the client 
        side handlers on what type of security to use. This is also true for the case of services acting as clients. The below figure 
        shows the JAX-RPC handlers that are involved in security related message processing on a server.</para>
      
      <figure id="ClientSideSec"><title>JAX-RPC handlers involved in security related message processing on a server.</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="security/message/ClientSideSec-Resized.jpg" format="JPEG"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      
    </section>
    
    <section><title>Message Processing</title>
      <para>The client side application can specify the use of either the GSI Secure Conversation security approach or the GSI Secure Message security approach. It does this by setting a per message property that is processed by the client side security handlers.</para>
      <para>There are three outbound client side security handlers:</para>
      <para>The secure conversation service handler is only operational if GSI Secure Conversation mode is in use. It establishes a security session with a secure conversation service collocated with the service with which the client aims to communicate. When the client sends the initial message to the service with a property indicating that session based security is required, this handler intercepts the message and establishes a security session. It will also authorize the service by comparing the service&apos;s principal/subject obtained during session establishment with a value provided by the client application. Once the session has been established the handler passes on the original message for further processing.</para>
      <para>The next handler in the chain, the secure message handler, is only operational if GSI Secure Message mode is in use. It signs and/or encrypts messages using X.509 credentials.</para>
      <para>The third outbound handler is operational only if GSI Secure Conversation mode is in use. It handles signing and/or encryption of messages using a security session established by the first handler.</para>
      <para>The client side inbound handler (the WS-Security client handler) deals with verifying and decrypting any signed and/or encrypted incoming messages. In the case of GSI Secure Message operation it will also authorize the remote side in a similar fashion to the outbound secure conversation service handler.</para>
    </section>
  </section>
</section>
<section id="message-developer-pubinterfaces">
  <title>Public interfaces</title>
  <section id="message-developer-apis"><title>Semantics and syntax of APIs</title>
    &WS_AA_Message_Level_Interface_API_Frag;
  </section>
  <section id="message-developer-wsdl"><title>Semantics and syntax of the WSDL</title>
    &WS_AA_Message_Level_Interface_WSDL_Frag;
  </section>
  <section id="message-developer-protocols"><title>Semantics and syntax of  non-WSDL protocols</title>
    &WS_AA_Message_Level_Interface_Protocol_Frag;
  </section>
  <section id="message-developer-protocol"><title>Framework-level Protocols</title>
    &WS_AA_Message_Level_Interface_Protocol_Frag;
  </section>
  <section id="message-developer-cmd"><title>Command-line tools</title>
    &WS_AA_Message_Level_Interface_Commandline_Frag;
  </section>
  <section id="message-developer-guis"><title>Overview of Graphical User Interfaces</title>
    &WS_AA_Message_Level_Interface_GUI_Frag;
  </section>
  <section id="message-developer-domain"><title>Semantics and syntax of domain-specific interface</title>
    &WS_AA_Message_Level_Interface_Domain_Frag;
  </section>
  <section id="message-developer-config"><title>Configuration interface</title>
    &WS_AA_Message_Level_Interface_Config_Frag;
  </section>
  <section id="message-developer-env"><title>Environment variable interface</title>
    &WS_AA_Message_Level_Interface_Env_Frag;
  </section>
</section>

<section id="message-developer-scenarios">
  <title>Usage scenarios</title>
  <section id="message-developer-scenarios-delegation">
  <title>Delegation</title>
  <para>There are two ways a client can delegate its credential to a service: a) using Delegation Service b) using GSI Secure Conversation.</para>

<para> Client can delegate using the <link linkend="delegation">Delegation Service</link>. This method is independent of the security scheme used and can be reused across multiple invocations of the client to multiple services (provided the service are in the same hosting envorinment as the delegation service). The link provided has details on client side steps to delegate and service side code to get the delegated credential.</para>

    <para> GSI Secure Conversation has delegation built into the protocol. Delegation can be requested by setting the <link linkend="message-pi-domain"><constant>GSIConstants.GSI_MODE</constant></link> property on ther Stub or using security descriptors as described in <xref linkend="authzframe-secdesc-client-secConv"/>. If full or limited delegation is performed, the client credential can be obtained from the message context as follows:

<screen>Subject subject = (Subject) msgCtx.getProperty(Constants.PEER_SUBJECT);</screen>
</para>

<para> The server can be configured such that container, service or client credentials are used for the operation invoked. For the client credentials to be used, client should have delegated the credentials. Configuring this option is described in <xref linkend="authzframe-secdesc-configRunas"/>. Note that this is a server side configuration. If <constant>caller-identity</constant> is chosen for the <constant>run-as</constant> configuration and the client's credentials have been successfully delegated, then the delegated credentials are associated with the current thread. The credentials in this case can be obtained as follows:

<screen>Subject subject = JaasSubject.getCurrentSubject();</screen>
</para>

  </section>
  
  <section id="message-developer-scenarios-keyInfoEPR">
	  <title> Embedding Key Information in EPRs </title>
	  <para> The toolikit provides API to embed key information in an Endpoint Reference as defined in the OGSA Basic Security Profile. The key information is embedded in the extensibility element of the EPR rather than the meta-data element as defined in the specification, since the toolkit uses older version of the WS Addressing specification.</para>
	  <para> This information would be useful to ascertain the expected identity of the service for authorizing the service or to get the public certificate of the resource to be used for encrypting the request to the service.  The optional usage element  in the emebedded key information indicates the use of the embedded keys, either for signature or encryption. </para>
	  
	  <para>The API  is in class <constant>org.globus.wsrf.impl.security.util.EPRUtil</constant>. The method to embed the certificates is called <constant>insertCertificates</constant> and the method to extract the key informationis called <constant>extractCertificates</constant>. Please refer to API documentation for details on using the methods.
	   </para>
	  
  </section>
</section>

<section id="message-developer-tutorials">
  <title>Tutorials</title>
  <para>There are no tutorials available at this time.</para>
</section>
<section id="message-developer-debugging">
  <title>Debugging</title>
  <para>There is no content available at this time. </para>
</section>
<section id="message-developer-troubleshooting">
  <title>Troubleshooting</title>
  <para>
    There is no content available at this time.
</para>
</section>
<section id="message-developer-relateddocs">
  <title>Related Documentation</title>
  <simpara>See <xref linkend="message-rn-associatedstandards"/> for a list of associated standards.</simpara>
</section>
