<title>GT 4.0 DRS: System Administrator's Guide</title>
<titleabbrev>System Administrator's Guide</titleabbrev>

<section id="s-datarep-admin-introduction"><title>Introduction</title>
<para>This guide contains advanced configuration information for system administrators
  working with the Data Replication Service (DRS). It provides references to information on procedures
  typically performed by system administrators, including installing, configuring,
 deploying, and testing the installation.</para>
 <important>
  <simpara> This information is in addition to the basic Globus Toolkit prerequisite, 
   overview, installation, security configuration instructions in the <ulink url="../../admin/docbook/">GT 4.0 System Administrator's Guide</ulink>.  
   Read through this guide before continuing!</simpara>  
 </important>
</section>


<section id="s-datarep-admin-installing"><title>Building and installing</title>
    <para>The DRS is installed as part of the default toolkit installation from the source installer. No additional steps are required for installation. The DRS is not included in the binary installer.</para>
</section>


<section id="s-datarep-admin-configuring"><title>Configuring </title>
    <para>This information is in addition to the basic configuration instructions in the <ulink url="http://www.globus.org/toolkit/docs/4.0/admin/docbook/">GT4.0 System Administrator's Guide</ulink>. Aside from the basic configuration of GT 4.0, please review the following instructions:</para>
    &DataRep_Interface_Config_Frag;
</section>

<section id="s-datarep-admin-deploying"><title>Deploying</title>
<para>No further information is necessary.</para>
</section>

<section id="s-datarep-admin-testing"><title>Testing</title>
<para>This service does not provide a set of tests yet.</para>
</section>

<section id="s-datarep-admin-security_considerations"><title>Security considerations</title>
&DataRep_Security_Considerations_Frag;
</section>

<section id="s-datarep-admin-troubleshooting"><title>Troubleshooting</title>
<para>Generating verbose log output is a critical aid in troubleshooting of the DRS and is useful 
when communicating problems to Globus support lists. To increase logging detail, add the following 
line to the <computeroutput>$GLOBUS_LOCATION/container-log4j.properties</computeroutput> file.</para>
<screen>
 ...
 log4j.category.org.globus.replica=DEBUG
 ...
</screen>
<!-- TODO Add troubleshooting help for problems related to:
  1) invalid index url
  2) invalid registration url
  3) invalid rft url
  4) improperly formated request file
  5) system freeze
-->
</section>
