<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd" [

<!ENTITY % xinclude SYSTEM "../xinclude.mod">
%xinclude;
<!ENTITY prompt "<prompt>&#37; </prompt>" >
]>

<section id="gram5-troubleshooting-client"><title>GRAM Client Troubleshooting</title>
    <indexterm type="gram5"><primary>troubleshooting</primary></indexterm>
    <indexterm type="gram5"><primary>troubleshooting</primary><secondary>errors</secondary></indexterm>

    <section><title>Credential Problems</title>
        <para>
        GRAM requires a client certificate and private key in order
        authenticate with the GRAM service. If these are not available, the
        GRAM client will fail. In typical use, a user will create a temporary
        proxy certificate either derived from their identity certificate issued
        by some certificate authority, or from a service such as myproxy. If a
        GRAM client command returns any error containing the string
        <literal>GSS Major Status</literal> you've hit a credential problem.
        Look at the <olink targetdoc="gsicUser"
        targetptr="security-credential-errors">Troubleshooting Section</olink>
        of the GSI manual for details about how to diagnose and correct these
        errors. The <command><olink targetdoc="gsicUser"
        targetptr="grid-cert-diagnostics">grid-cert-diagnostics</olink></command> tool
        with the <option>-p</option> command-line option is especially helpful
        for diagnosing some of these types of problems.
        </para>
    </section> <!--Credential Problems-->

    <section><title>Connection Failures</title>
        <para>
        There are three types of problems which can cause apparent connection
        failures: the service isn't running on the given resource name, it
        does not accept your credential for some reason, or you do not trust the
        service's credential.
        
        In the former two case, please
        contact the administrator of the GRAM resource to determine the cause.
        The <olink targetdoc="gram5Admin"
        targetptr="gram5-admin-debugging">Troubleshooting section</olink> of
        the GRAM Admin Guide contains information about debugging these by
        checking that the service is running and be looking at the
        <filename>/var/log/globus-gatekeeper.log</filename> file.
        </para>
    </section> <!-- Connection Failures -->

</section> <!--Client Troubleshooting-->
