<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<title>GT4 WS AA User&apos;s Guide</title>
<titleabbrev>User&apos;s Guide</titleabbrev>

<section id="authzframe-user-introduction">

  <title>Introduction</title>

  <para>Users who run clients can programmatically set up the authorization scheme to be enforced on a per invocation basis. The properties and
configuration information required depends on the configured
authorization scheme.  Refer to <xref linkend="authzframe-admin-configuring"/>
</para>

</section>

<section id="authzframe-user-commandline">
  <title>Command line tools</title>
  &WS_AA_Authz_Interface_Commandline_Frag;
</section>

<section id="authzframe-user-gui">

  <title>Graphical user interfaces</title>
&WS_AA_Authz_Interface_GUI_Frag;
</section>

<section id="authzframe-user-troubleshooting">
  <title>Troubleshooting</title>

  <section>
    <title>Authorization failed</title>

    <orderedlist>

      <listitem>

        <para>Using self authorization: Ensure that the client is running with the same credentials as the effective server-side credential (resource, service, container credential, in the order of occurrence).</para>

      </listitem>

      <listitem>

        <para>Using host authorization: <itemizedlist>

            <listitem>

              <para>Ensure that the effective server-side credential (resource, service, container credential, in the order of occurrence) is the host credential of the machine on which the service is running. </para>

            </listitem>

            <listitem>

              <para>Ensure that the client is not using 127.0.0.1 as the host address to access the service, but the actual host name.</para>

            </listitem>

          </itemizedlist></para>

      </listitem>

      <listitem>

        <para>Using identity authorization: Ensure that the DN matches the server&apos;s DN exactly. If using the command line interface quotes might have to be placed around the DN string for spaces to be maintained.</para>

      </listitem>

    </orderedlist>

  </section>

  <section>

    <title>No authorization with delegation fails</title>

    <para>When using GSI Secure Conversation delegation of credentials cannot be done if no authorization of the server is done (that is, if client side authorization is set to none). Use any other form of authorization while delegating.</para>

    <para>Alternatively, <link linkend="delegation">Delegation Service</link> can be used to delegate credentials in scenarios where delegated credentials are required but no authorization of the server is required.</para>

    <important>

      <para>Delegating credentials without authorizing server is not recommended since a malicious server can obtain the client&apos;s credential.</para>

    </important>

  </section>

</section>

