<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd"
[

<!ENTITY % xinclude SYSTEM "../../../xinclude.mod" >
%xinclude;

]>
<book id="myproxyUser">
<title>GT <replaceable role="entity">version</replaceable> MyProxy: User's Guide</title>
<titleabbrev>User's Guide</titleabbrev>

<chapter id="myproxy-user-introduction"><title>Introduction</title>

  <para> The MyProxy User's Guide provides general end user-oriented information. The major end-user issues are 
    <olink targetptr="myproxy-user-store-cred">storing</olink> and <olink targetptr="myproxy-user-retrieve-cred">retrieving</olink> credentials in the MyProxy repository.
</para>

</chapter>
<chapter id="myproxy-user-usagescenarios">
<title>Using MyProxy</title>
  <section id="myproxy-user-store-cred">
  <title>Storing a credential in the MyProxy repository</title>
    <para>
      Rather than storing your X.509 credentials
      (certificate and <glossterm>private key</glossterm>)
      on each machine you use,
      you can store them in a MyProxy repository
      and retrieve a <glossterm baseform="proxy credentials">proxy credential</glossterm> from the MyProxy repository when
      needed.
    </para>
    <para>
      To store a credential in the MyProxy repository, run the
      <command>myproxy-init</command> command
      on a computer where your Grid credentials are located.
      For example:
      <screen>
        $ myproxy-init -a -s myproxy.ncsa.uiuc.edu
        Your identity: /C=US/O=National Computational Science Alliance/CN=Jim Basney
        Enter GRID pass phrase for this identity:
        Creating proxy ........................................... Done
        Your proxy is valid until Fri Sep 13 13:52:56 2002
        Enter MyProxy Pass Phrase:
        Verifying password - Enter MyProxy Pass Phrase:
        A proxy valid for 168 hours (7.0 days) for user jbasney now exists on myproxy.ncsa.uiuc.edu.
      </screen>
      The <command>myproxy-init</command> command
      prompts first for the pass phrase of your private key
      (similar to <command>grid-proxy-init</command>) and
      then prompts twice for a new pass phrase to use to secure the
      credentials on the MyProxy server.
      By default, the credential is stored under your Unix username (jbasney
      in the example above) for 7 days and can be used to retrieve
      credentials with 12 hour lifetimes.
      <olink targetptr="myproxy-user-commandline"/> below lists all the available options for the myproxy-init command.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section id="myproxy-user-retrieve-cred">
    <title>Retrieving a credential from the MyProxy repository</title>
    <para>
      Once you've stored a credential in the MyProxy repository, you can
      retrieve a proxy credential whenever you need one with the 
      <command>myproxy-logon</command>
      command.
      For example:
      <screen>
        $ myproxy-logon -s myproxy.ncsa.uiuc.edu
        Enter MyProxy Pass Phrase:
        A proxy has been received for user jbasney in /tmp/x509up_u500
      </screen>
      The
      <command>myproxy-logon</command>
      command prompts for the pass phrase you set previously with
      <command>myproxy-init</command>, retrieves a proxy
      credential for you, and stores it in the correct default location for
      use with other Globus Toolkit programs.
      The <olink targetptr="myproxy-commandline"/>
      lists all the available options for the
      <command>myproxy-logon</command> command.
    </para>
  </section>
  
</chapter>

  <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
    href="../Cred_Mgmt_MyProxy_Interface_Commandline_Frag.xml"/>

<!-- 
<chapter id="myproxy-user-gui"><title>Graphical user interfaces</title>
  <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
    href="../Cred_Mgmt_MyProxy_Interface_GUI_Frag.xml"/>
</chapter>
  -->
<chapter id="myproxy-user-troubleshooting"><title>Troubleshooting</title>

<para>
When troubleshooting a MyProxy problem, it is important to consult the
myproxy-server logs.  If you don't have access to the myproxy-server
logs, please contact your myproxy-server administrator for help.
The myproxy-server logs to the system logger (syslog) LOG_DAEMON
facility.
Alternatively, run
</para>
<blockquote><para><command>myproxy-server -d</command></para></blockquote>
<para>
from a terminal.
In that mode, the myproxy-server will write debugging messages to the
terminal and exit after servicing a single request.
</para>

<para>
The most common cause of MyProxy authentication problems is incorrect
system clocks.  GSI authentication is very sensitive to clock skew.
Make sure your system clock is accurate (for example, by running 
<ulink url="http://www.ntp.org/">NTP</ulink>)
and your timezone is set correctly.
</para>

<para>
To debug GSI authentication problems, run
</para>
<blockquote><para><command>grid-proxy-init -debug -verify</command></para></blockquote>
<para>from the terminal where you run the MyProxy clients, and run</para>
<blockquote><para><command>grid-proxy-init -debug -verify -cert
/etc/grid-security/hostcert.pem -key
/etc/grid-security/hostkey.pem</command></para></blockquote>
<para>
as root on the myproxy-server machine (assuming you run the
myproxy-server as root).
</para>

<para>
The following common problems are documented below:
</para>

<section id="myproxy-user-servername"><title>MyProxy server name does not match expected
name.</title>
<para>
This error appears as a mutual authentication failure or a server
authentication failure, and the error message should list two names:
the expected name of the MyProxy server and the actual authenticated
name.  By default, the MyProxy clients expect the MyProxy server to be
  running with a <glossterm>host certificate</glossterm> that matches the target hostname.
This error can occur when running the
MyProxy server under a non-host certificate or if the server is
running on a machine with multiple hostnames.  The MyProxy clients
authenticate the identity of the MyProxy server to avoid sending
passphrases and credentials to rogue servers.
</para>
<para>
If the expected name contains an IP address, your system is unable to
do a reverse lookup on that address to get the canonical hostname of
the server, indicating either a problem with that machine's DNS record
or a problem with the resolver on your system.
</para>
<para>
If the server name shown in the error message is acceptable, set the
MYPROXY_SERVER_DN environment variable to that name to resolve the
problem.
</para>
</section>
<section id="myproxy-user-bind"><title>Error in bind(): Address already in use</title>
<para>
This error indicates that the myproxy-server port (default: 7512) is
in use by another process, probably another myproxy-server instance.
You can not run multiple instances of the myproxy-server on the same
network port.
If you want to run multiple instances of the myproxy-server on a
machine, you can specify different ports with the -p option, and then
give the same -p option to the MyProxy commands to tell them to use
the myproxy-server on that port.
</para>
</section>
<section id="myproxy-user-gpi"><title>grid-proxy-init failed</title>
<para>
This error indicates that the grid-proxy-init command failed when
myproxy-init attempted to run it, which implies a problem with the
underlying Globus installation.  Run
</para>
<blockquote><para>
<command>grid-proxy-init -debug -verify</command>
</para></blockquote>
<para>
for more information.
</para>
</section>

<section id="myproxy-user-auth"><title>User not authorized</title>
<para>
An error from the myproxy-server saying you are "not authorized" to
complete an operation typically indicates that the
myproxy-server.config
file settings are restricting your access to the
myproxy-server.  It is possible that the myproxy-server is running
with the default myproxy-server.config file, which does not authorize
any operations.
See <olink targetdoc="myproxyAdmin" targetptr="myproxy-configuring"/> for more information.
</para>
</section>

</chapter>
  <glossary role="auto" id="glossary-myproxyUser">
    <!-- 
    <remark>some terms not in the docs but wanted in glossary: 
    <glossterm>scheduler</glossterm>
    </remark>
    -->
    <glossdiv><title>A</title>
      <glossentry>
        <glossterm>Dummy term</glossterm>
        <glossdef>
          <para>This is a dummy entry for the automatic glossary database. Do not edit.</para>
        </glossdef>
      </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
  </glossary>
</book>