<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<para>
Overall, WS GRAM in 4.0.2 is much improved over 4.0.1.
</para>

<para>
A focussed (and ongoing) effort for large job loads to complete reliably has helped to identify a number of improvements.  See <ulink url="http://bugzilla.globus.org/bugzilla/show_bug.cgi?id=4197">Campaign 4197</ulink> for the complete details and note the 6 bugs marked as dependencies to this bug.  One of the 6 improvements made ( <ulink url="http://bugzilla.globus.org/bugzilla/show_bug.cgi?id=4330">Enh 4330</ulink>) was implementing a better algorithm for processing jobs from the internal job run queue. This improved responsiveness significantly.  During a large throughput run to a 4.0.1 WS GRAM service, a separate simple /bin/date Fork job took > 10 minutes to return.  In 4.0.2 the same Fork job was processed in ~2 minutes.
</para>

<para>
The WS GRAM testing infrastructure has been improved with automated throughput testing - http://skynet-login.isi.edu/gram-testing/.  Nightly the WS GRAM code is checked out of various CVS branches, built, and throughput tests run.  This has helped identify bugs more quickly and ease the effort toward resolving bugs that can be difficult to reproduce.  For a good example, see <ulink url="http://bugzilla.globus.org/bugzilla/show_bug.cgi?id=4253">bug 4235</ulink>.  The WS GRAM service is not released until these tests are passing consistently from the CVS release branch.  This has helped us provide an overall better WS GRAM service.
</para>

<para>
There were 38 bug fixes since 4.0.1, here are a few worth highlighting:
</para>
<itemizedlist>
   <listitem>
      <simpara>Improvements were made to help identify service installation/configuration problems between WS GRAM and the local Resource   Manager, by improving the SEG reporting on fatal errors.
           <ulink url="http://bugzilla.globus.org/bugzilla/show_bug.cgi?id=4229">Bug 4229</ulink>
      </simpara>
   </listitem>
   <listitem>
      <simpara>The variable "SCRATCH_DIRECTORY" was not being set in the job's environment.
           <ulink url="http://bugzilla.globus.org/bugzilla/show_bug.cgi?id=4192">Bug 4192</ulink>
      </simpara>
   </listitem>
   <listitem>
      <simpara>WS GRAM was not failing the job on some fatal error conditions.
           <ulink url="http://bugzilla.globus.org/bugzilla/show_bug.cgi?id=4247">Bug 4247</ulink>
           <ulink url="http://bugzilla.globus.org/bugzilla/show_bug.cgi?id=4279">Bug 4279</ulink>
           <ulink url="http://bugzilla.globus.org/bugzilla/show_bug.cgi?id=3631">Bug 3631</ulink>
      </simpara>
   </listitem>
   <listitem>
      <simpara>Job error reporting was improved.
           <ulink url="http://bugzilla.globus.org/bugzilla/show_bug.cgi?id=3742">Bug 4273</ulink>
           <ulink url="http://bugzilla.globus.org/bugzilla/show_bug.cgi?id=4241">Bug 4241</ulink>
      </simpara>
   </listitem>
   <listitem>
      <simpara>For the (default) INFO logging, WS GRAM will produce entry and exit logging for a job.
           <ulink url="http://bugzilla.globus.org/bugzilla/show_bug.cgi?id=3742">Bug 3742</ulink>
      </simpara>
   </listitem>
</itemizedlist>
