<title>WS GRAM Scalability and Performance Recommendations</title>
<para>This document includes recommendations for increasing the scalability and performance of WS GRAM in a Grid.</para> 
<section><title>Server-side Recommendations</title>
<orderedlist>
<listitem><para>GRAM4 service and or container can run out of memory under lower
    settings. For this reason, set the Max container heap size to be 1GB.</para>
    <screen>GLOBUS_OPTIONS="-Xms256M -Xmx1024M"</screen></listitem>

<listitem><para>The account the container runs under, typically "globus", can run
    out of open file descriptors. For this reason, set the open file
    descriptors to 16,384.</para>
    <screen>&lt;example of setting this. Varies per OS, but pick one as an example&gt;</screen></listitem>
<listitem><para>The GRAM4 service stores the per job metadata used for crash/
        recovery in files on disk. By default, the container account's
        home dir is used, specifically <filename>~/.globus/persisted/</filename>. Often this
        home dir is not located on a local disk, but on NFS. NFS is not
        needed for this purpose and can negatively effect performance.
    For this reason, configure the container to use a local disk.</para>
        <screen>GLOBUS_OPTIONS="-Dorg.globus.wsrf.container.persistence.dir=/use/this/path"</screen>
</listitem>
    
        <listitem><para>The container can run out of container threads resulting in client-
        side timeouts. The default is too low in GT 4.0.5 and earlier
        releases.  We recommend these settings as part of the
        global configuration in
        <filename>$GLOBUS_LOCATION/etc/globus_wsrf_core/server-config.wsdd</filename>:</para>
        <screen>
&lt;globalConfiguration:
    ...
    &lt;parameter name="containerThreads" value="4"/&gt;
    &lt;parameter name="containerThreadsMax" value="200"/&gt;
    &lt;parameter name="containerThreadsHighWaterMark" value="10"/&gt;
    ...
&lt;/globalConfiguration&gt;
        </screen>
            <para>For more information, see global configurations under Java WS Core <ulink url="http://www-unix.globus.org/toolkit/docs/4.0/common/javawscore/admin-index.html#s-javawscore-admin-configuring">here</ulink>.</para>
        </listitem>    
            <listitem><para>To significantly improve the performance of jobs that include
            file staging, set the value of the parameter <parameter>enableLocalInvocations</parameter>
            to true in the homeConfiguration of the ManagedJobFactoryService in
            <filename>$GLOBUS_LOCATION/etc/gram-service/jndi-config.xml</filename>.
            This however can only be done if WS-GRAM and RFT, which is used for
            staging, are co-located in the same container:</para>
            
<screen>
...
    &lt;parameter&gt;
        &lt;name&gt;
            enableLocalInvocations
        &lt;/name&gt;
        &lt;value&gt;
            true
        &lt;/value&gt;
    &lt;/parameter&gt;
...
</screen></listitem>
</orderedlist>
</section>            
 <section><title>Client-side Recommendations</title>
<orderedlist><listitem><para>            
            To avoid client-side timeouts in job submissions to a GT4 server
            under heavy load, the default of 2 minutes can be increased.
            To do this with globusrun-ws add the <option>-T &lt;milliseconds&gt;</option> options
                to the job submission command and see globusrun-ws -help for further
                information.
                To do this with the Java API GramJob call the method setTimeOut():</para>
<screen>
...
GramJob gramJob = new GramJob (...)
gramJob.setTimeOut(300000); // value in milliseconds
...
</screen></listitem>
                
                <listitem><para>If Condor-G is used as client: Make sure to use Condor version
                6.9.3 or higher.  In this version, the communication with the WS-GRAM service has been improved by consolidating 
    multiple web service operations into one.  Also, Condor-G includes its own version of GT related Java archives.  6.9.2 and earlier contain 
    an old version of these archives that cause occasional security errors when submitting to a 4.0.5 WS GRAM service.</para></listitem>
                </orderedlist>
                </section>