    <para>The WS MDS Aggregator Framework is the software framework on which WS MDS
        services are built. The aggregator framework collects data from an
        <emphasis>aggregator source</emphasis> and sends that data to an <emphasis>aggregator
            sink</emphasis> for processing. Aggregator sources distributed with the
        Globus Toolkit include modules that query service data, acquire
        data through subscription/notification, and execute programs to
        generate data.</para>
        
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata entityref="info_flow" format="JPEG" align="center"/>
            </imageobject>
            <textobject>
                <phrase>Graphic of Information Services Flow</phrase>
            </textobject>
        </mediaobject>
        
        <para>The Aggregator framework is designed to facilitate the
            collecting of information from or about WS-Resources via plugin
            aggregator sources and the feeding of that information to plugin
            aggregator sinks, which can then perform actions such as
            re-publishing, logging, or archiving the information.</para>
            <para>Aggregators work on a type of service group called an
                <command>AggregatorServiceGroupRP</command>. Resources may be
                <emphasis>registered</emphasis> to an AggregatorServiceGroupRP using the service
                group <computeroutput>add</computeroutput> operation, which will cause an entry to be
                added to the service group. The entry will include configuration
                parameters for the aggregator source; when the registration is
                made, the appropriate aggregation source and sinks will be
                informed; the aggregator source will begin collecting data and
                inserting it into the corresponding service group entry, and the
                aggregator sink will begin processing the information in the
                service group entries.</para>
                <para>The method of collection by source and processing by the sink is
                    dependent on the particular instantiation of the aggregator
                    framework.</para>
                    <para>The aggregator sinks distributed with the toolkit
                        (<computeroutput>org.globus.mds.aggregator.impl.ServiceGroupEntryAggregatorSink</computeroutput>
                        and <computeroutput>org.globus.mds.trigger.impl.TriggerResource</computeroutput>) are
                        described in the following table.</para>
                        <table><title>Standard aggregator sinks</title>
                            <tgroup cols="3">
                                <thead>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Aggregator Sink</entry>
                                        <entry>Service Implemented</entry>
                                        <entry>Description</entry>
                                    </row></thead>
                                <tbody>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry><computeroutput>ServiceGroupEntryAggregatorSink</computeroutput></entry>
                                        <entry>Index Service</entry>
                                        <entry>The servicegroup sink (used by the <glossterm linkend="index-service">Index Service</glossterm>)
                                            publishes received data as content in the AggregatingServiceGroup
                                            entry used to manage the registration. This data can therefore be
                                            retrieved by querying the index for its 'entries' resource
                                            property.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry><computeroutput>TriggerResource</computeroutput></entry>
                                        <entry>Trigger Service</entry>
                                        <entry>The <glossterm linkend="trigger-service">Trigger Service</glossterm> provides an aggregator sink
                                            which receives data, applies tests to that data, and if the tests
                                            match, runs a specified executable. See the <ulink url=
                                                "http://www.globus.org/toolkit/docs/4.0/info/aggregator/trigger/">trigger service</ulink> documentation for more
                                            information.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                </tbody></tgroup>
                        </table>
                        <para>The aggregator sources supplied with the toolkit are listed in
                            the following table. Note: all aggregator sources listed in this
                            table are in the <computeroutput>org.globus.mds.aggregator.impl</computeroutput>
                            package, so for example the aggregator source listed as
                            <computeroutput>QueryAggregatorSource</computeroutput> is actually
                            <computeroutput>org.globus.mds.aggregator.impl.QueryAggregatorSource</computeroutput></para>
                            <table><title>Standard aggregator sources</title>
                                <tgroup cols="2">
                                    <thead>
                                        <row>
                                            <entry>Aggregator Source</entry>
                                            <entry>Description</entry>
                                        </row>
                                    </thead><tbody>
                                        <row>
                                            <entry>QueryAggregatorSource</entry>
                                            <entry>The query source collects information from a
                                                registered resource by using WS-Resource Properties polling
                                                mechanisms (the GetResourceProperty, GetResourceProperties and
                                                QueryResourceProperties operations). Polls are made periodically,
                                                with both the period and target Resource Properties specified in
                                                the registration message.</entry>
                                        </row>
                                        <row>
                                            <entry>SubscriptionAggregatorSource</entry>
                                            <entry>The subscription source collects information from
                                                a registered resource using WS-Notification mechanisms. Data is
                                                delivered when property values change, rather than
                                                periodically.</entry>
                                        </row>
                                        <row>
                                            <entry>ExecutionAggregatorSource</entry>
                                            <entry>The execution source collects information about
                                                (not necessarily from) a registered resource by execution of a
                                                local executable, which is passed as input the identity of the
                                                registered resource. Details of the interface between the execution
                                                source and local executables are in <ulink url=
                                                    "http://www.globus.org/toolkit/docs/4.0/info/aggregator/WS_MDS_Aggregator_Public_Interfaces.html#domain">the domain
                                                    specific interfaces section of the Aggregator Framework Public
                                                    Interface Guide</ulink>.</entry>
                                        </row>
                                    </tbody></tgroup>
                            </table>
