<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<title>GT4 Message &amp; Transport Level Security Admin Guide</title>
<titleabbrev>Admin Guide</titleabbrev>

<section id="message-admin-introduction">
  <title>Introduction</title>
  <para>This guide contains advanced configuration information for system administrators
  working with Message/Transport-level Security. It provides references to information
  on procedures typically performed by system administrators, including installing,
    configuring, deploying, and testing the installation.</para>
  <important>
    <simpara>This information is in addition to the basic Globus Toolkit prerequisite, overview, installation, security configuration instructions in the <xref linkend="gtadmin"/>. Read through this guide before continuing!</simpara>
  </important>
  <para>The main administration issues for this component deal with configuring
credential related settings. There are multiple mechanisms for
doing this:</para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>Security Descriptors<itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <simpara>Container Security Descriptor: This is the <emphasis>preferred</emphasis> mechanism.</simpara>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <simpara>Service Security Descriptor</simpara>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist></para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <simpara>CoG properties</simpara>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <simpara>Environment variables</simpara>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <simpara>Relying on default behavior. The only default behaviors available concern the proxy file and trusted certificates locations.</simpara>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>More information on these mechanisms can be found in the <link linkend="message-pi">public interface guide</link>.
</para>
</section>
<section id="message-admin-installing">
  <title>Building and Installing</title>
  <para>The GT4 Message &amp; Transport Level Security component is currently installed as part of the GT4 Java WS Core component. More information on installing this component  can be found in <xref linkend="javawscore-admin-installing"/>.</para>
</section>
<section id="message-admin-configuring">
  <title>Configuring </title>
&WS_AA_Message_Level_Interface_Config_Frag;
</section>
<section id="message-admin-deploying">
  <title>Deploying</title>
  <para>The GT4 Message &amp; Transport Level Security component is currently deployed as part of the GT4 Java WS Core component.</para>
</section>
<section id="message-admin-testing">
  <title>Testing</title>
  <para>The GT4 Message &amp; Transport Security tests are intermingled with tests for the GT4 Authorization Framework and thus are also executed when running the authorization tests. Information on how to run the authorization tests can be found in <xref linkend="authzframe-admin-testing"/>.</para>
</section>
<section id="message-admin-security_considerations">
  <title>Security Considerations </title>
&WS_AA_Message_Level_Security_Considerations_Frag;
  <section>
    <title>File permissions</title>
    <para>The Java security code currently does not enforce secure permissions and, implicitly,  file ownership requirements on any of the security related files, e.g. configuration and credential files. It is thus important that administrators ensure that the relevant files have correct permissions  and ownership. Permissions should generally be as restrictive as possible,  i.e. <glossterm linkend="priv-key">private keys</glossterm> should be readable only by the file owner and other files should be writable by owner only, and the files should generally be owned by the globus user (the requirements that the C code enforces  are documented in <xref linkend="prewsaa-pi-config"/>).</para>

  </section>
</section>
<section id="message-admin-troubleshooting">
  <title>Troubleshooting</title>
&Credential_Troubleshooting_Frag;
</section>
