<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="wsrls-error-codes"><title>Errors</title>
 <indexterm type="wsrls">
  <primary>errors</primary>
 </indexterm>
 
  <table frame='all' id="wsrls-errors-table"><title>WS Replica Location Service (WS RLS) Errors</title>
<tgroup cols='3' align='left' colsep='1' rowsep='1'>
<colspec colname='c1' />
<colspec colname='c2' />
<colspec colname='c3' />
<thead>
<row>
  <entry>Error Code</entry>
  <entry>Definition</entry>
  <entry>Possible Solutions</entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody>
<row>
  <entry><code>Error: java.lang.NullPointerException</code></entry>
  <entry>When invoking the WS RLS command-line clients, a system-level exception like the one above may be encountered. </entry>
  <entry>
The admin should check the container logs for the exact error.
  </entry>
</row>
 <row>
  <entry><code>Error: A server error occured while processing the request</code></entry>
  <entry>When invoking the WS RLS command-line clients, a server error like the one above may be encountered.</entry>
  <entry>
The admin should check the container logs for the exact error.
  </entry>
 </row>
 <row>
  <entry><code>java.lang.UnsatisfiedLinkError</code></entry>
  <entry>This exception when using the WS RLS may indicate that the native RLS libraries that WS RLS depends on could not be located. </entry>
  <entry>
To correct this problem, ensure that the <filename>$GLOBUS_LOCATION/lib</filename> directory is in the library search path (on some systems this is the <envar>LD_LIBRARY_PATH</envar> variable).
  </entry>
 </row>
 <row>
  <entry><code>Unable to connect to localhost:39281</code></entry>
  <entry>The WS RLS is an interface layer that depends on the RLS for the replica location functionality. You must install and run RLS and configure WS RLS to use the RLS via its JNDI configuration.</entry>
  <entry>
Check that RLS is installed, running, and check that the WS RLS JNDI configuration [default path to file? fixme] uses the correct hostname and port to connect to the RLS.
  </entry>
 </row>
 <row>
  <entry><code>org.globus.common.ChainedIOException: Failed to initialize security context</code></entry>
  <entry>If this exception occurs while using WS RLS, it may indicate that the user's proxy is invalid.</entry>
  <entry>
To correct the error, the user must properly initialize the user proxy. See <olink targetdoc="gsicUser" targetptr="grid-proxy-init">grid-proxy-init</olink> for more information on proxy initialization.
  </entry>
 </row>
 <row>
  <entry><code>Error: org.xml.sax.SAXException: Unregistered type: class xxx</code></entry>
  <entry>If this exception occurs when using the WS RLS, it may indicate that an Axis generated XML type, defined by the WS RLS XSD, 
   was not properly registered. While all the XML types should get registered upon deployment without intervention by the user, 
   sometimes they do not.</entry>
  <entry>
To remedy the situation add a <computeroutput>typeMapping</computeroutput> to the <filename>server-config.wsdd</filename> file under <filename>globus_wsrf_replicalocation_service</filename>.
    Use the format shown <olink targetdoc="javawscoreDeveloper" targetptr="javawscore-developer-qname">here</olink>.
   
  </entry>
</row>
 <!-- just copy the <row> block above for each row you need to add -->
</tbody>
</tgroup>
   </table>
</section>
