          <row>
              <entry>Common options</entry>
              <entry> The following options are common to all CAS command-line tools</entry>
          </row>
         
          <row>
              <entry><para><emphasis>-c cas-url</emphasis></para></entry>
              <entry><para><emphasis>CAS Service URL: </emphasis>This option can be
                  used to set the CAS Service instance, where <emphasis>cas-url</emphasis> is the URL of
                  the CAS service instance. Alternatively, an environment variable can
                  be set as shown <ulink
                      url="http://www.globus.org/toolkit/docs/4.0/security/cas/WS_AA_CAS_Public_Interfaces.html#urlOption">here</ulink>.
              </para>
                  
                  <para>The instance URL typically looks like
                      <command>http://<emphasis>Host</emphasis>:<emphasis>Port</emphasis>/wsrf/services/CASService</command>,
                      where <emphasis>Host</emphasis> and <emphasis>Port</emphasis> are the host and port where the container with the CAS service is running.</para>
              </entry>
          </row>
          
          <row>
              <entry><emphasis>-s server-identity</emphasis></entry>
              <entry><para><emphasis>CAS Service Identity: </emphasis> This
                  option can be used to set the expected CAS server identity, where
                  <emphasis>server-identity</emphasis> is the identity of the CAS
                  service. Alternatively, an environment variable can be set as shown <ulink
                      url="http://www.globus.org/toolkit/docs/4.0/security/cas/WS_AA_CAS_Public_Interfaces.html#serverIdentity">here</ulink>. If
                  neither is set, host authorization is done and the expected server
                  credential is <emphasis>cas/&lt;fqdn&gt;</emphasis>, where &lt;fqdn&gt; is the fully
                  qualified domain name of the host on which the CAS service is up.</para>
                  <note> <para> If the service being contacted is using GSI Secure
                      Transport, then the container credentials configured for the service
                      will be used, even if service/resource level credentials are
                      configured. Hence authorization needs to be done based on the DN of
                      the container credentials.</para></note></entry>
          </row>
          
          <row>
              <entry>
                  <emphasis>-debug</emphasis>
              </entry>
              <entry>
                  <para><emphasis>Debug:</emphasis> To run the client with debug message traces and
                      error stack traces, the <emphasis>-debug</emphasis> flag must be used.</para>
              </entry>
          </row>
          
          <row>
              <entry>
                  <emphasis>-help</emphasis>
              </entry>
              <entry>
                  <para><emphasis>Usage: </emphasis>The <emphasis>-help</emphasis> flag prints the usage message for the
                      client.</para>
              </entry>
          </row>
          
          <row>
              <entry>
                  <emphasis>-v</emphasis>
              </entry>
              <entry>
                  <para><emphasis>Version number: </emphasis>The <emphasis><emphasis>-v</emphasis></emphasis> flag prints the version number.</para>
              </entry>
          </row>
          
          <row>
              <entry>
                  <emphasis>-m</emphasis>
              </entry>
              <entry>
                  <para><emphasis>Security Mechanism:</emphasis> The <emphasis>-m</emphasis> flag is used to
                      set the chosen security mechanism. It can be set to 'msg' for Secure
                      Message, 'conv' for Secure Conversation and 'trans' for Transport
                          security. If not set and the server URL starts with 'https', Transport
                      Security is used, else Secure Message is used.</para>
              </entry>
          </row>
          
          <row>
              <entry>
                  <emphasis>-p</emphasis>
              </entry>
              <entry><para><emphasis>Protection type:</emphasis> The <emphasis>-p</emphasis> flag is used to set
                  the protection type required with the security mechanism. Can be set
                  to 'sig' or 'enc' to indicate signature or encryption. Defaults to
                  signature.</para></entry>
          </row>
          
          <row>
              <entry align="center">
                  <note><simpara>If you have a asterisk (*) in your command, you might have to
                      escape it with backslash.</simpara></note>
              </entry>
          </row>