<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd"
[

<!ENTITY % myents SYSTEM "../../entities">

%myents;

]>
<section>
<para>All CAS client programs use the following environment variables to

determine the appropriate URL to connect to and server identity to

expect. In all cases, the command line options takes precedence over

the environment variables.</para>

<itemizedlist>

  <listitem id="urlOption">

    <para>The URL is determined using this algorithm:

<itemizedlist>

        <listitem>

          <simpara>If the <option>-c</option> command line option was specified, the URL specified with that option is used.</simpara>

        </listitem>

        <listitem>

          <simpara>Otherwise, the <envar>CAS_SERVER_URL</envar> environment variable must be set, and its value is used.</simpara>

        </listitem>

      </itemizedlist></para>

  </listitem>

  <listitem><!-- no id if frag is used in more than on place: id="serverIdentity" -->

    <para>The server identity (i.e. the

expected subject name of the CAS server certificate) is determined as

follows:



<itemizedlist>

        <listitem>

          <simpara>If the <option>-s</option> command line option was specified, the value specified with that option is used as the identity</simpara>

        </listitem>

        <listitem>

          <simpara>Otherwise, if the <envar>CAS_SERVER_IDENTITY</envar> environment variable is set, the value of that variable is used as the expected server identity. Ensure that the value is enclosed within double quotes if there are spaces in the DN. <emphasis>The double quotes are required by the CAS scripts when they are run from a Windows shell, although the shell does not require it even if the value has spaces.</emphasis></simpara>

        </listitem>

        <listitem>

          <simpara>If neither is set, host authorization is done and the expected server credential is <replaceable>cas/&lt;fqdn&gt;</replaceable>, where &lt;fqdn&gt; is the fully qualified domain name of the host on which the CAS service is up.</simpara>

        </listitem>

      </itemizedlist></para>

  </listitem>

</itemizedlist>

</section>