<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<section><title>Configuration overview</title>

  <para>The CAS service can be configured with a description of the VO the

CAS service serves and the maximum lifetime of the assertions it can

issue. Also, the service needs to be configured with information about

the back end database it uses. Any database with a JDBC   driver and reasonable SQL support can be used. 

That said, PostgreSQL was used for development and testing  and we strongly recommend that you use it.  The CAS

database schema to be used with PostgreSQL has been provided in <emphasis>$GLOBUS_LOCATION/etc/globus_cas_service/casDbSchema/cas_pgsql_database_schema.sql</emphasis>. </para>

  <para>Other than that, the security  settings of the service can be

modified  in the security descriptor associated with the CAS service. It allows for configuring the

credentials that will be used by the service, the type of authentication

and message protection required as  well as the authorization mechanism. By default, the following

security configuration is installed:</para>

  <itemizedlist>

    <listitem>

      <simpara>Credentials are determined by the container level security descriptor. If there is no container level security descriptor or if it does not specify which credentials to use then default credentials are used. </simpara>

    </listitem>

    <listitem>

      <simpara>Authentication and message integrity protection is enforced for all methods except <emphasis role="italic">queryResourceProperties</emphasis> and <emphasis role="italic">getResourceProperty.</emphasis> This means that you may use any of GSI <glossterm linkend="transport-level-security">Transport</glossterm>, GSI Secure Message or GSI Secure Conversation when interacting with the CAS service.</simpara>

    </listitem>

    <listitem>

      <simpara>The standard authorization framework is not used for authorization. Instead the the service uses the back end database to determine if the call is permitted. </simpara>

    </listitem>

  </itemizedlist>

  <note>

    <para>Changing required authentication and authorization

methods will require  matching changes to the clients that contact this

service.

</para>

  </note>

 <important>
 <para> 
 If the service is configured to use GSI Secure Transport, then container credentials are used for the handshake, irrespective of whether service level credentials are specified.
 </para>
 </important>
</section>

<section><title>Syntax of the interface</title>
  
  <section><title>Loading the CAS service at start up</title>
    <para>By default, the CAS service is not loaded at start up. To change this behavior, uncomment the <emphasis>loadOnStartup</emphasis> 
      property set in <emphasis>$GLOBUS_LOCATION/etc/globus_cas_service/server-config.wsdd</emphasis> as shown below. </para>
      
    <para>Once the <emphasis>loadOnStartup</emphasis> property is uncommented, the following happens at start up:</para>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>The CAS service is loaded.</listitem>
      <listitem>The database connection pool is initialized.</listitem>
      <listitem>The service registers itself to the default MDS Index Service.<!--FIXME: add info about automagic MDS registration--></listitem> 
    </orderedlist>
       
    <screen>&lt;service name=&quot;CASService&quot; provider=&quot;Handler&quot; use=&quot;literal&quot; 
      
      style=&quot;document&quot;&gt;
      
      &lt;!-- Uncomment if the service needs to be initialized at startup --&gt;
      
      &lt;parameter name=&quot;loadOnStartup&quot; value=&quot;true&quot;/&gt;
      
      &lt;parameter name=&quot;allowedMethodsClass&quot; 
      
      value=&quot;org.globus.cas.CASPortType&quot;/&gt;
      
      .
      
      .
      
      .
      
      &lt;/service&gt;</screen>
    
  </section>
  
  <section>  <title>Changing the maximum assertion lifetime</title>
    <para>To change the maximum assertion lifetime and VO description, set the parameters <constant>maxAssertionLifetime</constant> 
    and <constant>voDescription</constant> in <filename>$GLOBUS_LOCATION/etc/globus_cas_service/jndi-config.xml</filename> to the desired values.</para>
  </section>
  
<section><title>Configuring database backend</title>
  <para>To alter the configuration of the database back end edit the <constant>databseConfiguration</constant> section of
    
    <filename>$GLOBUS_LOCATION/etc/globus_cas_service/jndi-config.xml</filename> as follows:</para>
  
  <table><title>Database parameters</title>
    
    <tgroup cols="2">
      
      <tbody>
        
        <row>
          
          <entry>driver </entry>
          
          <entry>The JDBC driver to be used</entry>
          
        </row>
        
        <row>
          
          <entry>connectionURL </entry>
          
          <entry>The JDBC connection url to be used when connecting to the database</entry>
          
        </row>
        
        <row>
          
          <entry>userName </entry>
          
          <entry>The user name to connect to the database as</entry>
          
        </row>
        
        <row>
          
          <entry>password </entry>
          
          <entry>The corresponding database password</entry>
          
        </row>
        
        <row>
          
          <entry>activeConnections </entry>
          
          <entry>The maximum number of active connections at any given instance </entry>
          
        </row>
        
        <row>
          
          <entry>onExhaustAction </entry>
          
          <entry>The action to perform when the connection pool is exhausted. If value is 0 then fail, if 1 then block and if 2 then grow the pool (get more connections)</entry>
          
        </row>
        
        <row>
          
          <entry>maxWait </entry>
          
          <entry>The maximum time in milliseconds that the pool will wait for a connection to be returned </entry>
          
        </row>
        
        <row>
          
          <entry>idleConnections </entry>
          
          <entry>The maximum number of idle connections at any given time</entry>
          
        </row>
        
      </tbody>
      
    </tgroup>
    
  </table>
  
</section>
  
  <section><title>Configuring security descriptor</title>
    
    <para>To alter the security descriptor configuration refer to 
      <ulink url="http://www-unix.globus.org/toolkit/docs/4.0/security/authzframe/security_descriptor.html">Security Descriptors</ulink>. 
      The file to be changed is <filename>$GLOBUS_LOCATION/etc/globus_cas_service/security-config.xml</filename>.</para>
    
    </section>

</section>

