<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd"
[

<!ENTITY % myents SYSTEM "../../entities">

%myents;

]>
<section>
        <section><title>Trigger Service Resource Properties</title>
            <para>In addition to the resource properties for the Aggregator Framework, the Trigger Service exposes the following:</para>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem><simpara><constant>TriggerName</constant> This resource property allows one to arbitrarily name the trigger.  This is used to assist one in managing many triggers.</simpara></listitem>
                <listitem><simpara><constant>TriggerStatus</constant> This resource property is used to indicate the current status of the trigger.  There are two states allowed: <constant>enabled</constant> and <constant>disabled</constant>.</simpara></listitem>
                <listitem><simpara><constant>MemberEPR</constant> This resource property reveals the monitored service that the trigger is associated with</simpara></listitem>
                <listitem><simpara><constant>TriggerID</constant> This resource property is a unique ID assigned to the trigger.</simpara></listitem>
                <listitem><simpara><constant>MatchingRule</constant> This resource property is the XPath expression that will be used in evaluating incoming aggregator data.  The trigger will fire (if enabled) if the expression is "true" (in a boolean sense).</simpara></listitem>
                <listitem><simpara><constant>NamespaceMappings</constant> This resource property allows one to use namespaces in the MatchingRule.</simpara></listitem>
                <listitem><simpara><constant>ActionScript</constant> This resource property is the name of the action script that should be fired when the trigger evaluation is "true".  The action script is located in the <computeroutput>$GLOBUS_LOCATION/libexec/trigger/</computeroutput> directory.</simpara></listitem>
                <listitem><simpara><constant>RuleLastCheckedAt</constant> This resource property reveals when the MatchingRule was last checked/evaluated.</simpara></listitem>
                <listitem><simpara><constant>ConditionTrueSince</constant> This resource property reports since when the MatchingRule evaluated against the incoming aggregator data results in <constant>true</constant></simpara></listitem>
                <listitem><simpara><constant>ActionFiredAt</constant> This resource property reveals exactly when the trigger was last fired.</simpara></listitem>
                <listitem><simpara><constant>EnableBoolean</constant> This resource property is by default <computeroutput>true</computeroutput>, meaning that it is set up to evaluate XPath queries as "true" or "false", firing only when "true".</simpara></listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </section>
</section>