<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="delegation-error-codes"><title>Error Messages</title>
 <indexterm type="delegation">
  <primary>errors</primary>
 </indexterm>
 
 <table frame='all' id="delegation-errors-table"><title>WS A&amp;A Delegation Service Error Messages</title>
<tgroup cols='3' align='left' colsep='1' rowsep='1'>
<colspec colname='c1' />
<colspec colname='c2' />
<colspec colname='c3' />
<thead>
<row>
  <entry>Error Code</entry>
  <entry>Definition</entry>
  <entry>Possible Solutions</entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody>
<row>
  <entry><code>AuthorizationException: &quot;test DN&quot; is not authorized to use operation: {http://www.globus.org/08/2004/delegationService}requestSecurityToken</code></entry>
  <entry>This exception can occur when  a client whose DN is not in the <glossterm>grid map file</glossterm> configured for the delegation 
    factory service attempts to delegate (using <olink targetdoc="delegationUser" targetptr="globus-credential-delegate">globus-credential-delegate</olink>) 
    a credential to the factory service.
    <note>
      <para>The <emphasis>test DN</emphasis> specified in the error message is just a  placeholder and will contain the DN of the user attempting to access the credential.</para>
    </note>
  </entry>
  <entry>
fixme
  </entry>
</row>
    <row>
  <entry><code>AuthorizationException: &quot;test DN&quot; is not authorized to use operation: {http://www.globus.org/08/2004/delegationService}refresh</code></entry>
  <entry>This exception can occur when a client attempts to refresh a credential it did not delegate (using globus-credential-refresh).

    <note>

      <para>The <emphasis>test DN</emphasis> specified in the error message is just a  placeholder and will contain the DN of the user attempting to access the credential.</para>

    </note></entry>
  <entry>
fixme
  </entry>
  </row>
  <row>
  <entry><code><replaceable>test user DN</replaceable>  is not authorized to access this resource</code></entry>
  <entry>Similar to above error but experienced by developers using the API - Only the user who created the delegated credential is allowed to access it. 
      There are two sets of API functions for getting the credential and registering listeners: 
      one in which the caller&apos;s DN is picked up from the current thread and 
      the other in which a JAAS subject (containing the caller&apos;s DN) is explicitly passed as a function parameter. 
      If the caller&apos;s DN (picked up from thread or specified explicitly)  does not match the DN of the user who created 
      the credential, this error is thrown. 
      
    <note>
      <para>The <emphasis>test DN</emphasis> specified in the error message is just a  placeholder and will contain the DN of the user attempting to access the credential.</para>
    </note>
  </entry>

  <entry>
Ensure that the DN explicitly specified or the client DN associated with the thread matches the creator&apos;s DN.
  </entry>
</row>
 <row>
  <entry><code>Unable to retrieve caller DN, cannot register</code></entry>
  <entry>Developers come across this error when attempting to register a listener with a delegated credential resource without a  JAAS subject. 
  There are two ways of registering: either the JAAS subject can be explicitly  passed using the API or the JAAS subject  can be picked up from 
the current message context (the subject representing the client). If the latter mechanism for  registering is used and there is no client 
credential associated with the thread that is calling the register function, then this exception is thrown. </entry>
  <entry>
Make sure to use the API call  that explicitly  passes the subject.
  </entry>
 </row>

 <!-- just copy the <row> block above for each row you need to add -->
</tbody>
</tgroup>
   </table>
 
</section>
