<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<para>The trigger service is an MDS aggregator service, and so inherits much of
  its configuration system from the <glossterm>Aggregator Framework</glossterm> module.  </para>
  
  <section><title>Configuring the Aggregator Framework</title>
    &WS_MDS_Aggregator_Interface_Config_Frag;
  </section>
  <section><!-- no ids in frags used more than once:  id="trigger-admin-config-additional" --><title>Additional configuration for the Trigger Service</title>
    <para>In addition to the source parameters specified
      above, the <computeroutput>TriggerRuleType</computeroutput> element  <emphasis>must</emphasis> be added to all registrations
      made to the trigger service. </para>
    <para>The <computeroutput>TriggerRuleType</computeroutput> is  defined in <ulink url=
      "http://viewcvs.globus.org/viewcvs.cgi/ws-mds/trigger/source/schema/mds/trigger/trigger-types.xsd?rev=1.2&amp;only_with_tag=globus_4_0_0&amp;content-type=text/vnd.viewcvs-markup">
      trigger-types.xsd</ulink> in <filename>trigger/source</filename>.</para>
    <para>This registration parameter contains the following options:</para>

    <itemizedlist>
    <listitem><simpara><computeroutput>matchingRule</computeroutput>: XPath rule to be applied against incoming data.
        The XPath expression will be evaluated against aggregated data, and will
        be regarded as matching the incoming data if it matches one or more nodes
        in that data.
    </simpara></listitem>

    <listitem><simpara><computeroutput>namespaceMappings</computeroutput>: 
        An array of string namespace mappings in the form xmlns:foo=http://foo.bar.  
        This array of namespace mappings will be used to resolve namespace 
        prefixes used in the XPath matchingRule statement.          
    </simpara></listitem>
        
    <listitem><simpara><computeroutput>evaluateBoolean</computeroutput>: 
        If this parameter is present and set to true the service will interpret a
boolean XPath query result as the trigger firing condition.  A return value of 
true indicates that the trigger action will be fired, a return value of false 
will cause the trigger action to be suppressed.  Note that other rate limiting 
parameters may still apply even if the query result is TRUE, and therefore trigger 
actions can still be suppressed even in those cases.
    </simpara></listitem>
        
                        
    <listitem><simpara><computeroutput>actionScript</computeroutput>: the logical name of a script that
        will be executed when the matchingRule matches (except as rate limited). 
        This logical name must be mapped to a physical file name located in the 
        <computeroutput>$GLOBUS_LOCATION/libexec/trigger/</computeroutput> directory.
        The logical-to-physical filename mapping is specified in the 
        <computeroutput>executableMappings</computeroutput> parameter of the 
        <computeroutput>triggerConfiguration</computeroutput> block of the file
        <computeroutput>$GLOBUS_LOCATION/etc/globus_wsrf_mds_trigger/jndi-config.xml</computeroutput>.
    </simpara></listitem>
  
    <listitem><simpara><computeroutput>minimumFiringInterval</computeroutput>: 
        the action script will not be executed more than once in this number of seconds. 
        If unspecified, there will be no minimum interval. 
    </simpara></listitem>
    
    <listitem><simpara><computeroutput>minimumMatchTime</computeroutput>: 
      the matchingRule must be true for this number of seconds before the 
      actionScript will be executed. If unspecified, there is no minimum time 
      period that the rule must match and the rule will be eligible to fire 
      immediately after the matchingRule becomes true. 
    </simpara></listitem>
    
    <listitem><simpara><computeroutput>invalidityTime</computeroutput>: 
        An array of TriggerInvalidityTime time ranges during which the trigger will 
        not fire under any condition.  If the current trigger fire time falls within any
        of the time ranges present in this variable, the trigger will not fire.
    </simpara></listitem>
    
    <listitem><simpara><computeroutput>enableFilteredActionScriptInput</computeroutput>: 
        If this value is present and set to true, the service will pass the filtered output result 
        of the XPath matchingRule as additional input to the stdin of the action script, 
        in addition to the original input to which the matching rule was applied.  
        The default behavior if unspecified is false, meaning the Xpath query result will 
        not be passed as input to the action script.
     </simpara></listitem>

    <listitem><simpara><computeroutput>disableUnmodifiedActionScriptInput</computeroutput>: 
        If this value is present and set to true the service will not pass the original 
        trigger message input (to which the matching rule was applied) to the action script.  
        The default behavior is to always pass the entire input message to the action scripts. 
        For action scripts which do not need to consume the unmodified input, this 
        variable may be set to true in order to increase performance. 
    </simpara></listitem>
    
    <listitem><simpara><computeroutput>outputXSL</computeroutput>: (CURRENTLY UNIMPLEMENTED) 
        The delivered message will be transformed by the specified XSLT stylesheet and fed into the
        stdin of the action script.  
    </simpara></listitem>                
  </itemizedlist>
          
<para>The rate limiting parameters behave in such a way that the rate of action
  script executions can be <emphasis>decreased</emphasis> by <emphasis>increasing</emphasis> the <computeroutput>minimumFiringInterval</computeroutput>  and/or by <emphasis>increasing</emphasis> the <computeroutput>minimumMatchTime</computeroutput>.</para>
  </section>
  <section><title>Example of a trigger registration file</title>
<para>A complete and working example of a trigger registration file can be viewed
at <computeroutput>$GLOBUS_LOCATION/etc/globus_wsrf_mds_trigger/trigger-aggregator-registration.xml</computeroutput></para>
</section>