<chapter>
	<title>Installing GT 4.0</title>

	<orderedlist>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				First, download the required software noted above.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				Be aware that Apache Ant will use the Java
				referred to by JAVA_HOME, <emphasis>not</emphasis> necessarily the
				first Java executable on your PATH. Be sure to
				set JAVA_HOME to the top-level directory of your
				Java installation before installing.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				If you want to build RLS, set GLOBUS_IODBC_PATH
				to point to the directory containing the IODBC
				driver. If you do not, the build of RLS will be
				skipped. You may finish the installation of RLS
				separately from the main build.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				Create a user named "globus". This
				non-privileged user will be used to
				perform administrative tasks such as
				starting and stopping the container,
				deploying services, etc. Make sure this
				account has read and write permissions
				in the $GLOBUS_LOCATION directory.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem><para>As the globus user, run:</para>
			<programlisting>
globus$ export GLOBUS_LOCATION=<replaceable>/usr/local/globus-3.9.4</replaceable>
globus$ ./configure --prefix=$GLOBUS_LOCATION
globus$ make
			</programlisting>
			<para>You can use command line arguments to ./configure for a more custom install:</para>
			<programlisting>
Optional Features:
--disable-FEATURE       do not include FEATURE (same as --enable-FEATURE=no)
--enable-FEATURE[=ARG]  include FEATURE [ARG=yes]
--disable-prewsgram     Don't build pre-webservices GRAM. Default is enabled.
--disable-gridftp       Don't build GridFTP. Default is enabled.
--disable-prewsmds      Don't build pre-webservices mds. Default is enabled.
--disable-rls           Don't build RLS. Default is enabled, but you must also specify an IODBC driver using --with-iodbc
--disable-wsjava        Don't build java webservices core. Default is enabled.
--disable-wsmds         Don't build webservices Monitoring and Discovery Services. Default is enabled.
--disable-wsdel         Don't build webservices delegation code. Default is enabled.
--disable-wsrft         Don't build webservices Reliable File Transfer.  Default is enabled.
--disable-wsgram        Don't build webservices GRAM. Default is enabled.
--enable-wsgram-condor  Build GRAM Condor scheduler interface. Default is disabled.
--enable-wsgram-lsf     Build GRAM LSF scheduler interface. Default is disabled.
--enable-wsgram-pbs     Build GRAM PBS scheduler interface. Default is disabled.
--enable-i18n           Enable internationalization. Default is disabled.
--disable-wscas         Don't build webservices Community Authorization Service. Default is enabled.
--disable-wsc           Don't build C webservices core. Default is enabled.
--disable-tests         Don't build C test packages. Default is enabled.
--disable-wstests       Don't build webservices test packages. Default is enabled.

Optional Packages:
--with-PACKAGE[=ARG]    use PACKAGE [ARG=yes]
--without-PACKAGE       do not use PACKAGE (same as --with-PACKAGE=no)
--with-flavor=flavor    Use flavor as the base for GPT builds.
--with-buildopts="args" Arguments to pass to gpt-build, like "--verbose" or "--force".
--with-iodbc=dir        Use the iodbc library in dir/lib/libiodbc.so.  Required for RLS builds.
			</programlisting>
		</listitem>

		<listitem><para>You may replace <replaceable>/usr/local/globus-3.9.4</replaceable> with whatever directory you wish
				to install to.</para></listitem>
	</orderedlist>
	<para><emphasis>Important:</emphasis> If for some reason you do <emphasis>not</emphasis> create
		a user named "globus", be sure to run the installation as a <emphasis>non-root</emphasis> user.</para>
</chapter>
