<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd"
[

<!ENTITY % myents SYSTEM "../../entities">

%myents;

]>
<section>
<para>Features new in GT &shortversion;:

<itemizedlist>

<listitem> 

<para><emphasis>Enhanced server-side attributed-based authorization framework:</emphasis> The server-side authorization framework has been reworked to support
attribute based authorization with delegation of rights. The framework
allows for configuring a chain of Policy Information Points(PIPs) and
Policy Decision Points(PDPs) and a combining alogorithm that 
processes the individual decisions returned by the PDPs. Some of the
key changes from the previous versions are:

<itemizedlist>

<listitem><para>Authorization framework uses a set of attributes to identify
entities </para></listitem>

<listitem><para>The authorization engine uses Java Security provider
framework to allow different combining algorithms to be plugged
in.</para></listitem>

<listitem><para>A default implementation of permit override combining algorithm,
which looks for a permit decision chain, to allow for fine grained
delegation of rights.</para></listitem>

</itemizedlist>

</para>

<para> Refer <olink targetdoc="authzframeDeveloper" targetptr="authzframe-developer-archdes"/> for
detailed information on the architecture.</para>

</listitem>

<listitem><para><emphasis>Host or Self Authoriation:</emphasis> Support for a pluggable PDP that does host authorization, and if that fails, tries self authorization. </para></listitem>

<listitem>
  <para> The security descriptor framework, used to configure security properties for the security framework has been enhanced. Detailed information about the framework is provided <olink targetdoc="wsaajava" targetptr="wsaajava-secdesc"/></para>
</listitem>


</itemizedlist>

</para>

<para>Other Supported Features

<itemizedlist>

    <listitem>

      <simpara>Authorization based on <filename>grid-mapfile</filename> and other access control lists.</simpara>

    </listitem>

    <listitem>

      <simpara>Ability to implement custom authorization modules.</simpara>

    </listitem>

    <listitem>

      <simpara>A SAML callout authorization module enables outsourcing of authorization decisions to an authorization service (e.g. PERMIS).</simpara>

    </listitem>


  </itemizedlist></para>

<para>Deprecated Features

<itemizedlist>

    <listitem>

      <simpara>None</simpara>

    </listitem>

  </itemizedlist>
</para>

</section>