<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<title>GT &shortversion; RLS : User's Guide</title>
<titleabbrev>User's Guide</titleabbrev>

<section id="rls-user-introduction"><title>Introduction</title>
<para>The Replica Location Service (RLS) maintains and provides access to mapping 
  information from <glossterm baseform="logical name">logical names</glossterm> for data items to <glossterm baseform="target name">target names</glossterm>. </para>
<para>RLS was co-developed by the Globus team and Work Package 2 of the DataGrid 
project. The RLS prototype is currently available as an alpha release for 
testing and evaluation. The distributed RLS is intended to replace the 
centralized Globus replica catalog available in earlier releases of GT2.x. The 
distributed RLS provides higher performance, reliability and scalability. </para>
<para>Replication of data items can reduce access latency, improve data locality, 
and increase robustness, scalability and performance for distributed 
applications. An RLS typically does not operate in isolation but functions as 
one component of a data grid architecture (other components include services 
that provide reliable file transfers, metadata management, reliable replication and workflow management).</para>
<para>The RLS implementation is based on the following mechanisms:</para>
<itemizedlist>
  <listitem><simpara><emphasis>Consistent local state maintained in <glossterm baseform="Local Replica Catalog (LRC)">Local Replica Catalogs (LRCs)</glossterm>.</emphasis> 
    Local catalogs maintain mappings between arbitrary <glossterm baseform="logical file name">logical file names (LFNs)</glossterm> 
    and the <glossterm baseform="physical file name">physical file names (PFNs)</glossterm> associated with those LFNs on its storage 
  system(s).
&nbsp;</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara><emphasis>Collective state with relaxed consistency maintained in Replica 
    Location Indices (RLIs).</emphasis> Each <glossterm baseform="Replica Location Index">RLI</glossterm> contains a set of mappings from LFNs to 
  LRCs. A variety of index structures can be defined with different performance 
  characteristics simply by varying the number of RLIs and the amount of redundancy and partitioning among the RLIs.
&nbsp;</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara><emphasis>Soft state maintenance of RLI state.</emphasis> LRCs send information about 
  their state to RLIs using soft state protocols. State information in RLIs 
  times out and must be periodically refreshed by soft state updates. 
&nbsp;</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara><emphasis>Compression of state updates.</emphasis> This optional compression uses 
    <glossterm baseform="Bloom filter">Bloom filters</glossterm> to summarize the content of a Local Replica Catalog before 
  sending a soft state update to a Replica Location Index Node. 
&nbsp;</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara><emphasis>Membership and partitioning information maintenance.</emphasis> The current 
  RLS implementation maintains static information about the LRCs and RLIs 
  participating in the distributed system. As new implementations of the RLS are 
  developed, they will use OGSA mechanisms for registration of services and for 
  service lifetime management. </simpara></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
</section>



<section id="rls-user-commandline"><title>Command line tools</title>
<para>Please see the <xref linkend="rls-commandline"/>.</para>
</section>

<section id="rls-user-gui"><title>Graphical user interfaces</title>
&RLS_Interface_GUI_Frag;
</section>

<section id="rls-user-troubleshooting"><title>Troubleshooting</title>
<para>Information on troubleshooting can be found in the
<ulink url="http://www.globus.org/toolkit/data/rls/rls_faq.html">FAQ</ulink>.</para>
</section>

<section id="rls-user-usage"><title>Usage statistics collection by the Globus Alliance</title>
  &RLS_Usage_Statistics_Frag;
</section>

