<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<title>GT &shortversion; WS GRAM : System Administrator's Guide</title>
<titleabbrev> System Administrator's Guide</titleabbrev>
 
<section id="wsgram-admin-introduction"><title>Introduction</title>

<para>This guide contains advanced configuration information
  for system administrators working with WS GRAM. It provides references to
  information on procedures typically performed by system administrators,
  including installation, configuring, deploying, and testing the
  installation. It also describes additional prerequisites and host settings
  necessary for WS GRAM operation. Readers should be familiar with the
  <link linkend="execution-key">Key Concepts</link> and
    <link linkend="execution-approach">Implementation Approach</link>
  for WS GRAM to understand the motivation for and interaction between the
  various deployed components.
</para>


  <important>
 <simpara> The information in this WS GRAM Admin Guide is in addition to the basic Globus Toolkit prerequisite, 
   overview, installation, security configuration instructions in the <xref linkend="gtadmin" />.  
    Read through this guide before continuing!</simpara>  
  </important>

</section>
<!-- introduction -->

<section id="wsgram-admin-installing"><title>Building and Installing</title>
  <para>WS GRAM is built and installed as part of
    a default GT &shortversion; installation. For basic installation instructions, see   <xref linkend="gtadmin"/>.</para>
  
<section id="wsgram-admin-installing-req" xreflabel="Prerequisites for installing WS GRAM"><title>Prerequisites</title>

<!-- transport level security -->
<section id="wsgram-admin-security"><title>Transport Level Security (TLS)</title>
<para>
  In order to use WS GRAM, the container must be started with Transport Level
  security.  The "-nosec" option should *not* be used with
  <computeroutput>globus-start-container</computeroutput>.
</para>
</section>

<!-- sudo -->
<section id="wsgram-admin-sudo"><title>Functioning sudo</title> <para>
  WS GRAM requires that the <glossterm baseform="superuser do">sudo</glossterm> command is
  installed and functioning on the service host where WS GRAM software will
  execute.
</para>
<para>
  Authorization rules will need to be added to the
  <computeroutput>sudoers</computeroutput> file to allow the WS GRAM service
  account to execute (without a password) the <glossterm>scheduler adapter</glossterm> in the
  accounts of authorized GRAM users.  For sudo configuration details, see the
    <link linkend="wsgram-admin-configuring">Configuring</link> section.
</para>
<para>
   Platform Note: On AIX, sudo is not installed by default, but it is available as source and rpm here: 
  <ulink url="http://www-1.ibm.com/servers/aix/products/aixos/linux/download.html">AIX 5L Toolbox for Linux Applications</ulink>
</para>
</section>

<!-- local scheduler -->
<section id="wsgram-admin-localscheduler"><title>Local Scheduler</title>
<para> 
  WS GRAM depends on a local mechanism for starting and controlling jobs.
  Included in the WS GRAM software is a Fork <glossterm>scheduler</glossterm>, which requires no
  special software installed to execute jobs on the local host.  However, to
  enable WS GRAM to execute and manage jobs to a <glossterm>batch scheduler</glossterm>, the scheduler
  software must be installed and configured prior to configuring WS GRAM.
</para>
</section>

<!-- scheduler adapters -->
<section id="wsgram-admin-schedulerAdpaters"><title>Scheduler Adapter</title>
  <para>  WS GRAM depends on scheduler adapters to translate the WS GRAM <glossterm>job description</glossterm>
  document into commands understood by the local scheduler, as well as monitor
  the jobs.</para>
  <para>
      Scheduler adapters included in the GT &shortversion; release are:
  <ulink url="http://www.openpbs.org/">PBS</ulink>,
  <ulink url="http://www.cs.wisc.edu/condor/">Condor</ulink>,
  <ulink url="http://www.platform.com/Products/Platform.LSF.Family/Platform.LSF/">LSF</ulink>
  </para>

  <para>
      Third party schedulers adapters available for GT &shortversion; are: <ulink url="http://www.lesc.ic.ac.uk/projects/SGE-GT4.html">Sun Grid Engine</ulink>
  </para>

  <para>
      For configuration details, see "Configuring scheduler adapters" in the
  <link linkend="wsgram-admin-configuring">Configuring</link> section.
  </para>

</section>

<!-- GridFTP -->
<section id="wsgram-admin-gridftp"><title>GridFTP</title>
<para> 
  Though staging directives are processed by RFT (see next section), RFT
  uses GridFTP servers underneath to do the actual data movement. As a
  result, <emphasis>there must be at least one GridFTP server that shares a
  file system with the execution nodes</emphasis>.  There is no special process
  to get staged files onto the execution node before the job executable is run.

    See the "Non-default GridFTP server" section of <xref linkend="wsgram-admin-configuring"/> for details on how to configure WS GRAM for your
  GridFTP servers used in your execution environment.
</para>
</section>

<!-- RFT -->
<section id="wsgram-admin-rft"><title>Reliable File Transfer Service (RFT)</title>
<para> 
  WS GRAM depends on RFT to perform file staging and cleanup directives in 
  a job description.  For configuration details, see <xref linkend="rft-admin"/>.

  <emphasis>Important:</emphasis> Jobs requesting these functions will fail if
  RFT is not properly setup.
</para>
</section>
  <!-- RFT -->

</section>
<!-- Installation Requirements -->
</section>
<section id="wsgram-admin-configuring" xreflabel="Configuring WS GRAM"><title>Configuring </title>
  &WS_GRAM_Interface_Config_Frag;
</section>

<section id="wsgram-admin-deploying"><title>Deploying </title>
  <para>WS GRAM is deployed as part of a standard toolkit installation. 
    Please refer to  the <xref linkend="gtadmin"/> for details.</para>

<section id="wsgram-admin-deploying-tomcat"><title>Deploying in Tomcat</title>
<para>WS GRAM has been tested to work without any additional setup steps
when deployed into Tomcat.  Please see <xref linkend="javawscore-admin-tomcat-deploying"/> for
instructions.  Also, for details on tested containers, see the
<xref linkend="wsgram-rn-testedplatforms"/>.</para>
<note><simpara>Currently only a single deployment is supported because of a
limitation in the execution of the Scheduler Event Generator.  One must set
GLOBUS_LOCATION before starting Tomcat.</simpara></note>

</section>

</section>

<section id="wsgram-admin-testing"><title>Testing</title>
	<para>See<xref linkend="wsgram-user-usagescenarios"/> for information about submitting a test job.</para>
</section>


<section id="wsgram-admin-security_considerations"><title>Security Considerations </title>
&WS_GRAM_Security_Considerations_Frag;
</section>

<section id="wsgram-admin-troubleshooting"><title>Troubleshooting</title>
&WS_GRAM_Troubleshooting_Frag;
</section>

<section id="wsgram-admin-usage"><title>Usage statistics collection by the Globus Alliance</title>
&WS_GRAM_Usage_Statistics_Frag;
</section>

<!--  LocalWords:  NOPASSWD
 -->
