<chapter id="c-cas">
	<title>Configuring CAS</title>
<section id="s-cas-introduction"><title>Introduction</title>
<para>This guide contains advanced configuration information for system
administrators working with the Community Authorization Service (CAS). It
provides references to information on procedures typically performed by
system administrators, including installation, configuring, deploying,
and testing the installation.</para>

<para><emphasis>Note:</emphasis> This document contains information
about deploying a CAS server and is not needed for a CAS client
installation. [expand on this a little more] </para>
<para>This is a partially-complete docbook translation of
        <ulink url="http://www.globus.org/toolkit/docs/development/3.9.5/security/cas/admin/index.html">the CAS Admin Guide</ulink>.
        Please see that document for additional information.
</para>

</section>

<section id="s-cas-configuring"><title>Configuring </title>
<para>
	PHP Include
</para>
</section>
<section id="s-cas-deploying"><title>Deploying</title>

<para> 
The following steps are needed to deploy the CAS service.</para>

<itemizedlist>
  <listitem><simpara><link linkend="s-cas-casCreds">Obtaining credentials for the CAS server</link></simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara> <link linkend="s-cas-dbInstall">Database installation and configuration</link></simpara></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
<section id="s-cas-casCreds"><title>Obtaining credentials for the CAS server</title>
<para> The CAS service could run with its own set of credentials. Instructions to
  obtain service credentials may be found <ulink
    url="http://www.globus.org/toolkit/docs/2.4/admin/guide-verify.html#ldapcert">here</ulink>.
</para>
  
<para> The standard administrator clients that come with the distribution can be
  used to perform host authorization and expect that the CAS service have credentials
  that have service name "cas". The command in the above mentioned <ulink url="http://www.globus.org/toolkit/docs/2.4/admin/guide-verify.html#ldapcert">web
  page</ulink> may be altered as follows:
</para>
<screen>  casadmin$ grid-cert-request -service <emphasis>cas</emphasis> -host <emphasis>FQDN</emphasis></screen>
<para> The certificate and private key are typically placed in <emphasis>/etc/grid-security/cas-cert.pem</emphasis> and <emphasis>/etc/grid-security/cas-key.pem</emphasis>,
  respectively. In this document, the location of certificate and key files is
  referred to as CAS_CERT_FILE and CAS_KEY_FILE, respectively.
  </para>
</section>
<section id="s-cas-dbInstall"><title>Database installation and configuration </title>
	<para>
CAS uses a backend database to store all user data. Any JDBC compliant database
may be used. This section describes briefly the <link linkend="installingdb">installation
of such a database</link>and the <link linkend="initializingCASdb">creation of the database</link> using schema required for the CAS backend.
</para>
</section>
<section id="installingdb"><title>Installing the database </title>
<para>
Any JDBC compliant database may be used. PostgreSQL has been used for development
and testing. The drivers for the same are included in the distribution. If a
different database is used, the corresponding driver should be added to GLOBUS_LOCATION/lib.
</para>
<para> Brief instructions to install a JDBC compliant database and specifically
  PostGres can be found <ulink
url="http://www.globus.org/toolkit/3.0/ogsa/docs/admin/installation.html">here</ulink>.
  For more detailed instructions, please refer to specific database documentation.
  </para> 
</section>
<section id="initializingCASdb"><title>Initializing the CAS database </title>
<para> The schema of the database that needs to be created for CAS can be found
  at <filename> $GLOBUS_LOCATION/globus_cas_service/casDbSchema/cas_pgsql_database_schema.sql</filename></para>
<para> To create a database, for example <emphasis>casDatabase</emphasis>, on a PostgreSQL, install
  on local machine:</para>
<screen>casadmin$ createdb casDatabase  
casadmin$ psql -U casadmin -d casDatabase -f  \
          $GLOBUS_LOCATION/globus_cas_service/casDbSchema/cas_pgsql_database_schema.sql</screen>
<para> You will see a list of notices on the screen. Unless any of them say "ERROR",
  these are just output for information.</para>
<para>Information about the database needs to be configured as described <ulink url="http://www.globus.org/toolkit/docs/development/3.9.5/security/cas/WS_AA_CAS_Public_Interfaces.html#config">here</ulink> for
  the CAS service to be able to use it.</para>
</section>
</section>

<section id="s-cas-testing"><title>Testing</title>
<para> CAS has two sets of tests, one for the backend database access module and
  another set to test the service itself. To install both tests, install the
  CAS test package (<emphasis>gt4-cas-delegation-test-3.9-src_bundle.tar.gz</emphasis>) using
  GPT <emphasis>FILLME: instructions </emphasis> into <emphasis>GLOBUS_LOCATION</emphasis>.</para>
<para> It is assumed that:</para>
<itemizedlist>
  <listitem><simpara> a backend database has been set up and configured</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara> CAS service and tests are installed in <emphasis>$GLOBUS_LOCATION</emphasis></simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara> the service is running on localhost and port 8080 (for the sample commands)</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><para>the database is set up with:
      <orderedlist>
        <listitem><simpara> username as <emphasis>tester</emphasis></simpara></listitem>
        <listitem><simpara> database name as <emphasis>casDatabase</emphasis></simpara></listitem>
        <listitem><simpara> host as <emphasis>foo.bar.gov</emphasis> and default port.</simpara></listitem>
      </orderedlist>
  </para></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
</section>

<section><title> Testing the backend database module </title>
<orderedlist>
  <listitem><para>Run:
      <screen> cd $GLOBUS_LOCATION </screen>
  </para></listitem>
  <listitem><para> Populate the file <emphasis>etc/globus_cas_unit_test/casTestProperties</emphasis> with
    the following database configuration information:
        
        <table id="testDbConfig">
		<title>TITLE</title>
		<tgroup cols="2"><tbody>
          <row>
            <entry>dbDriver </entry>
            <entry> The JDBC driver to be used</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>dbConnectionURL </entry>
            <entry> JDBC connection url to be used to connect to database</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>dbUsername </entry>
            <entry> user name to connect to database as</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>dbPassword </entry>
            <entry> database password for the said username </entry>
          </row>
        </tbody></tgroup>
</table>
        
  </para></listitem>
  <listitem><para> The database needs to be empty for these tests to work. To delete all
    the data in the database, run:
      <screen>psql -d casDatabase -U tester -h foo.bar.gov -f etc/globus_cas_utils/database_delete.sql </screen>
  </para></listitem>
  <listitem><para> Run:
      <screen>ant -f share/globus_cas_unit_test/cas-test-build.xml testDatabase </screen>
  </para></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara> Test reports are placed in $GLOBUS_LOCATION/share/globus_cas_unit_test/cas-test-reports.</simpara></listitem>
</orderedlist>
</section>
<section><title> Testing CAS service module </title>
<para> These tests can be set up so as to be able to test multiple user scenario
  or it can be configured to run just as a single identity. The first set of
  tests are used to test admin functionality and sets up the database for second
  user. As the second user the permissions and queries are tested to ensure that
  the set up worked.</para>
<para> All the configuraiton information for the test, needs to be configured in <emphasis>etc/globus_cas_unit_test/casTestProperties</emphasis> file.
  The database section of the properties file needs to be configured as described <ulink
url="testDbConfig">here</ulink>. Other than those, the following properties also
  need to be configured for these tests:</para>
<table>
	<title>TITLE</title>
<tgroup cols="2">
<tbody>
  <row>
    <entry>user1SubjectDN</entry>
    <entry> The DN of the user running the first set of tests.</entry>
  </row>
  <row>
    <entry>user2SubjectDN</entry>
    <entry> The DN of the user running the second set of tests. Can be the same
      as previous property</entry>
  </row>
  <row>
    <entry>maxAssertionLifetime</entry>
    <entry> Should match the value set in service configuration as shown in 
	    <ulink url="http://www.globus.org/toolkit/docs/development/3.9.5/security/cas/WS_AA_CAS_Public_Interfaces.html#config">Configuration information</ulink></entry>
  </row>
</tbody></tgroup>
</table>
<para> Steps for testing:</para>
<orderedlist>
  <listitem><para>Run:
      <screen> cd $GLOBUS_LOCATION                </screen>
      </para></listitem>
  <listitem><para> The database needs to be empty for these tests to work. To delete all
    the data in the database, run:
      <screen>psql -d casDatabase -U tester -h foo.bar.gov -f etc/globus_cas_utils/database_delete.sql </screen>
      </para></listitem>
  <listitem><para> In the test properties file, set <emphasis>user2SubjectDN</emphasis> to be the subject
    in your regular proxy. The following returns the appropriate string:
      <screen>casadmin$ bin\grid-cert-info -subject -globus</screen>
      </para></listitem>
  <listitem><para> Generate an independent proxy using the following command:
      <screen>casadmin$ bin\grid-proxy-init -independent</screen>
      </para></listitem>
  <listitem><para> Set the identity in the proxy generated from the above step as <emphasis>user1SubjectDN</emphasis> in
    the test properties file. The following command will return the relevant
    string:
      <screen>casadmin$ java org.globus.tools.ProxyInfo -subject -globus</screen>
      </para></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara> Start a container on port (for example, testPort) and host (for example,
    hostPort).
    </simpara></listitem>
                  
<listitem><para> The following command runs tests for self permissions and sets up the database
  for user with subjectDN that is user2SubjectDN:
        <screen>casadmin$ ant -f share/globus_cas_unit_test/cas-test-build.xml -Dtest.port=testPort \
            -Dtest.host=testHost user1TestService</screen>
    </para></listitem>
  <listitem><para> To test as the second user, generate proxy for the subject DN specified
      for the second user:
        <screen>casadmin$ bin/grid-proxy-init </screen>
  </para></listitem>
    <listitem><para> To test as second user, run the following. If you are not running container
      on default host/port, set properties as shown <ulink url="#testParams">here.</ulink>
        <screen>casadmin$ ant -f share/globus_cas_unit_test/cas-test-build.xml -Dtest.port=testPort \
		-Dtest.host=testHost user2TestService</screen></para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem><simpara> Test reports are placed in $GLOBUS_LOCATION/share/globus_cas_unit_test/cas-test-reports.</simpara></listitem>
    <listitem><para>After these tests, the CAS database needs to be reset. The following
      command will delete all entries from the database:
        <screen> casadmin$ psql -U casadmin -d casDatabase -f GLOBUS_LOCATION/share/cas/database_delete.sql</screen>
    </para></listitem>
</orderedlist>
</section>
<section id="s-cas-admin-example"><title>Example of CAS Server Administration </title>
	<para>
The following contains an example of administering the CAS server policies using
the CAS administrative clients described <ulink url="http://www.globus.org/toolkit/docs/development/3.9.5/security/cas/WS_AA_CAS_Public_Interfaces.html#cmd">here</ulink>.
</para>
<para> Alice, Bob and Carol are three members of a community who have set up a Community
  Authorization service:
<itemizedlist>
  <listitem><simpara> Alice's role is primarily to administer the CAS server. </simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara>Bob is an analyst who needs read access to much of the community data. </simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara>Carol is a scientist who needs to be able to both read and write community
    data. </simpara></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
  </para>
<para>These examples show how:
<orderedlist>
  <listitem><simpara> Alice adds the users Bob and Carol to the CAS server</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara>Adds a FTP server with some data available to the community</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara>Adds permissions for the users using the CAS administration clients. </simpara></listitem>
</orderedlist>
</para>
<para>These examples assume the following:
<itemizedlist>
  <listitem><simpara> Alice has installed the CAS server and bootstrapped the database with
    herself as super user. Please refer to <ulink
url="./installGuide.html">installation documentation</ulink> for details. </simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara> Alice's nickname on the CAS server is <emphasis>alice</emphasis> and at bootstrap she
    has created a user group, <emphasis>suGroup</emphasis>,which has super user permissions
    on the database. </simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara>The CAS service URL is http://localhost:8080/ogsa/services/base/cas/CASService. </simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara> For all commands listed below, the enviroment variable, GLOBUS_LOCATION,
    has been set to point to the GT core install and the commands are run from
    GLOBUS_LOCATION/bin.</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara>An environment variable, CAS_SERVER_URL, has been set to point to the CAS
    server URL, http://localhost:8080/ogsa/services/base/cas/CASService. </simpara></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
</para>
<section><title> 1. Adding a user group </title>
<para> Since at the time of booting up the CAS server, only one user group that
  has super user permissions on the CAS server is created, Alice might want to
  create another user group to which new users maybe added and permissions to
  newly enrolled CAS entities may be given. This also eases the process of giving
  same rights to many users.Given they are two types of roles in the community
  she might want to create two groups, <emphasis>analysts</emphasis> and <emphasis>scientists</emphasis>.
  </para>
  

<para>Also, all permissions on the newly created group will be given to users of
  a particular user group. Say, Alice would like all users of the user group <emphasis>analysts</emphasis> to
  be able to manipulate the group.
  </para>
  
<para>To create a new user group Alice uses the <emphasis>cas-group-admin</emphasis> client.It
  requires a name for the new group being created, say <emphasis>analysts</emphasis>. 
  </para>
  
<screen>
alice%  cas-group-admin user create analysts analysts</screen>
<para>This will create a user group <emphasis>analysts</emphasis> and give all users in that group
  the permission to manage the group (i.e add users, remove users and so on).
  She can similarly create a group called <emphasis>scientist</emphasis> </para>
</section>
<section><title> 2. Adding a trust anchor</title>
<para> Prior to adding Bob and Carol to CAS server, Alice needs to ensure that the
  trust anchors for both have been added. If they share the same trust anchor
  with Alice then this step can be skipped, since at bootstrap Alice's trust
  anchor would have been added to the database. 
  </para>
  
<para>In our example, Alice and Carol share a trust anchor different from Bob's.
  Therefore, Alice needs to add Bob's trust anchor by using <emphasis>cas-enroll</emphasis> client
  with the <emphasis>trustAnchor</emphasis> option. She needs to provide details about the
  trust anchor such as the authentication method and authentication data used.
  </para>
  
<screen>
alice%  cas-enroll trustAnchor analysts AbcTrust X509 "/C=US/O=some/CN=ABC CA"
</screen>
<para>
The above will enroll a trust anchor with nickname <emphasis>AbcTrust</emphasis>, who uses <emphasis>X509</emphasis> as
authentication method and has the DN specified in the command. The members of
the <emphasis>analysts</emphasis> user group are given all rights on this object. This implies
that any user who has this trust anchor, would present credentials signed by
this trust anchor.
</para>
</section>
<section><title> <emphasis>3. Adding users</emphasis></title>
<para> Now, Alice can add Bob and Carol as users using the <emphasis>cas-enroll</emphasis> command
  with the <emphasis>user</emphasis> option. She needs to provide the user's subject DN and
  a reference to the trust anchor used by the user. As with any entity added
  to the CAS server, the admin needs to choose a user group whose members will
  have all permissions on that entity. In this example, Alice would like the
  members of user group <emphasis>suUser</emphasis> to be able to maninipulate the user entity <emphasis>Bob</emphasis>.
  </para>
  
<screen>
alice% cas-enroll user suUser bob "/O=Our Community/CN=Bob Foo" AbcTrust
</screen>
<para>
Alice uses a simliar command to add Carol to the CAS database.
</para>
</section>
<section><title> <emphasis>4. Adding users to a user group</emphasis></title>
<para>CAS server allows rights to be assigned only to user groups and not to individual
  users. Hence before Alice can assign rights to Bob or Carol, she needs to add
  them to some user group. She does this by using <emphasis>cas-group-add-entry</emphasis> client
  with the <emphasis>user</emphasis> option to indicate she is adding to a user group. This
  client requires the group name and nick name of the user who needs to be added.
  To add Bob to the <emphasis>analysts</emphasis> group, the command would be:
  </para>
<screen>
alice% cas-group-add-entry user analysts bob
</screen>
<para>If a user group <emphasis>scientists</emphasis> was created, Carol could similarly be added
  as a member.
  </para>

</section>
<section><title> <emphasis>4. Adding a new FTP server</emphasis></title>
<para>Alice now has the community users in the database and organized. She now wants
  to add some resources. Because the community currently has a single FTP server,
  foo.bar.edu, available to it, she will add this to the CAS database.
  </para>
  
<para>Each resource or object in the CAS server has a namespace associated to it
  that defines certain features. For example, it can define the comparison algorithm
  that needs to be used when this object name is used for comparison. It may
  also define the base URL that should be prefixed to objects that belong to
  this namespace. In this case, Alice chooses to use the <emphasis>FTPDirectoryTree</emphasis> namespace
  that is added to the CAS server at bootup. She uses the <emphasis>cas-enroll</emphasis> client
  with the <emphasis>object</emphasis> option to add the FTP server to the CAS database:
  </para>
<screen>
alice% cas-enroll object suGroup ftp://foo.bar.edu/* FTPDirectoryTree</screen>
<para>
This command adds the FTP server as an object and gives all members of the <emphasis>suGroup</emphasis> rights
to manipulate the object.
</para>
<para> To be able to grant/revoke access on an indiviual directory, add an object
  for the directory. For example, if Alice would like to be able to manipulate
  the <emphasis>data</emphasis> on the server as a separate entity, the following command will
  add an object for that.
  </para>
  
<screen>
alice% cas-enroll object suGroup ftp://foo.bar.edu/data/* FTPDirectoryTree
</screen>
</section>
<section><title> 4. Creating an object group </title>
<para> Alice suspects the community will end up with more directories containing
  data on other servers that will have identical polices as the /data directory
  on foo.bar.edu. So she is going to create an object group called <emphasis>data</emphasis> and
  assign foo.bar.edu/data to this group. This will allow her to grant rights
  on this group and easily add other directories to this group later.
  </para>
<para>To create a group called <emphasis>data</emphasis>, she uses the <emphasis>cas-group-admin</emphasis> client
  with the <emphasis>group</emphasis> and <emphasis>create</emphasis> options:
  </para>
<screen>
alice% cas-group-admin object create suGroup data</screen>
<para>
This creates an object group called <emphasis>data</emphasis> and the members of <emphasis>suGroup</emphasis> get
all rights on this group and hence should be able to add/remove members, grant
rights to add/delete from this group to others and also delete this group.
</para>
</section>
<section><title> <emphasis>5. Adding members to an object group </emphasis></title>
<para> Alice now can add foo.bar.edu/data to the <emphasis>data</emphasis> group. She can do this
  by using the <emphasis>cas-group-add-entry</emphasis> with the <emphasis>object</emphasis> option. To add
  the above described object, <emphasis>ftp://foo.bar.edu/data/*</emphasis> in namespace <emphasis>FooFTPNamespace</emphasis>,
  to object group <emphasis>data</emphasis>, Alice uses the following command:
  </para>
<screen>
alice% cas-group-add-entry object data object FooFTPNamespace ftp://foo.bar.edu/data/*
</screen>
<para>In the above command:</para>
<itemizedlist>
  <listitem><simpara>the first <emphasis>object</emphasis> refers to the group type.</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara><emphasis>data</emphasis> is the name of the object group.</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara>the second <emphasis>object</emphasis> refers to the type of CAS entity that is being
    added as a member.</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara> the last two parameters define the namespace and the object that needs
    to be added. </simpara></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
</section>
<section><title> 6. Adding service types </title>
<para> Alice now needs to add information about the kinds of rights that can be
  granteD for these objects. These are stored as <emphasis>service types</emphasis> and relevant
  actions are mapped to these service types.</para>
<para>In this scenario, the kind of service types that Alice should add would be <emphasis>file</emphasis>, <emphasis>directory</emphasis> and
  so on. To do so, the <emphasis>cas-enroll</emphasis> client with <emphasis>serviceType</emphasis> option
  may be used. To add a service type called <emphasis>file</emphasis> and give members of <emphasis>suGroup</emphasis> all
  rights on this service type, Alice uses the following command.</para>
<screen>
alice% cas-enroll serviceType suGroup file
</screen>
</section>
<section><title> 7. Adding action mappings</title>
<para> The relevant action mappings to the above mentioned service types would be <emphasis>read</emphasis>, <emphasis>write</emphasis> and
  so on. Alice needs to add these mappings to the database so that she can grant
  rights that allow a user to have <emphasis>file/read</emphasis> or <emphasis>file/write</emphasis> permissions
  on some object.
  </para> 

<para> To add action mappings to a service type, she uses the <emphasis>cas-action</emphasis> client
  with <emphasis>add</emphasis> option. The following command should add a mapping of action <emphasis>read</emphasis> to
  service type <emphasis>file</emphasis>.
  </para>
  
<screen>
alice% cas-action add file add
</screen>
<para>
Similarly, she can add other mappings, like <emphasis>write</emphasis>, to this service type.
</para>
</section>
<section><title> <emphasis>8. Granting permissions</emphasis></title>
<para> Alice now has resources in the object group <emphasis>data</emphasis> and users in the
  user groups <emphasis>analysts</emphasis> and <emphasis>scientists</emphasis>. She now wants to grant permissions
  on <emphasis>data</emphasis> group to the analysts and scientists, namely read permissions
  to the analysts and read and write permissions to the scientists.
  </para>
  

<para> To grant permissions, Alice needs to use the <emphasis>cas-rights-admin</emphasis> with
  the <emphasis>grant</emphasis> option. To give read permissions to the analysts group, Alice
  runs: 
  </para>
<screen>
alice% cas-rights-admin grant analysts objectGroup data serviceAction file read</screen>
<para>
She similarly grants rights to <emphasis>scientists</emphasis> group.
</para>
</section>
</section>
<section id="s-cas-security_considerations"><title>Security Considerations </title>

	<para>import</para>

</section>

</chapter>
