<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<para>Security tools are concerned with establishing the identity of users or services
  (authentication), protecting communications, and determining who is allowed
  to perform what actions (authorization), as well as with supporting functions
  such as managing user credentials and maintaining group membership information.</para>
<para>GT4 provides distinct WS and pre-WS authentication and authorization capabilities.
  Both build on the same base, namely standard X.509 end entity certificates
  and <glossterm linkend="proxy-cert">proxy certificates</glossterm>, which are used to identify persistent entities such
  as users and servers and to support the temporary delegation of privileges
  to other entities.</para>
  <para>For more information about the security concepts behind GT4, see <link linkend="security-key">Security: Key Concepts</link>. </para>
  <para>For a comparison of features between Java and C code, see  <link linkend="security-features">Security Features</link>.</para>
<para>GT4&rsquo;s WS security includes:</para>
<itemizedlist>
  <listitem> <simpara><link linkend="message">Message-level Security</link> mechanisms,
      which implement the WS-Security standard and the WS-SecureConversation
    specification to provide message protection for GT4&rsquo;s SOAP messages</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara><link linkend="message">Transport-level Security</link> mechanisms, which use transport-level security (TLS)
    mechanisms; and</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara>an <link linkend="authzframe">Authorization Framework</link> that allows for a variety of authorization
      schemes, including a &ldquo;grid-mapfile&rdquo; access control list, an
      access control list defined by a service, a custom authorization handler,
    and access to an authorization service via the SAML protocol.</simpara></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
<para>For non-WS components, GT4
    provides similar authentication, delegation, and authorization mechanisms,
  although with fewer authorization options. See the following components for more information:</para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem><simpara><link linkend="cas">Community Authorization Service (CAS)</link></simpara></listitem>
    <listitem><simpara><link linkend="delegation">Delegation Service</link></simpara></listitem>
     <listitem><para>Credential Management 
           <itemizedlist>
              <listitem><simpara><link linkend="myproxy">MyProxy</link></simpara></listitem>
               <listitem><simpara><link linkend="simpleca">SimpleCA</link></simpara></listitem>
            </itemizedlist></para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem> <para>Utilities <itemizedlist>
      <listitem><simpara><link linkend="openssh">GSI-OpenSSH</link></simpara></listitem>
    </itemizedlist></para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem><simpara><link linkend="prewsaa">Pre-WS Authentication &amp; Authorization</link></simpara></listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>TODO: add blurb about SGAS (SweGrid Accounting System)</para>