<section><title>Configuration overview</title>

<para>The CAS service can be configured with a description of the VO the
CAS service serves and the maximum lifetime of the assertion it can
issue. Also, the service needs to be configured with information about
the backend database it uses. Any JDBC compliant database can be used,
PostGres was used for development and testing. The database needs to
be set up such that it can receive requests over TCP/IP. The CAS
database schema to be used with PoseGres has been provided in
<emphasis>$GLOBUS_LOCATION/etc/globus_cas_utils/casDbSchema/cas_pgsql_database_schema.sql</emphasis>. </para>

<para>Other than that, the security configuration of the service can be
modifying the security descriptor. It allows for configuring in the
credentials that will be used by the service, type of authentication
and authorization that needs to be enforced.By default, the following
security configuration is installed:</para>
<itemizedlist>
<listitem><simpara> Credentials set for use by container is used. If that is not
specified, default credentials are used.
</simpara></listitem>
<listitem><simpara> GSI Secure conversation authentication is enforced for
all meethods
</simpara></listitem>
<listitem><simpara> The security framework is not used for authorization, but the the
service uses the backend database to determine if the call is
permitted.
</simpara></listitem>
</itemizedlist>

<note><para>Changing required authentication and authorization
method will require suitable changes to the clients that contact this
service.
</para></note>

</section>
<section><title>Syntax of the interface</title>
	<para>
<itemizedlist>
<listitem><simpara> To change the maximum assertion lifetime and VO description, set
the parameters <constant>maxAssertionLifetime</constant> and <constant>voDescription</constant> in
<filename>$GLOBUS_LOCATION/globus_cas_service/jndi-config.xml</filename> to required
values.
</simpara></listitem>

<listitem><para> To alter the configuration of database backend, edit
<constant>databseConfiguration</constant> section of
<filename>$GLOBUS_LOCATION/globus_cas_service/jndi-config.xml</filename> as follows:
</para>

<table>
	<title>TITLE</title>
	<tgroup cols="2"><tbody>
<row><entry>driver </entry><entry> The JDBC driver to be used</entry></row>
<row><entry>connectionURL </entry><entry> JDBC connection url to be used to connect to database</entry></row>
<row><entry>userName </entry><entry> user name to connect to database as</entry></row>
<row><entry>password </entry><entry> database password for the said username </entry></row>
<row><entry>activeConnections </entry><entry> Maximum number of active connections at any given instance </entry></row>
<row><entry>onExhaustAction </entry><entry> Action to perform when pool is exhausted. If value is, 0 - fail, 1 - block, 2 - grow (get more connections)</entry></row>
<row><entry>maxWait </entry><entry> Maximum time in milliseconds pool will wait for a connection to be returned </entry></row>
<row><entry>idleConnections </entry><entry> Maximum number of idle connections at any given instance  </entry></row>
</tbody></tgroup>
</table>
</listitem>

<listitem><simpara>To alter security descriptor configuration refer to <ulink
url="http://www-unix.globus.org/toolkit/docs/development/3.9.5/security/authzframe/security_descriptor.html">Security
Descriptors</ulink>. The file to be altered is
<filename>$GLOBUS_LOCATION/globus_cas_service/security-config.xml</filename>
</simpara></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
</para>
</section>
