<para>The Monitoring and Discovery System (MDS) is a suite of web services to monitor and discover resources and 
  services on Grids. This system allows users to discover what resources are considered part of a Virtual Organization (VO) 
  and to monitor those resources. MDS services provide query and subscription interfaces to arbitrarily detailed resource data 
  and a trigger interface that can be configured to take action when pre-configured trouble conditions are met.</para>
  
  <para>For more information about the information services concepts behind GT4, see <link linkend="r-info-key">Information Service: Key Concepts</link>. </para>
  
<para>GT4&rsquo;s MDS includes:</para>
<itemizedlist>
<listitem>  WS MDS, the WSRF implementation of MDS, which consists of:
<itemizedlist>
  <listitem> <simpara><ulink url="index/index.html">Index Service</ulink> [<ulink url="index/index.pdf">pdf</ulink>], which collects monitoring and discovery information from 
    Grid resources, and publishes it in a single location.</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara><ulink url="trigger/index.html">Trigger Service</ulink> [<ulink url="trigger/index.pdf">pdf</ulink>], which collects data from resources on the grid and, 
    if administrator defined rules match, can perform various actions.</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara><ulink url="aggregator/index.html">Aggregator Framework</ulink> [<ulink url="aggregator/index.pdf">pdf</ulink>], the software framework on which the 
    above WS MDS services are built.</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara><ulink url="webmds/index.html">WebMDS</ulink> [<ulink url="webmds/index.pdf">pdf</ulink>], which enables end users to view monitoring information via 
    a standard web browser interface, without installing any additional software on their PC.</simpara></listitem>
</itemizedlist></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara><ulink url="prewsmds/index.html">Pre-WS MDS</ulink> [<ulink url="prewsmds/index.pdf">pdf</ulink>] (which is now deprecated), the MDS implementation first introduced 
    in GT2.</simpara></listitem>
</itemizedlist>