<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd"
[

<!ENTITY % xinclude SYSTEM "../../../xinclude.mod" >
%xinclude;

]>

<book id="rftUser">
<title>GT <replaceable role="entity">version</replaceable> Reliable File Transfer (RFT) Service: User's Guide</title>
<titleabbrev>User's Guide</titleabbrev>

<bookinfo><abstract><title>Introduction</title>
<para>RFT Service implementation
  in GT <replaceable role="entity">version</replaceable> uses
standard SOAP messages over HTTP to submit and manage a set of 3rd
party GridFTP transfers and to delete files using GridFTP. The user
creates a RFT resource by submitting a list of URL pairs of&nbsp; files
that need to be transferred/deleted&nbsp; to RFT Factory service. The
user also specifies the time to live for the resource the user is
  creating to a GT <replaceable role="entity">version</replaceable> Container in which RFT is deployed and configured.
The resource is created after the user is properly authorized and
authenticated. RFT service implementation exposes operations to control
and manage the transfers (the resource). The operations exposed by both
RFT factory and RFT service are briefly described below. The resource
the user created also exposes the state of the transfer as a resource
property to which the user can either subscribe for changes or poll for
the changes in state periodically using standard command line clients.</para>
</abstract></bookinfo>
  
  <chapter id="rft-user-using"><title>Using RFT</title>
    <para>[TBD explain how end users are expected to use this - go through simple commands (for v simple xfers) and then point to more advanced instructions in dev guide)</para>
  </chapter>

  <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
    href="../RFT_Interface_Commandline_Frag.xml"/>

<!-- n/a 
<chapter id="rft-user-gui"><title>Graphical user interfaces</title>
  <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
    href="../RFT_Interface_GUI_Frag.xml"/>
</chapter>
  -->
<chapter id="rft-user-troubleshooting"><title>Troubleshooting</title>
  <indexterm type="rft-howto"><primary>troubleshooting</primary><secondary>(for end-users)</secondary></indexterm>
<section><title>Troubleshooting tips</title>
  <itemizedlist>
  <listitem><simpara>Always have a valid proxy before using command line
  RFT clients.</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara>Make sure to provide suitable options to the client, and especially for the Termination time, so that the resource does not get destroyed
before finishing the transfers.
  </simpara></listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
</section>
  <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
    href="../RFT_Recovery_Frag.xml"/>
</chapter>

<chapter id="rft-user-usage"><title>Usage statistics collection by the Globus Alliance </title>
  <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
    href="../RFT_Usage_Statistics_Frag.xml"/>
</chapter>

</book>