<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<title>GT &shortversion; OGSA-DAI: Developer's Guide</title>
<titleabbrev>Developer's Guide</titleabbrev>


<section id="ogsadai-developer-introduction"><title>Introduction</title>
<para>
  This guide contains information of interest to developers working with OGSA-DAI. 
  It provides reference information for application developers, including APIs, architecture, and
  procedures for using the APIs.
</para>
</section>

<section id="ogsadai-developer-beforeyoubegin">
<title>Before you begin</title>
  <section id="ogsadai-developer-features"><title>Feature summary</title>
    &OGSA_DAI_Feature_Summary_Frag;
  </section>
  <section id="ogsadai-developer-platforms"><title>Tested platforms</title>
    &OGSA_DAI_Feature_Summary_Frag;
   </section>
  
  <section id="ogsadai-developer-compatibility"><title>Backward compatibility summary</title>
    &OGSA_DAI_Compatibility_Summary_Frag;
  </section>
  
  <section id="ogsadai-developer-dependencies"><title>Technology dependencies</title>
    &OGSA_DAI_Dependencies_Summary_Frag;
  </section>
  
  <section id="ogsadai-developer-security_considerations"><title>Security considerations </title>
    &OGSA_DAI_Security_Considerations_Frag;
  </section>
  </section>

<section id="ogsadai-developer-archdes"><title>Architecture and design overview</title>
  <para>A high-level schematic representation of the OGSA-DAI architecture is shown in the diagram below. 
    This is an end goal. All the components may not yet be available within one of the OGSA-DAI distributions. 
    When you download an OGSA-DAI distribution you will only get components specific to one of the WS-I, WSRF 
    or OGSI based infrastructures. The version of OGSA-DAI included in the GT4.0 release only includes the WSRF 
    components. Also note that there is no client toolkit for WSRF in this release. For information about and availability 
    of other releases please visit the project website www.ogsadai.org.uk.</para>
  
  <figure id="JPGHighLevelArchitecture"><title>OGSA-DAI High-level Architecture</title>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="techpreview/ogsadai/developer/JPGHighLevelArchitecture-Resized.JPG" format="JPEG" align="center"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
  </figure>
  
  <para>The different components in this diagram are explained below, working from the bottom of the diagram up to the top.</para>
  <section id="ogsadai-developer-archdes-datalayer">
    <title>Data Layer</title>
    
    <para>The data layer consists of data resources which can be exposed via OGSA-DAI. Currently these include:</para>
<itemizedlist>    
    <listitem><para>Relational data resources, e.g. MySQL, SQL Server, DB2, Oracle.</para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>XML data resources, e.g. Xindice.</para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>Files data resources, e.g. files and directories, OMIM, SWISSPROT and EMBL.</para></listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
  
  <section id="ogsadai-developer-archdes-businesslogic">
    <title>Data Layer-Business Logic Layer Interface</title>
    
    <para>This interface communicates information between the business logic and data layers. This interface is 
      provided by OGSA-DAI classes which invoke JDBC drivers, XMLDB drivers, or other OGSA-DAI classes to manage 
      communications to and from data resources. </para>
  </section>
  
  <section id="ogsadai-developer-archdes-businesslogiclayer">
    <title>Business Logic Layer</title>
    
    <para>This layer encapsulates the core functionality of OGSA-DAI. This layer consists of components which manage:</para>
    
<itemizedlist>
  <listitem><para>Execution of Perform documents which encapsulate a pipelined sequence of activities to be executed at the service. These could consist of queries or updates that operate on a data resource and/or data transformation and/or delivery operations acting on the incoming or outgoing data streams.</para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>Preparation of responses to client requests for data resource query, update, transformation and delivery activities. Responses include execution status information and can also include data. Responses are in the form of Response documents.</para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>Data transformation and delivery management.</para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>Connection to, management of and interaction with data resources.</para></listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>The business logic later is termed the DAI-Core. </para>
  </section>
  
  <section id="ogsadai-developer-archdes-businesslogiclayerinterface">
    <title>Presentation Layer-Business Logic Layer Interface</title>
    
   <para> This interface communicates information between the presentation and business logic layers. 
     This interface supports invocation of OGSA-DAI functionality within the business logic layer in a way that 
     is independent of any Web or Grid environment, i.e. a way that is also suitable to allow non-Web-enabled 
     clients to access OGSA-DAI functionality directly. This interface provides the following:</para>
    
<itemizedlist>
  <listitem><para>Components to extract information for the business logic layer from requests arriving via:
<itemizedlist>
  <listitem><para>OGSA-DAI WSRF services.</para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>OGSA-DAI WS-I services.</para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>OGSA-DAI OGSI services.</para></listitem>
</itemizedlist></para>
  </listitem>
<listitem><para>Note that WS-I is being used in a very specific way - services that only require those standards that are addressed in the WS-I Basic Profile 1.1 document. Components to extract information from the business logic layer and build responses to be provided via:
<itemizedlist>
  <listitem><para>OGSA-DAI WSRF services.</para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>OGSA-DAI WS-I services.</para></listitem>
  <listitem><para>OGSA-DAI OGSI services.</para></listitem>
</itemizedlist></para>
</listitem>
</itemizedlist>
    
    <section id="ogsadai-developer-archdes-presentation-to-businesslogic">
<title>  Information From Presentation Layer to Business Logic Layer</title>
    <itemizedlist>
    <listitem><para>Client proxy certificates and credentials in a Web- and Grid-independent format.</para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>Received data.</para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>Perform documents from clients.</para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>DAI-Core configuration information including data resource drivers, data resource URIs, database user names and passwords, information on supported activities and the legal form of Perform documents.</para></listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>
    <section id="ogsadai-developer-archdes-businesslogic-to-presentation">   
      <title>Information From Business Logic Layer to Presentation Layer</title>
    
<itemizedlist>
  <listitem><para>Response documents.</para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>Data for delivery.</para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>Data resource schema.</para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>Information on data resource-related activities that can be requested by the user within Perform documents.</para></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section id="ogsadai-developer-archdes-presentationlayer">  
<title>Presentation Layer</title>
  
  <para>This layer encapsulates the functionality relating to exposing OGSA-DAI to a Grid via Web- or Grid-enabled 
    interfaces. For each realisation there is associated WSDL and XML Schema describing the Web- or Grid-enabled 
    interfaces. The following presentation layer interfaces are supported:</para>
  <itemizedlist>
  <listitem><para>OGSA-DAI OGSI-compliant services based on the Globus Toolkit 3.2.</para></listitem>
  <listitem><para>OGSA-DAI WSRF-compliant services based on the Globus Toolkit 4.0.</para></listitem>
  <listitem><para>OGSA-DAI WS-I-compliant services based on Apache Axis 1.2.</para></listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  </section>
  
  <section id="ogsadai-developer-archdes-clients">  
    <title>Clients</title>
  
  <para>OGSA-DAI can support access by any suitable OGSI-, WSRF or WS-I-compliant client, depending on the 
    OGSA-DAI presentation layer deployed at the server which the client is trying to access.</para>
  <para>OGSA-DAI provides a Client Toolkit which provides a higher-level of interaction with OGSA-DAI services than 
    that supported by exchanging Perform and Response documents. This however is not yet supported by the WSRF 
    version of OGSA-DAI. There will be a version available for the next WSRF version of OGSA-DAI that will be available 
    from the OGSA-DAI web site and will be included in the next Globus Toolkit release. </para>
  </section>
</section>

<section id="ogsadai-developer-pubinterfaces"><title>Public interface</title>
  <section id="ogsadai-developer-apis"><title>Semantics and syntax of APIs</title>
    &OGSA_DAI_Interface_API_Frag;
  </section>
  
  <section id="ogsadai-developer-wsdl"><title>Semantics and syntax of the WSDL</title>
    &OGSA_DAI_Interface_WSDL_Frag;
  </section>
  
  <section id="ogsadai-developer-protocols"><title>Semantics and syntax of non-WSDL protocols</title>
    &OGSA_DAI_Interface_Protocol_Frag;
  </section>
  
  <section id="ogsadai-developer-cmd"><title>Command-line tools</title>
    &OGSA_DAI_Interface_Commandline_Frag;
  </section>
  
  <section id="ogsadai-developer-guis"><title>Overview of Graphical User Interface</title>
    &OGSA_DAI_Interface_GUI_Frag;
  </section>
  
  <section id="ogsadai-developer-domain"><title>Semantics and syntax of domain-specific interface</title>
    &OGSA_DAI_Interface_Domain_Frag;
  </section>
  
  <section id="ogsadai-developer-config"><title>Configuration interface</title>
    &OGSA_DAI_Interface_Config_Frag;
  </section>
  
  <section id="ogsadai-developer-env"><title>Environment variable interface</title>
    &OGSA_DAI_Interface_Env_Frag;
  </section>
</section>

<section id="ogsadai-developer-scenarios"><title>Usage scenarios </title>
  <section id="ogsadai-developer-scenarios-dataresources">
<title>Interacting with Data Resources</title>
  
  <para>OGSA-DAI supports interaction with data resources, and other data manipulation operations, via a 
    document-oriented interface. The basic building blocks for doing this are:</para>
  
<itemizedlist>
  <listitem><para> Activities - form the basic data resource manipulation, data transformation and delivery operations that a 
    client may want to perform. OGSA-DAI comes with a bunch of pre-defined activities, see the documentation in the 
    distribution for more detail on what is available, and if you do not find the activity that you own then you can write your 
    own and plug it into the existing framework. Activities are the basic building block of Perform documents.</para></listitem>
  <listitem><para>Perform Documents - allow clients to specify a collection of operation that they would like to perform on a 
    data resource. Activities are collected together in the perform document with a simple data flow going from one 
    activity to the next. In principle a simple operation could be to perform an SQL query on a relational database, take
    the results and perform an XSL Transform - assuming that the results are returned in XML format and then delivered 
    to a third party using ftp. A number of activities could be linked together to process the data before it is delivered. The 
    object here is to take the computation to the data and avoid as many client-service interaction. Perform documents 
    are submitted to data service resources exposed by OGSA-DAI data services - a data service resource manages the 
    exposure of and interaction with a data resource.</para></listitem>
  <listitem><para>Response Documents - are returned by data service resources via OGSA-DAI services to clients to inform 
    them as to the execution status of their Perform documents and, often, to also return data directly back to a client if 
    third party delivery is not being used.</para></listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>Using these fairly basic properties it is possible to achieve fairly complex interaction patterns as illustrated in 
    the figure below.</para>
    
    <figure id="Scenarios"><title>Possible OGSA-DAI Scenario Configurations</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="techpreview/ogsadai/developer/Scenarios.jpg" format="JPEG" align="center"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
  
  <para>Thus, one is able to do a simple query-response interaction where the data goes directly back to the analyst 
    querying a data service resource exposed by a data service. A third party delivery where the data is returned to a third 
    party consumer and the analyst receives the status of the the perform document. Another scenario has the client 
    passing on the details of the data service resource (and the data service which exposes it) to a third party who then 
    pulls the data from the data service resource via the data service.</para>
  
  <para>The process is relatively similar for updates where the analyst can submit the update directly to a data service 
    resource (via a data service), with the data being transferred in the same message. Alternatively the data for an 
    insert may be pulled or pushed from a third party.</para>
  
  <para>More complex scenarios are also possible with the ability to perform service-to-service communication. 
    However, although it is possible to do this within OGSA-DAI it has been found that performing data transfers using 
    SOAP is not very efficient. More work remains to be done in this area.</para>
  
  <para>Thus based on the simple concept of activities, perform and response documents fairly complex scenarios 
    can be achieved using OGSA-DAI. </para>
</section>
</section>

<section id="ogsadai-developer-debugging"><title>Debugging</title>
<para>There is no particular debugging advice at this time.</para>
</section>

<section id="ogsadai-developer-troubleshooting"><title>Troubleshooting</title>
  <para>Please check with the Administration Troubleshooting section for some common errors encountered with 
    OGSA-DAI. More information will also be available from the OGSA-DAI web site (<ulink url="http://www.ogsadai.org.uk">www.ogsadai.org.uk</ulink>).</para>
</section>

<section id="ogsadai-developer-relateddocs"><title>Related Documentation</title>
  <para>OGSA-DAI related presentations can be found at the OGSA-DAI web sited under: <ulink url="http://www.ogsadai.org.uk/docs">www.ogsadai.org.uk/docs</ulink> - 
    note that this contains information about the different flavours of OGSA-DAI and not just the WSRF version. You also will 
    find links to courses and tutorials at <ulink url="http://www.ogsadai.org.uk/courses/">www.ogsadai.org.uk/courses/</ulink>.</para>
</section>

