<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">

<chapter id="wsaajava-pdp-SAMLAuthzCallout" xreflabel="SAMLAuthorizationCallout PDP"><title>SAML Authorization Callout</title>
 <indexterm type="authzframe"><primary>PDP</primary><secondary>SAML Authorization Callout</secondary></indexterm>
 <section><title>Class name</title>
  <para><filename>org.globus.wsrf.impl.security.authorization.SAMLAuthorizationCallout</filename></para>
 </section>
 
 <section><title>Overview</title>
 <para> This PDP can be used to talk to any authorization service that implements the <ulink url="https://forge.gridforum.org/projects/ogsa-authz">OGSA AuthZ</ulink> interface. The steps involved include:
<orderedlist>
<listitem><para>
Secure call is made to the authorization service
</para></listitem>

<listitem><para>
Secure response is expected
</para></listitem>

<listitem><para>
Identity of soap message siganture or tls connection is established
</para></listitem>

<listitem><para>
If response is signed, identity of response signature is established.
</para></listitem>

<listitem><para>
Issuer identity is determined from authz service is 4 or 5, in that order
</para></listitem>

<listitem><para>
If there are any errors constructing request,contacting authz service or parsing response, an indeterminate decision is issued by container
</para></listitem>

<listitem><para>
Response signature is verified.
</para></listitem>

<listitem><para>
Every assertion in the response is verified to be issued by issuer identity (point 5)
</para></listitem>

<listitem><para>
If any of the statement is not a permit on the particular subject, resource, action, a deny is returned by issuer identity. Otherwise a permit is returned.
</para></listitem>

<listitem><para>
In the future, a delegation step from the issuer identity (in 5) to some other issuers could be set as policy on SAMLAuthzCallout to establish a chain.
</para></listitem>

</orderedlist>
</para>
 </section>
 
 <section><title>Configuration</title>

  <variablelist>
   <varlistentry><term><filename>authzService</filename></term>
    <listitem>
      <para>
      Property that points to the authorization service to contact. The value should be a URL.
      </para>
    </listitem>
   </varlistentry>

   <varlistentry><term><filename>securityMechanism</filename></term>
    <listitem>
      <para>
      Property that indicates the security mechanism to use to contact authorization service. Should be either &quot;msg&quot; for GSI Secure Message or &quot;conv&quot; for GSI Secure Conversation. If authorization service URL container &quot;https&quot; as protocol, GSI Secure Transport is used to contact the authorization service.
      </para>
    </listitem>
   </varlistentry>

   <varlistentry><term><filename>protectionLevel</filename></term>
    <listitem>
      <para>
      Property that indicates the protection level to use to contact the authorization service. Should be either &quot;sig&quot; for signature and &quot;enc&quot; for encryption. 
      </para>
    </listitem>
   </varlistentry>

   <varlistentry><term><filename>authzServiceCertificate</filename></term>
    <listitem>
      <para>
      Property that points to the authorization service public certificate file. This property is required only if &quot;securityMechanism&quot; is GSI Secure Message and &quot;protectionLevel&quot; is encryption.
      </para>
    </listitem>
   </varlistentry>

   <varlistentry><term><filename>authzServiceIdentity</filename></term>
    <listitem>
      <para>
      Property that has the expected identity of the authorization service. This is used for authorizing the call to authorization service.
      </para>
    </listitem>
   </varlistentry>

   <varlistentry><term><filename>samlAuthzSimpleDecision</filename></term>
    <listitem>
      <para>
      Property indicates if SimpleAuthorizationDecisionStatement as defined in OGSA AuthZ specification  is being requested from the authorization service.
      </para>
    </listitem>
   </varlistentry>

 </variablelist>

 </section>
 
 <section><title>Decision Table</title>
  <informaltable>
   <tgroup cols='2'>
    <tbody>
     <row><entry> Error constructing local SAML data types. </entry><entry>INDETERMINATE</entry></row>
     <row><entry> Error converting EPR to string</entry><entry>INDETERMINATE</entry></row>
     <row><entry> Error signing SAML Request</entry><entry>INDETERMINATE</entry></row>
     <row><entry> Error accessing configured authorization service </entry><entry>INDETERMINATE</entry></row>
     <row><entry> Null response from configured authorization service </entry><entry>INDETERMINATE</entry></row>
     <row><entry> SAML exception from configured authorization service </entry><entry>INDETERMINATE</entry></row>
     <row><entry> SAML Response signed by identity different from expected identity ofconfigured authorization service </entry><entry>INDETERMINATE</entry></row>

     <row><entry>If decision returned from service is anything other than permit.</entry><entry>DENY</entry></row>
     <row><entry>If decision returned from service is permit.</entry><entry>PERMIT</entry></row>
    </tbody>
   </tgroup>
  </informaltable>
  
 </section>
 
 <section><title>Related interceptors</title>
  <para> No interceptors are related other than the default bootstrap interceptor
   (<olink targetdoc="wsaajavaPIP" targetptr="wsaajava-pip-X509Bootstrap"/>), which is required to be used with this PDP.</para>
 </section>
</chapter>