<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
    "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">

<section id="wsaajava-pdp-XACMLAuthzCallout"
         xreflabel="XACML Authorization Callout PDP">
    <title>XACML Authorization Callout</title>
    <indexterm type="authzframe">
        <primary>PDP</primary>
        <secondary>XACMLAuthzCallout</secondary>
    </indexterm>
    <section>
        <title>Class name</title>
        <para>
            <filename>
                org.globus.wsrf.impl.security.authorization.XACMLAuthorizationCallout
            </filename>
        </para>
    </section>

    <section>
        <title>Overview</title>

        <para>Policy Decision Point that communicates with a configured
            authorization service that has XACML Authorization Service
            interface. The PDP constructs a XACML Authorization Query and parses
            the XACML Authorization Decision response from the service to
            ascertain a decision. It uses the data types defined in
            <ulink
                link="http://docs.oasis-open.org/xacml/2.0/access_control-xacml-2.0-saml-profile-spec-os.pdf">
                SAML 2.0 Profile for XACML 2.0</ulink>.
        </para>

        <section>
            <title>Request construction</title>
            <para>
                The PDP does not create or collect any attributes, but sends a
                subset of attributes from the RequestEntities object as part of
                XACML Request sent to the authorization service. Custom PIPs
                which collect relevant attributes should be configured in the
                authorization chain. Requestor attributes are added to
                SubjectType, action attributes to Action Type, resource
                attributes to ResourceType and environment attributes to
                EnvironmentType. Both identity and non-identity attributes that
                meet the following criteria are added:
            </para>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Any attribute with data type set to
                        http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#string with the
                        attributes values of type java.lang.String are added.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Any attribute with data type set to
                        http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#integerwith the
                        attributes values of type java.lang.Integer are added.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Any attribute with the attributes values that
                        implement org.opensaml.xml.XMLObject are added.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>

            <para>Only a subset of attributes are added, since these are known
                types to serialize and send on the wire. Custom types can be
                sent by adding attribute values that implement XMLObject
                interface.
            </para>
        </section>

        <section id="xacmlAuthzPDP-response-eval">
            <title>Evaluation of response from authoritzation service</title>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>The response is expected to have the attribute
                        InResponseTo, since it is be sent in response to the
                        query sent by the callout. If attribute is null or does
                        not match query id, indeterminate decision is returned.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>If no assertion is received or if no XACML Authz
                        Decision Statement is found, an indeterminate decision
                        is returned.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>If return context is set to true and no request
                        context is returned from service, an indeterminate
                        decision is returned. The request context is NOT used
                        currently for any decision making process.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>If even a single XACMLAuthzDecsionStatement, embedded
                        in a Response with InResponseTo attribute set to the
                        Request id is found, with the ResultType deny, a deny
                        decision is returned.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>If even a single XACMLAuthzDecsionStatement, embedded
                        in a Response with InResponseTo attribute set to the
                        Request id is found, with the ResultType indeterminate,
                        a indeterminate decision is returned.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>If every XACMLAuthzDecisionStatement, embedded in a
                        Response with InResponseTo attribute set to the Request
                        id is found, with the ResultType permit, a permit
                        decision is returned.Note: at least one such permit
                        statement is required, if not an indeterminate decision
                        is returned.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </section>

        <section>
            <title>Known Limitation</title>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>The response received from an authorization service
                        should have explicit xmlns declarations for the prefixes
                        that are part of values of xsi:type attribute. Example,
                        if one of the elements in Response is &lt;foo:element1
                        xsi:type=&quot;bar:type1&quot;&gt;&lt;/foo:element1&gt;
                        and no other element in response has the prefix bar, an
                        explicit xmlns:bar attribute should be added to the
                        Response element, even if the ns is present in SOAP
                        header.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </section>

        <section>
            <title>Installation</title>
            <para>This component is not installed by default, use the following
                options to install it.
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>From source: XACML authorization module depends on
                            Java WS Core installation, including the basic
                            authorization module.
                            <itemizedlist>
                                <listitem>
                                    <para>Checkout source code:
                                        <pre>cvs co wsrf/schema wsrf/build.xml
                                            wsrf/java authorization/java
                                        </pre>
                                    </para>
                                </listitem>
                                <listitem>
                                    <para>Install to GLOBUS_LOCATION:
                                        <itemizedlist>
                                            <listitem>
                                                <para>export GLOBUS_LOCATION
                                                    /sandbox/globus/gtInstall
                                                </para>
                                            </listitem>
                                            <listitem>
                                                <para>cd wsrf</para>
                                            </listitem>
                                            <listitem>
                                                <para>ant all</para>
                                            </listitem>
                                        </itemizedlist>
                                    </para>
                                </listitem>
                                <listitem>
                                    <para>
                                        <itemizedlist>
                                            <listitem>
                                                <para>Checkout source code for
                                                    the XACML authorization
                                                    callout and install:
                                                </para>
                                            </listitem>
                                            <listitem>
                                                <para>cvs co
                                                    authorization/common/xacml
                                                    authorization/java/xacml
                                                    authorization/build.xml
                                                </para>
                                            </listitem>
                                            <listitem>
                                                <para>cd authorization</para>
                                            </listitem>
                                            <listitem>
                                                <para>ant deployXACML</para>
                                            </listitem>
                                        </itemizedlist>
                                    </para>
                                </listitem>
                            </itemizedlist>
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Using Globus installer: The first step in an
                            installer is to run configure command. Use option
                            <code>-enablexacml</code>
                            with the configure command to install the XACML
                            pieces
                            .
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </para>
        </section>

        <section>
            <title>Testing XACML Authorization Callout</title>
            <para>Code base is shipped with unit tests that leverage a sample
                XACML authorization service and test the callout.
            </para>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>export GLOBUS_LOCATION /sandbox/globus/gtInstall
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>cd authorization/java/xacml/test</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>ant test</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Test reports are available in
                        authorization/java/xacml/test/test-reports
                    </para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </section>

        <section>
            <title>Configuration</title>
            <para>The XACML callout can be used at container, service or
                resource level security and configured using security
                descriptors. The following properties can be configured:
            </para>
            <itemizedlist>

                <listitem>
                    <para>Authorization service endpoint: This is a required
                        configuration that provides the endpoint of the
                        authorization service. The value should have the format
                        &lt;protocol&gt;://&lt;hostname&gt;:&lt;portNumber&gt;/serivicePath.
                        For
                        example,
                        https://foo.bar.edu:8443/wsrf/services/SampleAuthzService.
                    </para>
                </listitem>

                <listitem>
                    <para>Input context only: Determines the value of attribute
                        set in XACML Authz Decision Query. Based on
                        specification,
                        if the value is “true”, then the authorization decision
                        MUST
                        be made solely on the basis of information contained in
                        the
                        XACML Authz Decision Query and external XACML Attributes
                        MUST NOT be used. If the value is “false”, then the
                        authorization decision MAY be made on the basis of XACML
                        Attributes not contained in the XACML Authz Decision
                        Query.
                        False, by default.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Return Context: Attribute is set in the XACML Request.
                        If the value is “true”, then the PDP MUST include an
                        &lt;xacmlcontext:Request&gt;
                        instance in the XACMLAuthzDecision Statement in the
                        XACMLAuthzDecision Response. This &lt;xacml-context:Request&gt;
                        instance MUST include all those attributes supplied by
                        the
                        PEP in the &lt;xacml-samlp:XACMLAuthzDecisionQuery&gt;
                        that
                        were used in making the authorization decision. If
                        “false”,
                        then the PDP MUST NOT include an &lt;xacml-context:Request&gt;
                        instance in the XACMLAuthzDecision Statement in the
                        XACMLAuthzDecision Response. False, by default.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Combine Policies: Attribute is set in the XACML
                        Request. If the attribute value is &quot;true&quot;,
                        then the PDP MUST
                        insert all policies passed in the
                        &lt;xacmlsamlp:XACMLAuthzDecisionQuery&gt;
                        into the set of policies or policy sets that define the
                        PDP
                        as specified in Section 7.13 of the XACML 2.0 core
                        specification. If the attribute value is &quot;false&quot;,
                        then there
                        MUST be no more than one &lt;xacml:Policy&gt; or &lt;xacml:PolicySet&gt;
                        passed in the &lt;xacml-samlp:XACMLAuthzDecisionQuery&gt;.
                        True, by default.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Privacy enabled: If the attribute is set to true,
                        encryption is enabled in communication with the
                        authorization
                        service. If the authorization service URL is http, then
                        secure
                        message is used and public certificate of the server can
                        be
                        configured for encryption.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Authorization service identity: Expected identity of
                        the authorization service.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Obligation handlers: An arbitrary number of obligation
                        handlers can be configured with a corresponding
                        obligation
                        Ids. The handlers should extend the abstract class
                        org.globus.wsrf.impl.security.authorization.AbstractObligationHandler
                        and are used to process the obligations returned by the
                        authorization service.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>

            <section>
                <title>Configuration Notes:</title>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Default container configuration is NOT used and
                            hence relevant security descriptor should be
                            configured with the properties
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>All requests to the authorization service uses the
                            system credentials and is NOT configurable.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>If authorization service URL starts with http,
                            then GSI Secure Message is used for conversation. If
                            the service URL starts with https, then GSI Secure
                            Transport is used. This is not configurable.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </section>

            <section>
                <title>Sample security descriptor:</title>
                <para>Sample security descriptor with XACML configuration:
                    <ulink
                        link="http://viewcvs.globus.org/viewcvs.cgi/authorization/java/xacml/samples/etc/xacml-security-config.xml?view=markup">
                        Security Descriptor
                    </ulink>
                </para>
            </section>

            <section>
                <title>Obligation Handlers</title>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            Local Obligation Handler: The toolkit is shipped
                            with a LocalAccountObligationHandler, that processes
                            obligation with id provided in the constructor. It
                            expects local user name to be added as an attribute
                            with id XACMLConstants.USERNAME_ATTRIBUTE_ID, with
                            string dataype. All values of the above attribute
                            are added to the peer subject as local username
                            principal, similar to the mechanism used in GridMap
                            PDP.

                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            Custom obligation handler: An obligation handler to
                            process any obligation can be configured and should
                            extend from the AbstractObligaitonHandler class.
                            This requires the the method evaluateObligation be
                            overridden withe code to process the obligation. The
                            authorization context is provided as the
                            RequestEntity object and can be used to store any
                            processed obligation data.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </section>
        </section>

        <section>
            <title>Decision Table</title>
            <informaltable>
                <tgroup cols='2'>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>No peer subject</entry>
                            <entry>INDETERMINATE</entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>Configuration erors</entry>
                            <entry>INDETERMINATE</entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>Deny response from authorization service
                            </entry>
                            <entry>DENY</entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>Response from authorization service vioates
                                conditions explained in
                                <olink
                                    targetptr="xacmlAuthzPDP-response-eval"></olink>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>DENY</entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>Permit response from authorization service
                            </entry>
                            <entry>PERMIT</entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </informaltable>

        </section>

        <section>
            <title>Related interceptors</title>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Default bootstrap interceptor
                        (<olink targetptr="wsaajava-pip-X509Bootstrap"/>)
                    </para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </section>
    </section>