<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd"
[

<!ENTITY % myents SYSTEM "../../../entities">

%myents;

]>
<book id="delegationUser">
<title>GT4 Delegation Service User&apos;s Guide</title>
<titleabbrev>User&apos;s Guide</titleabbrev>

<chapter id="delegation-user-introduction">

  <title>Introduction</title>

  <para>The  delegation service can be used when a user wants to delegate rights to a service that is hosted in the same container as the delegation service.  The delegation service accepts a credential      from the user and provides access to that credential to any authorized service that runs in the same container. Upon delegation to the service an endpoint reference to the delegated credential is returned to the client, which can then be furnished to other services as a handle to the credential. </para>

  <para>Moreover, the endpoint reference returned on delegation can be used by the client to refresh the credential stored with the delegation service.  When the client performs a refresh the service sends notifications to any service that has registered interest  in that particular credential.</para>

<para> The generic client <olink targetdoc="javawscoreUser" targetptr="wsrf-destroy"/>
can be used to remove the delegated credential.</para>

  <para> The <olink targetdoc="javawscoreUser" targetptr="wsrf-query"/> can be used to query the termination time of the delegation resource, which is the lifetime of the credential. The resource property to query is <command>{http://docs.oasis-open.org/wsrf/2004/06/wsrf-WS-ResourceLifetime-1.2-draft-01.xsd}TerminationTime</command>.</para>

  <note> <para> If the service being contacted is using GSI <glossterm baseform="transport-level security">Secure
Transport</glossterm>, then the container credentials configured for the service
will be used, even if service/resource level credentials are
configured. Hence authorization needs to be done based on the DN of
the container credentials.</para></note>

</chapter>

<reference id="delegation-user-commandline">

  <title>Command-line tools</title>

  <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
    href="../WS_AA_Delegation_Service_Interface_Commandline_Frag.xml" xpointer="xpointer(/reference/*)"/>

</reference>

<chapter id="delegation-user-gui">

  <title>Graphical user interfaces</title>
  <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
    href="../WS_AA_Delegation_Service_Interface_GUI_Frag.xml" xpointer="xpointer(/section/*)"/>
</chapter>

<chapter id="delegation-user-troubleshooting">

  <title>Troubleshooting</title>

  <section>

    <title> AuthorizationException: &quot;test DN&quot; is not authorized to use operation: {http://www.globus.org/08/2004/delegationService}requestSecurityToken</title>

    <para>This exception can occur when  a client whose DN is not in the <glossterm>grid map file</glossterm> configured for the delegation factory service attempts to delegate (using globus-credential-delegate) a credential to the factory service.</para>

    <note>

      <para>The <emphasis>test DN</emphasis> specified in the error message is just a  placeholder and will contain the DN of the user attempting to access the credential.</para>

    </note>

  </section>

  <section>

    <title> AuthorizationException: &quot;test DN&quot; is not authorized to use operation: {http://www.globus.org/08/2004/delegationService}refresh</title>

    <para>This exception can occur when  a client       attempts to refresh a credential it did not delegate (using globus-credential-refresh).</para>

    <note>

      <para>The <emphasis>test DN</emphasis> specified in the error message is just a  placeholder and will contain the DN of the user attempting to access the credential.</para>

    </note>

  </section>

  <section>

    <title>CoG Configuration and troubleshooting</title>

    <para>Also, for security related troubleshooting the <ulink url="http://www.globus.org/cog/distribution/1.2/FAQ.TXT">CoG FAQ</ulink> might prove useful (especially sections on configuring credentials, CAs and so on.)</para>

  </section>

</chapter>
  <glossary role="auto" id="glossary-delegationUser">
    <!-- 
    <remark>some terms not in the docs but wanted in glossary: 
    <glossterm>scheduler</glossterm>
    </remark>
    -->
    <glossdiv><title>A</title>
      <glossentry>
        <glossterm>Dummy term</glossterm>
        <glossdef>
          <para>This is a dummy entry for the automatic glossary database. Do not edit.</para>
        </glossdef>
      </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
  </glossary>
</book>