<title>GT 4.0 DRS (Tech Preview): System Administrator's Guide</title>
<titleabbrev>System Administrator's Guide</titleabbrev>

<section id="s-datarep-admin-introduction"><title>Introduction</title>
<para>This guide contains advanced configuration information for system administrators
  working with the Data Replication Service (DRS). It provides references to information on procedures
  typically performed by system administrators, including installing, configuring,
 deploying, and testing the installation.</para>
 <important>
  <simpara> This information is in addition to the basic Globus Toolkit prerequisite, 
   overview, installation, security configuration instructions in the <ulink url="../../admin/docbook/">GT 4.0 System Administrator's Guide</ulink>.  
   Read through this guide before continuing!</simpara>  
 </important>
</section>


<section id="s-datarep-admin-installing"><title>Building and installing</title>
<para>DRS is not installed as part of the standard install. To install the DRS, first install the Globus Toolkit
 by following the basic installation instructions as referenced above. Following the basic installation, issue
 a <emphasis>make gt4-replicator postinstall</emphasis> command from the directory that was used to build the toolkit. The
 following commands will install the DRS.</para>
<screen>
 ./configure --prefix=/path/to/install
 make
 make gt4-replicator postinstall
</screen>
<para><emphasis>Note:</emphasis> The DRS depends on the Globus RLS. In order for the &quot;make&quot; command above to build
 and install the RLS, you must follow the basic installation instructions for GT 4.0 as noted previously. 
 Installation of the RLS requires that the <emphasis>GLOBUS_IODBC_PATH</emphasis> environment variable be properly set <emphasis>before</emphasis> 
 issuing the &quot;make&quot; command. Not setting this environment variable before installation is a common
 mistake encountered by users.</para>
</section>


<section id="s-datarep-admin-configuring"><title>Configuring </title>
<para>This information is in addition to the basic configuration instructions in the 
 <ulink url="http://www.globus.org/toolkit/docs/4.0/admin/docbook/">GT4.0 System Administrator's Guide</ulink>. Aside from the basic configuration of GT 4.0, please review the following instructions for:</para>

<section id="s-datarep-admin-dbconfig"><title>Database Configuration</title>
<para>The setup and configuration of the DRS depends on the installation of a relational database server. At present, 
these instructions will work with the PostgreSQL database server. The developers of DRS used the PostgreSQL 7.4.6 
release when testing this service. <emphasis>Note:</emphasis> You must start PostgreSQL with the <emphasis>-i</emphasis> option to enable TCP/IP 
communication, which is required by DRS.</para>
<para>After installing and starting the database server, you will need to add a user account and create a database for DRS.
The following commands may be used to configure PostgreSQL. (<emphasis>Note:</emphasis> you may select your own user account rather than using the example <emphasis>dbuser</emphasis>, but you must reflect that change consistently throughout the configuration of the service.)</para>
<para>1. Add user account:</para>
<screen>
 <emphasis>createuser -d -A -P</emphasis>
 Enter name of user to add: <emphasis>dbuser</emphasis>
 Enter password for new user:
 Enter it again:
 CREATE USER
</screen>
<para>2. Create database:</para>
<screen>
 <emphasis>createdb -O dbuser -W -U dbuser replicator</emphasis>
 Password:
 CREATE DATABASE
</screen>
<para>3. Create database schema:</para>
<screen>
 <emphasis>psql -W -U dbuser -d replicator -f \
  $GLOBUS_LOCATION/share/globus_wsrf_replicator/replicator_psql.sql</emphasis>
 Password:
 CREATE SEQUENCE
 CREATE SEQUENCE
 psql:/globus/install/share/globus_wsrf_replicator/replicator_psql.sql:22: 
 NOTICE:  CREATE TABLE / PRIMARY KEY will create implicit index 
 "t_replicator_pkey" for table "t_replicator"
 CREATE TABLE
 psql:/globus/install/share/globus_wsrf_replicator/replicator_psql.sql:35: 
 NOTICE:  CREATE TABLE / PRIMARY KEY will create implicit index 
 "t_replication_pkey" for table "t_replication"
 CREATE TABLE
 CREATE TABLE
 CREATE TABLE
</screen>
<para>4. Verify database setup:</para>
<screen>
 <emphasis>psql -W -U dbuser -d replicator</emphasis>
 Password:
 Welcome to psql 7.4.6, the PostgreSQL interactive terminal.
 
 Type:  \copyright for distribution terms
        \h for help with SQL commands
        \? for help on internal slash commands
        \g or terminate with semicolon to execute query
        \q to quit
	
 replicator=&gt; <emphasis>\dt</emphasis>
            List of relations
  Schema |     Name      | Type  |    Owner
 --------+---------------+-------+-------------
  public | t_credential  | table | dbuser
  public | t_replication | table | dbuser
  public | t_replicator  | table | dbuser
  public | t_source      | table | dbuser
 (4 rows)
 
 replicator=&gt; <emphasis>\di</emphasis>
                          List of relations
  Schema |        Name        | Type  |    Owner    |     Table
 --------+--------------------+-------+-------------+---------------
  public | t_replication_pkey | index | dbuser      | t_replication
  public | t_replicator_pkey  | index | dbuser      | t_replicator
 (2 rows)

 replicator=&gt; <emphasis>\ds</emphasis>
                   List of relations
  Schema |       Name        |   Type   |    Owner
 --------+-------------------+----------+-------------
  public | t_replication_seq | sequence | dbuser
  public | t_replicator_seq  | sequence | dbuser
 (2 rows)

 replicator=&gt; <emphasis>\d t_replicator</emphasis>
                             Table "public.t_replicator"
    Column   |       Type       |                     Modifiers
 ------------+------------------+-----------------------------------------------
  id         | integer          | not null default nextval('t_replicator_seq'...
  status     | integer          | default 0
  created    | double precision | not null
  started    | double precision | default 0
  terminated | double precision | default 0
  terminate  | double precision | default 0
  subject    | text             |
  username   | text             |
  total      | integer          | default 0
  finished   | integer          | default 0
  failed     | integer          | default 0
  cancelled  | integer          | default 0
  fault      | text             |
 Indexes:
     "t_replicator_pkey" primary key, btree (id)

 replicator=&gt; <emphasis>\q</emphasis>
</screen>
</section>

<section id="s-datarep-admin-jndiconfig"><title>JNDI Configuration</title>
<para>In addition to database setup, the DRS requires certain JNDI settings to be properly configured. The
installed JNDI configuration file may be found at <emphasis>$GLOBUS_LOCATION/etc/globus_wsrf_replicator/jndi-config.xml</emphasis>. 
To view the default configuration file (shipped with the GT 4.0 release) from the Globus CVS repository 
<ulink url="http://viewcvs.globus.org/viewcvs.cgi/ws-replica/replicator/service/java/source/deploy-jndi-config.xml?rev=1.3&amp;content-type=text/vnd.viewcvs-markup">click here</ulink>.</para>
<para>The settings are structured as name-value pairs. For example:</para>
<screen>
 &lt;parameter&gt;
 &nbsp;&nbsp;&lt;name&gt;<emphasis>rliUrl</emphasis>&lt;/name&gt;
 &nbsp;&nbsp;&lt;value&gt;<emphasis>rls://127.0.0.1:39281</emphasis>&lt;/value&gt;
 &lt;/parameter&gt;
</screen>
<para>The following settings must be properly configured:</para>
<itemizedlist>
  <listitem><simpara><emphasis>rliUrl</emphasis>: the connection URL for your installation of RLS running as a RLI service.</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara><emphasis>lrcUrl</emphasis>: the connection URL for your installation of RLS running as a LRC service.</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara><emphasis>rftUrl</emphasis>: the connection URL for your installation of the RFT ReliableFileTransferFactoryService.</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara><emphasis>maxTransferWait</emphasis>: the maximum number of seconds that the Replicator resource will wait for its RFT file transfers to complete. <emphasis>Note:</emphasis> the default value of <emphasis>600</emphasis>, or 10 minutes, will be insufficient for large replication activities.</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara><emphasis>proxyfileChangePermsCmd</emphasis>: the platform-dependent command to change file permissions to user-only read-write permissions.</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara><emphasis>proxyfileDir</emphasis>: the directory that you would like the DRS to temporarily store user proxies. No setting is necessary. This value may be empty.</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara><emphasis>driverClassName</emphasis>: the JDBC database driver class name. This class must be reachable by the service via the container's classpath. The default value of <emphasis>org.postgresql.Driver</emphasis> works with PostgreSQL and comes installed with the standard installation of GT 4.0.</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara><emphasis>url</emphasis>: the connection URL for your installation and configuration of the database server for use with DRS.</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara><emphasis>username</emphasis>: the user associated with your database setup.</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara><emphasis>password</emphasis>: the password associated with your database user account.</simpara></listitem>
</itemizedlist>

</section>
</section>

<section id="s-datarep-admin-deploying"><title>Deploying</title>
<para>No further information is necessary.</para>
</section>

<section id="s-datarep-admin-testing"><title>Testing</title>
<para>This service does not provide a set of tests yet.</para>
</section>

<section id="s-datarep-admin-security_considerations"><title>Security considerations</title>
&DataRep_Security_Considerations_Frag;
</section>

<section id="s-datarep-admin-troubleshooting"><title>Troubleshooting</title>
<para>Generating verbose log output is a critical aid in troubleshooting of the DRS and is useful 
when communicating problems to Globus support lists. To increase logging detail, add the following 
line to the <computeroutput>$GLOBUS_LOCATION/container-log4j.properties</computeroutput> file.</para>
<screen>
 ...
 log4j.category.org.globus.replica=DEBUG
 ...
</screen>
<!-- TODO Add troubleshooting help for problems related to:
  1) database setup
  2) security security
  3) RLS
  4) RFT
-->
</section>
