<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<para>The following changes have occurred for Java WS Core since the last stable release, &previousversion;:</para>
  <section>
    <title>Parameter ordering for Axis generated files</title>
    <para>The Java WS Core &shortversion; release contains a newer version of Axis. In this version of Axis the ordering of parameters in the constructors of generated types has changed. The parameters are now sorted alphabetically. Code that creates an instance of some generated type using a constructor with multiple arguments might need to be checked and updated appropriately. This change does not affect code that creates an instance of some generated type using a default constructor and sets the values using the individual setter methods.
</para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Transport security is used by default (since 3.9.4)</title>
    <para>Transport security (HTTPS) is now assumed as  the default security mechanism. For example, the standalone container will now start in a transport security mode (HTTPS container running on port 8443). The plain (HTTP) container can still be started  using the <option>-nosec</option> option. Please see the <xref linkend="globus-start-container"/> documentation for details.
</para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Different naming scheme for Axis generated files (since 3.9.4)</title>
    <para>The Axis version distributed with Java WS Core follows the JAX-RPC specification and Java naming standards more closely than before when naming the generated files (generated by the <application>wsdl2java</application> process). The code generated is exactly the same as before but the names of the files are slightly different. The changes to the names are pretty straightforward: All underscores are dropped, and the first letter of each word within the name is capitalized. If there are collisions between names (for example, the port type name is the same as some element name), the name for the port type will end with <constant>_PortType</constant> and for the element with <constant>_Element</constant>. Examples:
</para>
    <screen>foo.java -&gt; Foo.java
_Foo_Bar.java -&gt; FooBar.java
_GetMultipleResourceProperties.java -&gt; GetMultipleResourceProperties_Element.java
GetMultipleResourceProperties.java -&gt; GetMultipleResourceProperties_PortType.java</screen>
  </section>


