<?xml version='1.0' ?>
<title>GT &shortversion; SweGrid Accounting System (SGAS) (Tech Preview): System Administrator's Guide</title>
<titleabbrev>System Administrator's Guide</titleabbrev>

<section id="sgas-admin-introduction"><title>Introduction</title>
<para>This guide contains advanced configuration information for system administrators
  working with the SweGrid Accounting System (SGAS). It provides references to information on procedures
  typically performed by system administrators, including installing, configuring,
 deploying, and testing the installation.</para>
 <important>
  <simpara> This information is in addition to the basic Globus Toolkit prerequisite, 
   overview, installation, security configuration instructions in the <xref linkend="gtadmin" />.  
   Read through this guide before continuing!</simpara>  
 </important>
</section>


<section id="sgas-admin-installing"><title>Building and installing</title>
 <para>Building from source is only needed if you need to modify or test the source code for some reason.</para>
 <para>The source code is available in the same installer tar ball as the binaries, in the file <filename>sgas-4.0.1-src.tar.gz</filename>. 
  To build from source, extract the files in that tar ball and run the make-dist script contained therein.</para>
 <para>Source code is available via AFS. To retrieve the latest code set your CVSROOT environment variable to: 
  <filename>/afs/pdc.kth.se/src/packages/SweGrid/SourceRepository</filename>. Then export the code by running the following command:</para>
 <screen>cvs export -D today accounting</screen>
 <para>If you don't have access to AFS you can also download a nightly checkout of the code from 
  <ulink url="http://www.sgas.se/source/">http://www.sgas.se/source/</ulink>.</para>
 
</section>


<section id="sgas-admin-configuring"><title>Configuring </title>
<para>This information is in addition to the basic configuration instructions in the 
 <xref linkend="gtadmin" />.</para>
 <para>The accounting system is an orthogonal component that complements an installation of (in particular) GRAM. 
  Integration with WS GRAM is ongoing and not included in this tech preview.</para>
 <para>At this point in time, detailed deployment and configuration information can be found at 
  <ulink url="http://www.sgas.se/docs/SGASInstallConfig.pdf">http://www.sgas.se/docs/SGASInstallConfig.pdf</ulink>.</para>

</section>

<section id="sgas-admin-deploying"><title>Deploying</title>
 <para>At this point in time, detailed deployment and configuration information can be found at 
  <ulink url="http://www.sgas.se/docs/SGASInstallConfig.pdf">http://www.sgas.se/docs/SGASInstallConfig.pdf</ulink>.</para>
</section>

<section id="sgas-admin-testing"><title>Testing</title>
 <para>A test suite for an SGAS installation is provided. To use it run:</para>
 <screen>build.sh run-test</screen>
 <para>after you have installed the system. </para>
  <para>On Windows systems, use the <command>build.bat</command> 
  script instead of <command>build.sh</command>.</para>
</section>

<section id="sgas-admin-security-considerations"><title>Security considerations</title>
&SGAS_Security_Considerations_Frag;
</section>

<section id="sgas-admin-troubleshooting"><title>Troubleshooting</title>
 <para>Detailed error messages, such as stack traces are not logged to the command line utility (<command>sgas-admin</command>) 
  output but instead are written to an error log file. The default location of this file is <filename>./sgas-admin.log</filename>. 
  The location and other SGAS admin log properties can be changed in the file 
  <filename>etc/sgas-client/sgas-admin-log4j.properties</filename> in the 
  SGAS installation directory. The errors displayed in the command line tool share the same correlation id (CID) 
  as the errors in the error log file.</para>
 <para>If you encounter problems or need assistance, don't hesitate to send an email to swegrid-accounting@pdc.kth.se.</para>
 
</section>
