<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd"
[

<!ENTITY % xinclude SYSTEM "../../../xinclude.mod" >
%xinclude;


]>
<book id="datarepAdmin">
<title>GT <replaceable role="entity">version</replaceable> DRS: System Administrator's Guide</title>
<titleabbrev>System Administrator's Guide</titleabbrev>

<bookinfo><abstract><title>Introduction</title>
<para>This guide contains advanced configuration information for system administrators
  working with the Data Replication Service (DRS). It provides references to information on procedures
  typically performed by system administrators, including installing, configuring,
 deploying, and testing the installation.</para>
<para> <important>
  <simpara> This information is in addition to the basic Globus Toolkit prerequisite, 
   overview, installation, security configuration instructions in the <olink targetdoc="gtadmin"/>.  
   Read through this guide before continuing!</simpara>  
 </important></para></abstract>
</bookinfo>


<chapter id="datarep-admin-installing"><title>Building and installing</title>
    <para>DRS is distributed with the Globus Toolkit <replaceable role="entity">version</replaceable> and is available in both the binary bundles and the source bundle. For most purposes, the binary bundle provides the simplest means of installing the DRS and its requirements. There are three typical ways to access and install the DRS:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
        <listitem><simpara><olink targetptr="datarep-admin-install-binary"/></simpara></listitem>
        <listitem><simpara><olink targetptr="datarep-admin-install-source"/></simpara></listitem>
        <listitem><simpara><olink targetptr="datarep-admin-install-cvs"/></simpara></listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <important><simpara>Before proceding with installation of DRS, please familiarize yourself with the installation procedures for RLS (see <olink targetdoc="rls"/>) and RFT (see <olink targetdoc="rft"/>).</simpara></important>

    <section id="datarep-admin-install-binary"><title>Installing DRS using Globus Toolkit Binary Bundle</title>
        <para>Follow instructions provided by <olink targetdoc="gtadmin"/> and <olink targetdoc="gtadmin" targetptr="gtadmin-install"/> in order to install the DRS from one of the available binary bundles of the Globus Toolkit.</para>
        <para>Once you have unpackaged the binary bundle, the following commands may be used to install DRS:</para>
        <screen>
% ./configure --prefix=$GLOBUS_LOCATION --enable-rls --enable-drs
% make
% make install
        </screen>
    </section>

    <section id="datarep-admin-install-source"><title>Installing DRS using Globus Toolkit Source Bundle</title>
        <para>DRS is not installed as part of the default source install. In order to install DRS, you will need to ensure that RLS is also installed as part of the build by reviewing its installation procedures. Along with RLS configure settings (e.g., ODBC related settings) the <computeroutput>--enable-drs</computeroutput> flag is required as part of the configuration step.</para>
        <para>The following commands will install the DRS (optionally you may use the &quot;drs&quot; make target to build only DRS and its requirements:</para>
        <screen>
% ./configure --prefix=<emphasis>/path/to/install</emphasis> --with-iodbc-includes=<emphasis>/path/to/iodbc/include</emphasis> --with-iodbc-libs=<emphasis>/path/to/iodbc/lib</emphasis> --enable-rls --enable-drs
% make <emphasis>[drs]</emphasis>
% make install
        </screen>
    </section>

    <section id="datarep-admin-install-cvs"><title>Installing DRS using Globus CVS</title>
        <para>Additionally, you may access the DRS from the Globus Toolkit CVS repository. You may deploy the 4.0.x DRS on top of an existing GT 4.0.x installation using the <computeroutput>globus_4_0_branch</computeroutput> tag. You may deploy the 4.1.x DRS on top of an existing GT 4.1.x installation using trunk.</para>
        <para>The following example instructions will only work given the presence of an existing GT installation with <emphasis>all DRS dependencies</emphasis>. The best way to establish such an environment is to first follow the basic installation instructions and subsequently use the following instructions to obtain the latest updates from the CVS branch. Note the use of the <computeroutput>globus_4_0_branch</computeroutput> tag depends on whether you are interested in updates from the maintenance branch or the development trunk.</para>
        <screen>
% setenv GLOBUS_LOCATION /path/to/existing/<emphasis>gt4xx</emphasis>/install/
% setenv CVSROOT :pserver:anonymous@cvs.globus.org:/home/globdev/CVS/globus-packages
% cvs co <emphasis>-r globus_4_0_branch</emphasis> ws-replica/
% cd ws-replica/replicator/
% ant deploy
        </screen>
        <para>To learn more about general instructions regarding GT CVS access, see <ulink url="http://www.globus.org/toolkit/docs/development/remote-cvs.html">Remote CVS Access</ulink>.</para>
    </section>
</chapter>



    <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
        href="../DataRep_Interface_Config_Frag.xml"/>
<!-- n/a
<chapter id="datarep-admin-deploying"><title>Deploying</title>
<para>No further information is necessary.</para>
</chapter>
 -->
<chapter id="datarep-admin-testing"><title>Testing</title>
<para>This service does not provide a set of tests yet.</para>
</chapter>

<chapter id="datarep-admin-security-considerations"><title>Security considerations</title>
    <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
        href="../DataRep_Security_Considerations_Frag.xml"/>
</chapter>

<chapter id="datarep-admin-troubleshooting"><title>Troubleshooting</title>
<para>Generating verbose log output is a critical aid in troubleshooting of the DRS and is useful 
when communicating problems to Globus support lists. To increase logging detail, add the following 
line to the <computeroutput>$GLOBUS_LOCATION/container-log4j.properties</computeroutput> file.</para>
<screen>
 ...
 log4j.category.org.globus.replica=DEBUG
 ...
</screen>
<!-- TODO Add troubleshooting help for problems related to:
  1) invalid index url
  2) invalid registration url
  3) invalid rft url
  4) improperly formated request file
  5) system freeze
-->
</chapter>
</book>