<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
  <title>Globus Toolkit</title>
  <link>http://www-unix.globus.org/toolkit/</link>
  <description>Up-to-date links to new downloads and information for developers using the Globus Toolkit</description>
  <language>en-us</language>
  <image>
    <title>Globus Toolkit</title>
    <url>http://www-unix.globus.org/toolkit/images/gtLogo.jpg</url>    <link>http://www-unix.globus.org/toolkit/</link>
    <width>98</width>
    <height>96</height>
  </image>
<item>
  <pubDate>Thu,  5 May 2005 12:03:07 -0500</pubDate>
  <title>Sun Grid Engine integration packages now available for GT4</title>
  <description>
          In a collaboration between the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lesc.ic.ac.uk/projects/SGE-GT4.html&quot;&gt;London e-Science Centre&lt;/a&gt; (as a member of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.grids.ac.uk/ETF/index.shtml&quot;&gt;UK Grid Engineering Taskforce&lt;/a&gt;), &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gridwisetech.com/?page=15&quot;&gt;Gridwise&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mcnc-gcns.org/&quot;&gt;MCNC&lt;/a&gt;, Sun Grid Engine 6 has been integrated with GT4.</description>
  <link>http://www-unix.globus.org/toolkit/news.html#9</link>
</item>
<item>
  <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2005 23:59:01 -0500</pubDate>
  <title>Handle System - GT Integration Project kick-off</title>
  <description>
          Coinciding with the GT 4.0 release, a collaborative project between CNRI and the Globus Alliance has been launched.  The goal of the project is to leverage CNRI's sophisticated Handle System (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.handle.net&quot;&gt;www.handle.net&lt;/a&gt;) for identifier and resolution services through a tight integration with GT4's Web services protocols.  Please visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://hdl.handle.net/4263537/5018&quot;&gt;this page&lt;/a&gt; to learn more and download demo code.</description>
  <link>http://www-unix.globus.org/toolkit/news.html#8</link>
</item>
<item>
  <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2005 23:59:00 -0500</pubDate>
  <title>The GT 4.0.0 release is now available for download!</title>
  <description>
Version 4.0 of the Globus Toolkit (GT4) is now available for download.  4.0 is the newest stable release of GT and represents a major advance in toolkit quality.  Highlights of this release include:

&lt;ul&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;Full-featured, state-of-the-art Web service hosting environments for Java, Python and C&lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;Tools and libraries for the development of WSRF and WS compliant client and server applications&lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;An improved WSS-compliant security infrastructure with an extensible authorization framework&lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;A new GRAM implementation optimized for flexibility, stability and scalability&lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;A new and improved GridFTP server&lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;Significant stability and scalability improvements in RFT, RLS and GRAM&lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;An updated version of OGSA-DAI that allows access to data via WSRF mechanisms&lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;Improved Information Services infrastructure&lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;Improved and extended documentation&lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;Several usability improvements, including better error reporting and installer enhancements&lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;Enhanced cross-platform support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other important details:
&lt;ul&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;GT4 includes a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www-unix.globus.org/toolkit/docs/4.0/Usage_Stats.html&quot;&gt;mechanism to collect usage statistics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;This release is covered by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www-unix.globus.org/toolkit/license.html&quot;&gt;an Apache-derived open source license&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;The GT website has also been updated with a new look &amp; feel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
  <link>http://www-unix.globus.org/toolkit/news.html#7</link>
</item>
<item>
  <pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2005 15:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
  <title>GT 3.9.5 (the GT4 beta release) is now available</title>
  <description>&lt;p&gt;
The Beta release of Globus Toolkit 4.0 is now available for download. This release is a key milestone in the GT4 development cycle, as the public interfaces included in the distribution will not change for 4.0. Highlights of this release include:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A WSRF port of OGSA-DAI
  &lt;li&gt;A mechanism to collect usage statistics
  &lt;li&gt;Stability and performance improvements
  &lt;li&gt;Improved cross-platform support
  &lt;li&gt;Further documentation refinements
  &lt;li&gt;Improved installer interface
  &lt;li&gt;Important bug fixes
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Relevant links for this release include:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Software &lt;a href=&quot;http://www-unix.globus.org/toolkit/downloads/development/&quot;&gt;http://www-unix.globus.org/toolkit/downloads/development/&lt;/a&gt;
 (or CVS tag &quot;globus_3_9_5&quot;)
&lt;li&gt;Release Notes
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www-unix.globus.org/toolkit/docs/development/3.9.5/release_notes.html&quot;&gt;http://www-unix.globus.org/toolkit/docs/development/3.9.5/release_notes.html&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documentation
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www-unix.globus.org/toolkit/docs/development/3.9.5/&quot;&gt;http://www-unix.globus.org/toolkit/docs/development/3.9.5/&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
This release represents a significant step toward our goal of improving the quality of the toolkit. Please try 3.9.5 and tell us what you think!
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
  <link>http://www-unix.globus.org/toolkit/news.html#1</link>
</item>
<item>
  <pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2004 20:04:08 -0600</pubDate>
  <title>GT 3.9.4 (a GT4 alpha release) is now available</title>
  <description>A new development release of the Globus Toolkit is now available for download. This release includes the full set of core GT components scheduled for 4.0 Final. Highlights include:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A new C client for WS GRAM
&lt;li&gt;A first look at our C WSRF implementation
&lt;li&gt;Significant performance enhancements for all WS-based technology
&lt;li&gt;Several performance improvements in our new GridFTP server
&lt;li&gt;An improved installer interface
&lt;li&gt;Improved documentation
&lt;li&gt;Important bug fixes
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Relevant links for this release include:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Software
 http://www-unix.globus.org/toolkit/downloads/development/ (or CVS tag &quot;globus_3_9_4&quot;)
&lt;li&gt;Release Notes
 http://www-unix.globus.org/toolkit/docs/development/3.9.4/release_notes.html
&lt;li&gt;Documentation
 http://www-unix.globus.org/toolkit/docs/development/3.9.4/
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The 3.9.4 release marks an important milestone, as it represents closure of the &quot;feature addition&quot; phase of the GT4 development cycle. We now enter a period in which the sole focus of GT4 developers is to test and refine the performance and reliability of GT4 code. In fact, this testing phase began with the 3.9.3 release, as many individual components reached feature-completeness. We heartily thank those in the community who have been testing 3.9.3! Your feedback has been invaluable and has lead to many of the improvements included in today's release.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Early studies of 3.9.3 revealed significant performance problems with the Java WS components. Happily, today's release includes improvements in performance that, for some components, approach an order of magnitude. Nevertheless, there is still much work to do before reaching the quality standards we've set for GT4. Based on our experience with 3.9.3, it has become clear that we cannot keep to the original GT4 release schedule and also meet the quality characteristics demanded by the community.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
And so in order to allow more time for performance, stability and other usability improvements, the Globus Alliance is extending the GT4 testing cycle. The new target date for 4.0 Final and near-term release schedule is as follows:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
17 December 2004 - GT4 Alpha development release (3.9.4) that includes the full set of core GT components, as well as significant performance and usability improvements. Available for download now!
31 January 2005 - GT4 Alpha development release (3.9.5)
March 2005 - GT4 Beta development release (3.9.6) to contain the final set of public interfaces for 4.0
April 2005 - GT 4.0 Final
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Though we are confident that the new schedule is realistic, it should be noted that these dates are subject to change if serious problems of function or performance are uncovered during testing. The bottom line is that the Globus Alliance is committed to delivering a 4.0 Final that performs well and is robust. 3.9.4 represents a good step toward that goal. Please do try it and tell us what you think.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
  <link>http://www-unix.globus.org/toolkit/news.html#3</link>
</item>
<item>
  <pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2004 19:43:16 -0500</pubDate>
  <title>GT 3.9.3 (a GT4 alpha release) is now available</title>
  <description>&lt;p&gt;
A new alpha-quality development release of the Globus Toolkit is now available for download. Highlights include:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
FEATURE-FROZEN COMPONENTS
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Java WS Core (API and tools for building WS-I compliant, stateful web services; includes support for tomcat) 
&lt;li&gt;Community Authorization Service (CAS) 
&lt;li&gt;Delegation Service (a new GT web service providing an interface for delegation of credentials to a host) 
&lt;li&gt;Pre-WS Authentication and Authorization (GSI for Pre-WS components) 
&lt;li&gt;Credential Management (including MyProxy and SimpleCA) 
&lt;li&gt;Reliable File Transfer (RFT) 
&lt;li&gt;GridFTP (featuring the new server implementation; includes support for striping) 
&lt;li&gt;Replica Location Service (RLS) 
&lt;li&gt;Pre-WS GRAM 
&lt;li&gt;Pre-WS MDS (MDS2) 
&lt;li&gt;WS MDS (MDS4) 
&lt;li&gt;XIO
&lt;/ul&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;
NEARLY FEATURE-FROZEN COMPONENTS
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WS Authentication and Authorization (includes Java message and transport-level security and a WS authorization framework) 
&lt;li&gt;WS GRAM (improved server design with near-frozen public interfaces; multi-job support; interim java client) 
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Please note that another development release will follow shortly and will include the remaining features targeted for 4.0 Final:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;C WS Core (basic toolset in C for creating stateful web services) 
&lt;li&gt;C WS Authentication and Authorization support 
&lt;li&gt;C WS GRAM client 
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Relevant links for the 3.9.3 distribution:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Software: http://www-unix.globus.org/toolkit/downloads/development/ 
&lt;li&gt;Documentation: http://www-unix.globus.org/toolkit/docs/development/3.9.3/ 
&lt;li&gt;Calls for Community Testing: http://www-unix.globus.org/toolkit/testing/calls/ 
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
In production settings, users should continue to use one of the two officially supported stable releases (GT 3.2 is recommended.) More information on stable and development releases can be found at http://www-unix.globus.org/toolkit/versioning.html 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
If you are interested in participating in discussions related to GT4 development activities such as testing or documentation, please join the gt4-friends mailing list. To subscribe to the list, send mail to majordomo@globus.org with the words
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&quot;subscribe gt4-friends&quot;
&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;
in the message body.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Thank you for your support of Globus Toolkit development!
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
  <link>http://www-unix.globus.org/toolkit/news.html#2</link>
</item>
<item>
  <pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2004 13:57:23 -0500</pubDate>
  <title>GT 3.9.2 (a GT4 alpha release) is now available</title>
  <description>&lt;p&gt;
A new development release of the Globus Toolkit is now available 
for download. Highlights of the 3.9.2 release include: Alpha-quality 
previews of familiar GT services ported to WSRF (RFT, GRAM, MDS) 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Improvements to our Java WS Core component
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
A new C WS Core component
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
A new Python WS Core component (contribution from LBNL)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Improvements to our new GridFTP server, including support for 
striping
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
  <link>http://www-unix.globus.org/toolkit/news.html#5</link>
</item>
<item>
  <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2004 13:55:19 -0500</pubDate>
  <title>Globus Toolkit 3.2.1</title>
  <description>A new incremental release, Globus Toolkit 3.2.1, is now available 
for download. This is now the latest stable release of the Globus 
Toolkit. </description>
  <link>http://www-unix.globus.org/toolkit/news.html#4</link>
</item>
  </channel>
</rss>
