<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd"
[

<!ENTITY % xinclude SYSTEM "../../xinclude.mod" >
%xinclude;

]>
<book id="gridftpKey">
  <title>GT <replaceable role="entity">version</replaceable> GridFTP Key Concepts</title>
  <titleabbrev>GridFTP Key Concepts</titleabbrev> 

  <bookinfo id="gridftp-key-overview"><abstract><title>Overview</title>
<para>One of the foundational issues in HPC computing is the ability to move
large (multi Gigabyte, and even Terabyte), file-based data sets between sites.
Simple file transfer mechanisms such as FTP and SCP are not sufficient either
from a reliability or performance perspective. GridFTP extends the standard FTP
protocol to provide a high-performance, secure, reliable protocol for bulk data
transfer.</para></abstract>
</bookinfo>

  <chapter id="gridftp-key-advantages"><title>GridFTP Protocol</title>
<!-- 
  If you are not familiar with FTP in general, it might be a good idea to browse
  relevant definitions [fixme here - olink to glossary].
  -->

<para>
GridFTP is a protocol defined by Global Grid Forum Recommendation GFD.020,
  RFC 959, RFC 2228, RFC 2389, and a draft before the IETF FTP working group. Key
  features include:
<itemizedlist>
  <listitem><simpara>Performance - GridFTP protocol supports using parallel TCP
  streams and multi-node transfers to achieve high
  performance.</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara>
  Checkpointing - GridFTP protocol requires that the server send restart markers
  (checkpoint) to the client.
  </simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara>
  Third-party transfers - The FTP protocol on which GridFTP is based separates control and data channels, enabling third-party transfers, that is, the transfer of data between two end hosts, mediated by a third host.
  </simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara>
  Security - Provides strong security on both control and data channels. Control
  channel is encrypted by default. Data channel is authenticated by default with
  optional integrity protection and encryption. 
  </simpara></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
  </para>
</chapter>

  <chapter id="globus-gridftp"><title>Globus Implementation of GridFTP</title>
  The GridFTP protocol provides for the secure, robust, fast and efficient transfer
  of (especially bulk) data. The Globus Toolkit provides the most commonly used
  implementation of that protocol, though others do exist (primarily tied to
  proprietary internal systems). </para>
<para>The Globus Toolkit provides:</para>
<itemizedlist>
  <listitem><simpara>a server implementation
          called <computeroutput>globus-gridftp-server</computeroutput>,</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara> a scriptable command line client called <computeroutput>globus-url-copy</computeroutput>, and</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara>a set of development libraries for custom clients. </simpara></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
<para>While the Globus
  Toolkit does not provide an interactive client, the <olink targetdoc="gridftpUser">GridFTP
            User's Guide</olink> does provide
            information on at least one interactive client developed by other
            projects.</para>
<para>If you wish to make data available to others, you need to install a
  server on a host that can access that data and make sure that there is an appropriate
  Data Storage Interface (DSI) available for the storage system holding the data.
  This typically means a standard POSIX file system, but DSIs do exist for the
  Storage Resource Broker (SRB), the High Performance Storage System (HPSS),
  and NeST from the Condor team at the University of Wisconsin &ndash; Madison.
  A complete list of DSIs is available [fixme here]. If you need an interface to a
  storage system not listed here, please contact us. While we certainly cannot
  offer to write DSIs for every storage system, we can assist in the development,
  or if a broad enough community can be identified that uses the system, we may
be able to obtain joint funding to develop the necessary interface.</para>
<para>If you simply wish to access data that others have made available, you need
  a GridFTP client. The Globus Toolkit provides a client called <computeroutput>globus-url-copy</computeroutput>  for this purpose. This client is capable of accessing data via a range of protocols
  (http, https, ftp, gsiftp, and file). As noted above this is not an interactive
  client, but a command line interface, suitable for scripting. For example,
the following command:</para>
<screen>globus-url-copy gsiftp://remote.host.edu/path/to/file file:///path/on/local/host</screen>
<para>would transfer a file from a remote host to the locally accessible path specified
in the second URL.</para>
<para>Finally, if you wish to add access to files stored behind GridFTP servers,
  or you need custom client functionality, you can use our very powerful client
library to develop custom client functionality.</para>
<para>
  For more information about GridFTP, see:</para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem><simpara>the <olink targetdoc="gridftp">documentation</olink>.</simpara></listitem>
    <listitem><simpara><ulink url="http://www.globus.org/alliance/publications/papers/gridftp_final.pdf">The Globus Striped GridFTP Framework and Server</ulink></simpara></listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  
</chapter>


  <glossary role="auto" id="glossary-gridftpKey">
    <!-- 
    <remark>some terms not in the docs but wanted in glossary: 
    <glossterm>scheduler</glossterm>
    </remark>
    -->
    <glossdiv><title>A</title>
      <glossentry>
        <glossterm>Dummy term</glossterm>
        <glossdef>
          <para>This is a dummy entry for the automatic glossary database. Do not edit.</para>
        </glossdef>
      </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
  </glossary>
</book>
