<section><title>Service configuration files</title>
<para>The service configuration files such as the JNDI configuration file,<computeroutput>jndi-config.xml</computeroutput>,
and the Web service deployment descriptor, <computeroutput>server-config.wsdd</computeroutput>, located in the 
<computeroutput>$GLOBUS_LOCATION/etc/globus_wsrf_replicator</computeroutput> directory, contain sensitive information 
such as database username and password. It is important to ensure that these files are readable 
only by the system administrator that is responsible for the container. During deployment, the 
permissions on these files are adjusted automatically, however, you should verify the permissions 
to ensure that they have been correctly set for your specific platform.</para>

</section>
<section><title>Database information</title>
<para>Critical information is maintained in the DRS database, including the replication request and 
all associated filenames, the endpoint reference to the delegated credential in the delegation service, 
and the username and user subject for each requester. It is important that the user employ appropriate 
security measures to ensure the integrity and confidentiality of information maintained in your chosen 
database server. These steps may include granting limited permissions to other users of the database 
server, and ensuring that the database server encrypts its user passwords.</para>

</section>
<section><title>Delegated proxy credential files</title>
<para>Creating a Replicator requires that the user supply a delegated credential to the DRS 
during the initial creation request. The service retrieves the delegated credential from the 
Delegation Service and stores it on the file system. As part of the DRS configuration (see 
installation and configuration instructions), the user selects a directory to use for storage of
delegated credentials. The default setting is for the DRS to store the file in the system's 
designated temporary directory (e.g., <computeroutput>/tmp</computeroutput> on many platforms). The service sets the
permissions on the temporary file such that it can only be accessed by the user account used to
run the container.</para>
</section>




