
<glossdiv><title>B</title>
            <glossentry id="bloom-filter">
                  <glossterm> Bloom filter</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para> Compression scheme used by the Replica Location Service (RLS) that is
                              intended to reduce the size of soft state updates between Local
                              Replica Catalogs (LRCs) and Replica Location Index (RLI) servers. A
                              Bloom filter is a bit map that summarizes the contents of a Local
                              Replica Catalog (LRC). An LRC constructs the bit map by applying a
                              series of hash functions to each logical name registered in the LRC
                              and setting the corresponding bits.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            
</glossdiv>

 

            <glossdiv><title>L</title>
            <glossentry id="lrc">
                  <glossterm>Local Replica Catalog (LRC)</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para> Stores mappings between logical names for data items and the target
                              names (often the physical locations) of replicas of those items.
                              Clients query the LRC to discover replicas associated with a logical
                              name. Also may associate attributes with logical or target names. Each
                              LRC periodically sends information about its logical name mappings to
                              one or more RLIs. </para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="logical-file-name">
                  <glossterm>logical file name</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para> A unique identifier for the contents of a file.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="logical-name">
                  <glossterm>logical name</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para> A unique identifier for the contents of a data item.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            </glossdiv>


            
            <glossdiv><title>P</title>

            <glossentry id="physical-file-name">
                  <glossterm>physical file name</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para> The address or the location of a copy of a file on a storage system.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>

            </glossdiv>
 
            <glossdiv><title>R</title>
            <glossentry id="rli">
                  <glossterm>Replica Location Index (RLI)</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para> Collects information about the logical name mappings stored in one or
                              more Local Replica Catalogs (LRCs) and answers queries about those
                              mappings. Each RLI periodically receives updates from one or more LRCs
                              that summarize their contents.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="rls">
                  <glossterm>Replica Location Service (RLS)</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para> A distributed registry that keeps track of where replicas exist on
                              physical storage systems. The job of the RLS is to maintain
                              associations, or mappings, between logical names for data objects and
                              one or more target or physical names for replicas. Users or services
                              register data items in the RLS and query RLS servers to find replicas.
                              (RLS) </para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="rls-attribute">
                  <glossterm>RLS attribute</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para> Descriptive information that may be associated with a logical or
                              target name mapping registered in a Local Replica Catalog (LRC).
                              Clients can query the LRC to discover logical names or target names
                              that have specified RLS attributes.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            </glossdiv>

  
    <glossdiv> <title>T</title>       

            <glossentry id="target-name">
                  <glossterm>target name</glossterm>
                  <glossdef>
                        <para> The address or location of a copy of a data item on a storage system.</para>
                  </glossdef>
            </glossentry>


      </glossdiv>
