<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd"
[

<!ENTITY % xinclude SYSTEM "../../../../xinclude.mod" >
%xinclude;


]>
<book id="clientrepAdmin">
<title>GT <replaceable role="entity">version</replaceable> Replication Client: System Administrator's Guide</title>
<titleabbrev>System Administrator's Guide</titleabbrev>

<bookinfo><abstract><title>Introduction</title>
<para>This guide contains advanced configuration information for system administrators
  working with the Replication Client. It provides references to information on procedures
  typically performed by system administrators, including installing, configuring,
 deploying, and testing the installation.</para>
<para> <important>
  <simpara> This information is in addition to the basic Globus Toolkit prerequisite, 
   overview, installation, security configuration instructions in the <olink targetdoc="gtadmin"/>.  
   Read through this guide before continuing!</simpara>  
 </important></para></abstract>
</bookinfo>


<chapter id="clientrep-admin-installing"><title>Building and installing</title>
    <para>Replication Client is distributed with the Globus Toolkit <replaceable role="entity">version</replaceable> and is available in both the binary bundles and the source bundle. For most purposes, the binary bundle provides the simplest means of installing the Replication Client and its dependencies. The GT make target for this component is <computeroutput>gt4-replication-client</computeroutput> and for tests <computeroutput>gt4-replication-client-test</computeroutput>. The make target is incuded in <computeroutput>all</computeroutput>. Basic installation steps:</para>
    <screen>
% ./configure --prefix=$GLOBUS_LOCATION
% make <emphasis>[all | gt4-replication-client]</emphasis>
% make install
    </screen>
</chapter>

    <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
        href="../Clientrep_Interface_Config_Frag.xml"/>

<chapter id="clientrep-admin-deploying"><title>Deploying</title>
<para>There are no additional steps for deploying. The Replication Client is a client-side tool. In order to use the client a Globus Replica Location Service (RLS) and a Globus GridFTP Server (GridFTP Server) must be accessible.</para>
</chapter>

<chapter id="clientrep-admin-testing"><title>Testing</title>
    <para>You must start a GridFTP Server on port 9001 of the local host. Note that GridFTP Server normally runs as the root user. See GridFTP for more details. If GridFTP Server is running on the local host on port 9001, run the following script.</para>
    <screen>
% $GLOBUS_LOCATION/test/globus_replica_replication_test_unit/TEST.pl
    </screen>
    <para>The above test performs unit testing of the replication client java API. If the command indicates errors or failures, check the web page in the directory as specified by the script for more details.</para>
    <para>Next, run the following script to unit test the globus-replication-client command-line client.</para>
    <screen>
% $GLOBUS_LOCATION/test/globus_replica_replication_test_client/TEST.pl > test-output.html
    </screen>
    <para>To view the output of the client tests, open the html file which you directed the test&singlequot;s output too.
</chapter>

<chapter id="clientrep-admin-security-considerations"><title>Security considerations</title>
    <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
        href="../Clientrep_Security_Considerations_Frag.xml"/>
</chapter>

<chapter id="clientrep-admin-debugging">
    <title>Debugging</title>
    <indexterm type="clientrep"><primary>logging</primary></indexterm>
<para>fixme</para>
</chapter>
    
    
<chapter id="clientrep-admin-troubleshooting"><title>Troubleshooting</title>
<para>For a list of common errors in GT, 
        see <olink targetdoc="gtuser" targetptr="errors"/>.</para>
<xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
        href="../Clientrep_Errors_Frag.xml"/>

</chapter>
    <index type="clientrep">
    <title>Index</title>
</index>
</book>
