<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<title>GT &shortversion; Index Service: System Administrator's Guide</title>
<titleabbrev>System Administrator's Guide</titleabbrev>

<section id="index-admin-introduction"><title>Introduction</title>
<para>This guide contains advanced configuration information for
system administrators working with the WS MDS Index Service. It
provides references to information on procedures typically
performed by system administrators, including installation,
configuring, deploying, and testing the installation.</para>
<para><important><simpara>This information is in addition to the basic Globus Toolkit
prerequisite, overview, installation, security configuration
    instructions in the <xref linkend="gtadmin"/>.
Read through this guide before continuing!</simpara></important></para>
</section>
<section id="index-admin-installing"><title>Building and
Installing</title>
<para>The Index Service is built and installed as part of a default GT
    &shortversion; installation. For basic installation instructions, see <xref linkend="gtadmin"/>. No extra installation steps are required for this
component.</para>
</section>
<section id="index-admin-configuring"><title>Configuring</title>
    <!-- not valid if i put note after frag... -->
    <note>
        <para>The aggregation source used to collect data can be changed from
            default, as detailed in the "Defining the Aggregator Sources" section below.</para></note>
    
&WS_MDS_Index_Interface_Config_Frag;

</section>
<section id="index-admin-deploying"><title>Deploying</title>
    <para>The Index Service is deployed into the Globus container by
    default during the <link linkend="gtadmin">standard
toolkit installation</link>.</para>
<section id="index-admin-deploying-tomcat"><title>Deploying into Tomcat</title>
    <para> The WS MDS Index Service has been tested to work without any additional setup when deployed into Tomcat. Please follow these <xref linkend="javawscore-admin-tomcat-deploying"/> to deploy GT4 services into Tomcat. Note: please complete any prerequisite service configuration steps before you deploy into Tomcat.</para>
</section>
</section>
<section id="index-admin-testing"><title>Testing</title>
<para>The entire content of the default index service in a deployment
can be seen by executing the following command, which will dump the
entire RP set of the service:</para>
<screen>wsrf-query -a -z none -s https://127.0.0.1:8443/wsrf/services/DefaultIndexService/</screen>
</section>
<section id="index-admin-security_considerations"><title>
Security Considerations</title>
&WS_MDS_Index_Security_Considerations_Frag;
</section>
<section id="index-admin-troubleshooting"><title>
Troubleshooting</title>
<para><emphasis>Problem: An index service entry has AggregatorConfig data but an empty
AggregatorData entry.</emphasis></para> 
    
    <para>Solution: There is probably something wrong with the
registration. For example, a registration that uses
    QueryAggregatorSource <glossterm>aggregator source</glossterm> may have incorrect values
for the resource's hostname or port number or a misspelled resource
property name, or the remote resource may impose security
restrictions that prevent the queries from the index from working.
You can use the standard toolkit resource property query tools
        (such as <xref linkend="wsrf-get-properties"/>) to verify that the
remote resource is responding.</para>

</section>

<section id="index-admin-usage"><title>Usage statistics collection by the Globus Alliance</title>
    &WS_MDS_Usage_Statistics_Frag;
</section>