<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">

<section id="myproxy-env-var"><title>Environmental variables for MyProxy</title>
<table><title>Environment variables</title>
<tgroup cols="2"><tbody>
<row><entry>   MYPROXY_SERVER</entry>
<entry>          Specifies  the  hostname where the <command>myproxy-server</command> is running.
              This environment variable can be used in place of the <option>-s</option> option.</entry>
</row>

<row><entry>   MYPROXY_SERVER_PORT</entry>
<entry>          Specifies the port where the <command>myproxy-server</command> is running.  This
              environment variable can be used in place of the <option>-p</option> option.</entry>
</row>

<row><entry>   MYPROXY_SERVER_DN</entry>
<entry>         Specifies the distinguished name (DN) of the  <command>myproxy-server</command>.
              All  MyProxy client programs authenticate the server's identity.
              By default, MyProxy servers run with host  credentials,  so  the
              MyProxy  client  programs  expect  the  server to have a distinguished
  name of the form  "host/&lt;fqhn&gt;"  or  "myproxy/&lt;fqhn&gt;"
              (where  &lt;fqhn&gt;  is  the fully-qualified hostname of the server).
              If the server is running with some other DN, you  can  set  this
              environment  variable  to tell the MyProxy clients to accept the
              alternative DN.</entry>
</row>

<row><entry>   X509_USER_CERT</entry>
<entry>          Specifies a non-standard location for the certificate from which
              the <glossterm baseform="proxy credentials">proxy credential</glossterm> is created by <command>myproxy-init</command>.
              It also specifies  an alternative location for the server's certificate.
              By default, the server uses <filename>/etc/grid-security/hostcert.pem</filename> when
              running  as  root or <filename>~/.globus/usercert.pem</filename> when running as non-root.</entry>
</row>

<row><entry>   X509_USER_KEY</entry>
              <entry>          Specifies a non-standard location for the <glossterm>private key</glossterm> from which
              the proxy credential is created by <command>myproxy-init</command>.
              It also specifies an alternative location for the server's private  key.
              By  default the server uses <filename>/etc/grid-security/hostkey.pem</filename> when
              running as root or <filename>~/.globus/userkey.pem</filename> when  running  as  non-root.</entry>
</row>

<row><entry>   X509_USER_PROXY</entry>
<entry>          Specifies  an  alternative location for the server's certificate
              and private key (in the same file).  Use when running the server
              with  a  proxy  credential.  Note that the proxy will need to be
              periodically renewed before expiration  to  allow  the  <command>myproxy-server</command> to
              keep functioning. When the <command>myproxy-server</command> runs with
              a non-host credential, clients must have the  <envar>MYPROXY_SERVER_DN</envar>
              environment  variable  set to the distinguished name of the certificate
              being used by the server.</entry>
</row>

<row><entry>   GLOBUS_LOCATION</entry>
<entry>          Specifies the root of the MyProxy installation, used to find the
	default location of the <filename>myproxy-server.config</filename> file
              and the credential storage directory.</entry>
</row>

<row><entry>   LD_LIBRARY_PATH</entry>
<entry>          The  MyProxy  server is typically linked dynamically with Globus
              security  libraries,  which  must  be  present  in  the  dynamic
	      linker's  search  path.   This  typically requires <filename>$GLOBUS_LOCATION/lib</filename> to
              be included in the list in the <envar>LD_LIBRARY_PATH</envar> environment
              variable, which is set by the  <filename>$GLOBUS_LOCATION/libexec/globus-script-initializer</filename> script,
	      which should be called from any <command>myproxy-server</command> startup script.
              Alternatively, to set <envar>LD_LIBRARY_PATH</envar> appropriately
              for the Globus libraries in an interactive shell, source <filename>$GLOBUS_LOCATION/etc/globus-user-env.sh</filename>   (for   sh   shells)   or   <filename>$GLOBUS_LOCATION/etc/globus-user.env.csh</filename> (for csh shells).</entry>
</row>

<row><entry>GT_PROXY_MODE</entry>
<entry>
              Set to "old" to use the "legacy globus proxy" format.
              By default, MyProxy uses the RFC 3820 compliant proxy
              (also known as "proxy draft compliant") format.
              If <envar>GT_PROXY_MODE</envar> is set to "old", then
              myproxy-init will store a legacy proxy and
              myproxy-logon will retrieve a legacy proxy (if
              possible).  Note that if the repository contains a proxy
              certificate, rather than an end-entity certificate, the
              retrieved proxy will be of the same type as the stored
              proxy, regardless of the setting of this environment
              variable.</entry>
</row>

</tbody></tgroup>
</table>
</section>