<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="wsaajava-changessummary">
  <title>Summary of Changes in Java WS Security</title>
<indexterm type="waajava"><primary>changes summary</primary></indexterm>
  
<section id="waajava-changessummary">
  <title>Summary of Changes in message/transport-level security</title>

  <para>The following changes have occurred for Message/Transport-level
  Security since GT <replaceable role="entity">previousversion</replaceable> :</para>

  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>Added support for signing policy enforcement. Disabling the
      enforcement is provided directly by the CoG JGlobus library, <olink
      targetdoc="javacogAdmin"
      targetptr="javacog-admin-configuring-signing-policy"></olink>.</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para>The security descriptor framework, used to configure security
      properties for the security framework has been enhanced. Detailed
      information about the framework is provided at <olink
      targetdoc="wsaajavaDescriptor"
      targetptr="wsaajava-secdesc-introduction"></olink>.</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para>Java WS Authentication code honors environment variables to pick
      up credential to use as described <ulink
      url="http://bugzilla.mcs.anl.gov/globus/show_bug.cgi?id=4146">here</ulink>.</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para>Java WS Authentication code allows configuration of trust
      certificate in non-default location as described <ulink
      url="http://bugzilla.mcs.anl.gov/globus/show_bug.cgi?id=3843">here</ulink>.</para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
</section>
  
 <section id="authzframe-changessummary">
  <title>Summary of Changes in WS Authorization Framework</title>
<indexterm type="wsaajava"><primary>changes summary</primary></indexterm>
  <para>The server side authorization framework has been reworked to support
  attribute-based authorization. The APIs and framework have been enhanced to
  deal with a representation where each entity is identified by a bag of
  attributes.</para>

  <para>Also the default engine used for combining the individual Policy
  Decision Point(PDP) decision has been changed from a deny-override algorithm
  to a permit override scheme that looks for a chain of delegation of rights
  from the resource owner to the requestor.</para>

  <para>Refer <olink targetdoc="wsaajavaDeveloper"
  targetptr="wsaajava-developer-archdes"></olink> for detailed information
  on the architecture.</para>

  <important>
    <para>The WS authorization interfaces have been frozen as of the GT 4.1.2
    release.</para>
  </important>

  <note>
    <para>All the PDPs that were distributed with the previous version have
    been ported to new framework and are supported.</para>
  </note>

  <section>
    <title>Java WS Authorization Code reorganization <emphasis>[post 4.1.3
    only]</emphasis></title>

    <para>The Java WS server side authorization code has been moved to a
    separate moduled called <code>authorization</code>. The work was tracked
    as part of <ulink
      url="http://bugzilla.globus.org/bugzilla/show_bug.cgi?id=5559">Bug
    5559</ulink> and while this does not change any interface on the server side, it
    separates the code from the Java WS Core module.</para>

    <para>A migration guide, that outlines the changes needed for services
    that build on Java WS Core is provided <ulink
    url="http://dev.globus.org/wiki/Java_WS_Core/Independent_Java_Authz_Module">here</ulink>.</para>
  </section>
</section>
 
</section>