<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd"
[

<!ENTITY % myents SYSTEM "../../../entities">

%myents;

]>
<section>
<para>
The aggregator sources supplied with the toolkit collect information using resource
    property queries (query sources), subscription/notification (subscription sources), and execution of
   external programs (execution sources).
</para>

   <para>The aggregator sources supplied with the Globus Toolkit are listed in
      the following table.</para>
      
      <note><simpara>All aggregator sources listed in this
      table are in the <computeroutput>org.globus.mds.aggregator.impl</computeroutput>
      package, so for example the aggregator source listed as
      <computeroutput>QueryAggregatorSource</computeroutput> is actually
      <computeroutput>org.globus.mds.aggregator.impl.QueryAggregatorSource</computeroutput></simpara></note>
      
   <table><title>Standard aggregator sources</title>
      <tgroup cols="2">
         <thead>
            <row>
               <entry>Aggregator Source</entry>
               <entry>Description</entry>
            </row>
         </thead><tbody>
            <row>
               <entry>QueryAggregatorSource</entry>
               <entry><simpara>The query source collects information from a registered resource by using WS-Resource Properties polling mechanisms:</simpara>
                  <itemizedlist>
                     <listitem><simpara><constant>GetResourcePropertyPollType</constant>; requests a single Resource Property from the remote resource.</simpara></listitem>
                     <listitem><simpara><constant>GetMultipleResourcePropertiesPollType</constant>; requests multiple Resource Properties from the remote resource.</simpara></listitem>
                     <listitem><simpara><constant>QueryResourcePropertiesPollType</constant>; requests a query be executed against the Resource Property Set of the remote
                        resource.</simpara></listitem>
                  </itemizedlist>
                  <simpara>Polls are made periodically, with both the period and target Resource Properties specified in the registration message.</simpara></entry>
            </row>
            <row>
               <entry>SubscriptionAggregatorSource</entry>
               <entry>The subscription source collects information from a registered resource using WS-Notification mechanisms. Data is delivered when property values change, rather than
                  periodically.</entry>
            </row>
            <row>
               <entry>ExecutionAggregatorSource</entry>
               <entry>The execution source collects information about
                  (not necessarily from) a registered resource by execution of a
                  local executable, which is passed as input the identity of the
                  registered resource. Details of the interface between the execution
                  source and local executables are in <olink targetdoc="aggregatorSources" targetptr="aggregator-sources-execution"/>.</entry>
            </row>
         </tbody></tgroup>
   </table>
</section>