<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd"
[

<!ENTITY % myents SYSTEM "../../entities">

%myents;

]>
<book id="executionKey">
<title>Execution Management: Key Concepts</title>
<titleabbrev> Key Concepts</titleabbrev> 

<bookinfo id="execution-key-overview"><abstract><title>Overview</title>
<para>The Globus Toolkit provides both a suite of web services and a "pre-web services" Unix
  server suite to submit, monitor, and cancel jobs on Grid computing resources.
  Both systems are known under the moniker "GRAM", while "GRAM4" refers only
  to the web service implementation. Jobs are computational tasks that may perform
  input/output operations while running which affect the state of the computational
  resource and its associated file systems. In practice, such jobs may require
  coordinated staging of data into the resource prior to job execution and out
  of the resource following execution. Some users, particularly interactive ones,
  benefit from accessing output data files as the job is running. Monitoring
  consists of querying and subscribing for status information such as job state
changes. </para>
<para> Grid computing resources are typically operated under the control of a scheduler
  which implements allocation and prioritization policies while optimizing the
  execution of all submitted jobs for efficiency and performance. GRAM is not
  a resource scheduler, but rather a protocol engine for communicating with a
  range of different local resource schedulers using a standard message format. </para>
<para>For more detailed information about the concepts behind the software implementation,
  see <olink targetdoc="executionKey " targetptr="execution-approach"/>.</para></abstract>
</bookinfo>


<chapter id="execution-key-concepts"><title>Conceptual details</title>
<para>A number of concepts underly the purpose and motivation for GRAM. These concepts
are divided into broad categories below. </para>

<section><title>Targeted job types</title>
<para> GRAM is meant to address a range of jobs where arbitrary programs, reliable
  operation, stateful monitoring, credential management, and file staging are
  important. GRAM is not meant to serve as a "remote procedure call" (RPC) interface
  for applications not requiring many of these features, and furthermore its
  interface model and implementation may be too costly for such uses. The GRAM4
  service will become cheaper over time as the underlying web service technologies
  improve, but as with the older pre-web service GRAM, its protocols will always
  involve multiple round-trips to support these advanced features that are not
  required for simple RPC applications. </para>
  <para> The underlying WSRF core environment used for GRAM4 should also be considered
  as a direct application-hosting solution for lightweight, shared applications.
  In other words, if an application requires only modest input and output data
  transport in a stateless manner (all that matters is the result data or fault
  signal) and will be invoked many times, it may be a good candidate for exposure
  as an application-specific Web service.</para>
</section>
<section><title>Component architecture</title>
<para> Rather than consisting of a monolithic solution, GRAM is based on a component
  architecture at both the protocol and software implementation levels. This
  component approach serves as an ideal which shapes the implementation as well
  as the abstract design and features. </para>
<informaltable>
<tgroup cols="2"><tbody>
  <row><entry>GRAM service suite</entry>
  <entry>
    <para>Job management with GRAM makes use of multiple types of service: 
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Job management services represent, monitor, and control the overall
          job life cycle. These services are the job-management specific software
          provided by the GRAM solution.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>File transfer services support staging of files into and out of compute
          resources. GRAM makes use of these existing services rather than providing
          redundant solutions; GRAM4 has further refactored some file transfer
          mechanisms present in pre-web service GRAM.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Credential management services are used to control the delegation
          of rights among distributed elements of the GRAM architecture based
          on users' application requirements. Again, GRAM makes use of more general
          infrastructure rather than providing a redundant solution, and GRAM4
          has continued this refactoring to better separate credential management
          at the protocol level.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    </para>
  </entry>
</row>
  <row><entry>Service model</entry>
  <entry>
    <para>For GRAM4, the Globus Toolkit software development environment, and
      particularly WSRF core, is used to implement distributed communications
      and service state. For pre-web service GRAM, the "gatekeeper" daemon and
      GSI library are used for communications and service dispatch.</para>
  </entry>
</row>
  <row><entry>Scheduler adapters</entry>
  <entry>
    <para>A scripted plug-in architecture is provided by GRAM to enable extension
      with adapters to control a variety of local schedulers.</para>
  </entry>
</row>
</tbody></tgroup>
</informaltable>
</section>
<section><title>Security</title>
<informaltable>
<tgroup cols="2"><tbody>
  <row><entry>Secure operation</entry>
  <entry>
    <para>GRAM4 utilizes WSRF functionality to provide for authentication of job
      management requests as well as to protect job requests from malicious interference,
      while pre-web service GRAM uses GSI and secure sockets directly. The use
      of GRAM does not reduce the ability for system administrators to control
      access to their computing resources. The use of GRAM also does not reduce
      the safety of jobs users run on a given computing resource.</para>
  </entry>
</row>
  <row><entry>Local system protection domains</entry>
  <entry>
    <para>To protect users from each other, jobs are executed in appropriate local
      security contexts, e.g. under specific Unix user IDs based on details of
      the job request and authorization policies. Additionally, GRAM mechanisms
      used to interact with the local resource are design to minimize the privileges
      required and to minimize the risks of service malfunction or compromise.</para>
  </entry>
</row>
  <row><entry>Credential delegation and management</entry>
  <entry>
    <para>A client may delegate some of its rights to GRAM services in order to
      facilitate the above functions, e.g. rights for GRAM to access data on
      a remote storage element as part of the job execution. Additionally, the
      client may delegate rights for use by the job process itself. With pre-web
      service GRAM, these two uses of rights are inseparable, while GRAM4 provides
      separate control for each purpose (while still allowing rights to be shared
      if that is desired).</para>
  </entry>
</row>
  <row><entry>Audit</entry>
  <entry>
    <para>To assist with normal accounting functions as well as to further mitigate
      risks from abuse or malfunction, GRAM uses a range of audit and logging
      techniques to record a history of job submissions and critical system operations.</para>
  </entry>
</row>
</tbody></tgroup>
</informaltable>
</section>
<section><title>Job Management</title>
<informaltable>
<tgroup cols="2"><tbody>
  <row><entry>Reliable job submission</entry>
  <entry>
    <para>GRAM4 provides an "at most once" job submission semantics. A client
      is able to check for and possibly resubmit jobs, in order to account for
      transient communication errors without risk of running more than one copy
      of the job. Similarly, pre-web service GRAM provides a two-phase submission
      mechanism to submit and then commit a job to be run.</para>
  </entry>
</row>
  <row><entry>Job cancellation</entry>
  <entry>
    <para>While many jobs are allowed to run to their natural completion, GRAM provides
      a mechanism for clients to cancel (abort) their jobs at any point in the
      job life cycle.</para>
  </entry>
</row>
</tbody></tgroup>
</informaltable>
</section>
<section><title>Data Management</title>
<informaltable>
<tgroup cols="2"><tbody>
  <row><entry>Reliable data staging</entry>
  <entry>
    <para>GRAM4 provides for reliable, high-performance transfers of files between
      the compute resource and external (gridftp) data storage elements before
      and after the job execution. Pre-web service GRAM can also stage with gridftp
      systems but with less flexible reliable-transfer logic driving its requests.</para>
  </entry>
</row>
  <row><entry>Output monitoring</entry>
  <entry>
    <para>GRAM supports a mechanism for incrementally transferring output file contents
      from the computation resource while the job is running. GRAM4 uses a
      new mechanism to allow arbitrary numbers of files to be transferred in
      this fashion, while pre-web service GRAM only supports incremental transfer
      of the job's standard output and error streams.</para>
  </entry>
</row>
</tbody></tgroup>
</informaltable>
</section>
<section><title>Task coordination</title>
<informaltable>
<tgroup cols="2"><tbody>
  <row><entry>Parallel jobs</entry>
  <entry>
    <para>Some jobs are parallel, meaning that they consist of more than one simultaneous
      tasks. These tasks are often hosted on parallel computing hardware to provide
      increased computational throughput.</para>
  </entry>
</row>
  <row><entry>Task rendezvous</entry>
  <entry>
    <para>Some parallel programming environments, such as MPI, provide mechanisms
      for all tasks in a parallel computation to find out about each other: to
      know the number of peer tasks as well as possibly to exchange some information
      between tasks. Native parallel programming models often support this within
      the local job start mechanism.</para>
    <para>GRAM provides a mechanism for task rendezvous which job applications may
      use if they do not have another more appropriate solution. This mechanism
      may be used directly by application code or by intervening middleware libraries,
      e.g. libraries that are designed to present a simplified programming model
      to applications run via GRAM. GRAM does not require tasks to be coordinated,
      but addresses this requirement in order to facilitate a wider range of
      applications. The protocols and APIs used to support task rendezvous are
      different for GRAM4 and GRAM2.</para>
  </entry>
</row>
</tbody></tgroup>
</informaltable>
</section>
</chapter>

    <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
      href="GRAM4_Approach.xml"/>
</book>