<title>GT &shortversion; WS GRAM Approach</title>
<titleabbrev>GT &shortversion; WS GRAM Approach</titleabbrev> 

<section id="execution-approach-intro"><title>Introduction</title>

<para>

The WS GRAM software implements a solution to the job-management
problem described in <xref linkend="execution-key"/>, providing Web services interfaces
consistent with the WSRF model. This solution is specific to operating
systems following the Unix programming and security model.

</para>

</section>
<section id="execution-approach-approach"><title>Component architecture approach</title>

<para>
WS GRAM combines job-management services and local system adapters
  with other service components of GT &shortversion; in order to support job
execution with coordinated file staging.
</para>
  
  <figure id="WS_GRAM_components"><title>WS GRAM Components</title>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="execution/key/WS_GRAM_components.png" format="PNG" align="center"  contentwidth="5.5in"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
  </figure>

<section><title>WS GRAM</title>

<para>The heart of the WS GRAM service architecture is a set of Web
services designed to be hosted in the Globus Toolkit's WSRF core
hosting environment. Note, these services, described below, make use
of platform-specific callouts to other software components described
in the next section.</para>

<table><title>TITLE</title>
<tgroup cols="2"><tbody>

<row><entry>ManagedJob</entry>

<entry><para> Each submitted job is exposed as a distinct resource
qualifying the generic ManagedJob service. The service provides an
interface to monitor the status of the job or to terminate the job (by
terminating the ManagedJob resource).  The behavior of the service,
i.e. the local scheduler adapter implementation, is selected by the
specialized <emphasis>type</emphasis> of the resource.</para></entry>
</row>

<row><entry>ManagedJobFactory</entry>

<entry><para> Each compute element, as accessed through a local scheduler,
is exposed as a distinct resource qualifying the generic
ManagedJobFactory service. The service provides an interface to create
ManagedJob resources of the appropriate type in order to perform a job
in that local scheduler.</para></entry>
</row>

</tbody></tgroup>
</table>

</section>
<section><title>Major Protocol Steps</title>

<para>
The components in the WS GRAM solution are organized to support a
range of optional features that together address different usage
scenarios.  These scenarios are explored in depth in terms of protocol
exchanges in the Protocol Variations section. However, at a high level
we can consider the main client activities around a WS GRAM job to be
a partially ordered sequence.
</para>
  
  <figure id="WS_GRAM_functions"><title>WS GRAM Functions</title>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="execution/key/WS_GRAM_functions.png" format="PNG" align="center"  contentwidth="5.5in"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
  </figure>

</section>
<section><title>Creation of Job</title>
<para>
The main component of the WS GRAM service model is the ManagedJob
resource created by a ManagedJobFactory::createManagedJob invocation. A
meaningful WS GRAM client MUST create a job that will then go through
a life cycle where it eventually completes execution and the resource
is eventually destroyed (the core black-and-white nodes in the
high-level picture).
</para>

</section>
<section><title>Optional Staging Credentials</title>
<para>
Optionally, the client MAY request staging activities to occur before
or after the job. If these are requested in the create call, suitable
delegated credential EPRs MUST be passed in as part of the creation
input, meaning that delegation operations MUST be performed sometime
before createManagedJob when staging is enabled (the light-blue delegation
nodes in the high-level picture). Two credential fields must be
initialized: the staging and transfer credentials, which may refer to
distinct credentials or may both refer to the same credential.  The
staging credential gives WS GRAM the right to interact with the RFT
service, while the transfer credential gives RFT the right to interact
with GridFTP servers.
</para>

</section>
<section><title>Optional Job Credential</title>
<para>
Optionally, the client MAY request that a credential be stored into
the user account for use by the job process. When this is requested in
the create call, a suitable delegated credential EPR is passed as part
of the creation input. As for staging, the credential MUST have been
delegated before the job is created (the green nodes in the picture).
</para>

</section>
<section><title>Optional Credential Refresh</title>
<para>
Optionally, credentials delegated for use with staging, transfer, or
job processes may be refreshed using the Delegation service
interface. This operation may be performed on any valid Delegation
EPR (the blue/green striped node in the picture).
</para>

</section>
<section><title>Optional Hold of Cleanup for Streaming Output</title>
<para>
If the client wishes to directly access output files written by the
job (as opposed to waiting for the stage-out step to transfer files
from the job host), the client should request that the file cleanup
process be held until released. This gives the client an opportunity
to fetch all remaining/buffered data after the job completes but
before the output files are deleted. (See the pink nodes in the
high-level picture).
</para>
<para>
The cleanup hold and release are not necessary if the client will not
be accessing files that are scheduled for cleanup in the job request,
either because the client is not accessing any files or because the
files it is accessing will remain on the job host after ManagedJob
termination.
</para>

</section>
<section><title>ManagedJob Destruction</title>
<para>
Under nearly all circumstances, ManagedJob resources will be
eventually destroyed after job cleanup has completed. Clients may
hasten this step via an explicit destroy request or by manipulation of
the scheduled termination time. Most system administrators will set a
default and maximum ManagedJob linger time after which automatic
purging of completed ManagedJob resources will occur.
</para>

</section>
<section><title>Globus Toolkit Components used by WS GRAM</title>

<para>
<table><title>TITLE</title>
<tgroup cols="2"><tbody>

<row><entry>ReliableFileTransfer</entry>

<entry>
  <para>The ReliableFileTransfer (RFT) service of GT &shortversion; is invoked by the
WS GRAM services to effect file staging before and after job
computations.</para>

  <para>
The integration with RFT provides a much more robust file staging
manager than the ad-hoc solution present in previous versions of the
GRAM job manager logic. RFT has better support for retry, restart, and
fine-grained control of these capabilities. WS GRAM exposes the full
flexibility of the RFT request language in the job staging clauses of
the job submission language.
</para>
</entry>
</row>

<row><entry>GridFTP</entry>

<entry><para>GridFTP servers are required to access remote storage elements
as well as file systems accessible to the local compute elements that
may host the job. The ReliableFileTransfer Web service acts as a
so-called third-party client to the GridFTP servers in order to manage
transfers of data between remote storage elements and the compute
element file systems. It is not necessary that GridFTP be deployed on
the same host/node as the WS GRAM services, but staging will only be
possible to the subset of file systems that are shared by the GridFTP
server that is registered with the WS GRAM service. (REF TO
DEPLOY/CONFIG HERE) If no such server or shared file systems are
registered, staging is disallowed to that WS GRAM compute
element.</para>

<para>
GridFTP is also used to monitor the contents of files written by the
job during job execution. The standard GridFTP protocol is used by a
slightly unusual client to efficiently and reliably check the status
of files and incrementally fetch new content as the file grows. This
method supports "streaming" of file content from any file accessible
by GridFTP, rather than only the standard output and error files named
in the job request--the limitation of previous GRAM solutions. This
approach also simplifies failover and restart of streaming to multiple
clients.
</para>

<para>The integration with GridFTP replaces the legacy GASS (Globus
Access to Secondary Storage) data transfer protocol. This changeover
is advantageous both for greater performance and reliability of data
staging as well as to remove redundant software from the GRAM
codebase.
</para>
</entry>
</row>

<row><entry>Delegation</entry>

<entry>
  <para>The Delegation service of GT &shortversion; is used by clients to delegate
credentials into the correct hosting environment for use by WS GRAM
or RFT services.</para>

  <para>
The integration of the Delegation service replaces the implicit,
binding-level delegation of previous GRAM solutions with explicit
service operations. This change not only reduces the requirements on
client tooling for interoperability purposes, but also allows a new
separation of the life cycle of jobs and delegated credentials.
Credentials can now be shared between multiple short-lived jobs or
eliminated entirely on an application-by-application basis to make
desired performance and security tradeoffs. Meanwhile, for unique
situations WS GRAM retains the ability to refresh credentials for
long-lived jobs and gains an ability to designate different delegated
credentials for different parts of the job's life cycle.
</para>
</entry>
</row>

</tbody></tgroup>
</table>
</para>
</section>

<section><title>External Components used by WS GRAM</title>
<para>

<table><title>TITLE</title>
<tgroup cols="2"><tbody>

<row><entry>Local job scheduler</entry>

<entry><para>An optional local job scheduler is required in order to manage the
resources of the compute element. WS GRAM has the ability to spawn
simple time-sharing jobs using standard Unix <computeroutput>fork()</computeroutput> methods,
but most large-scale compute elements will be under the control of a
schedule such as PBS, LSF, Loadleveler, etc.</para></entry>
</row>

<row><entry>sudo</entry>

<entry><para>The de facto standard Unix <computeroutput>sudo</computeroutput> utility is used by
WS GRAM to gain access to target user accounts without requiring
WS GRAM to have general super-user privilege on the system. The sudo
command is used to execute WS GRAM adapter tools in the user account
context; these adapters perform the local system-specific operations
needed to initialize and run user jobs.</para>

<para>The <computeroutput>sudo</computeroutput> utility not only provides a simple way for
WS GRAM to run programs as other users without "root" privilege, but
it provides fine-grained controls for the system administrator to
restrict which user accounts are valid WS GRAM targets as well as
secure auditing of all operations requested by WS GRAM.

This mechanism replaces the root-privileged Gatekeeper component of
the Pre-WS GRAM service in order to avoid running an entire WSRF
hosting environment as root.  This change provides enhanced security,
at the expense of slightly more complicated deployment effort, and is
motivated by the relative increase in the size of the WS GRAM and WSRF
codebase as compared to the traditional Gatekeeper.</para>
</entry>
</row>
</tbody></tgroup>
</table>

</para>

</section>

<section><title>Internal Components used by WS GRAM</title>
<para>

<table><title>TITLE</title>
<tgroup cols="2"><tbody>

<row><entry><ulink url="&docpath;execution/wsgram/developer/internal-components.html#seg">Scheduler Event Generator</ulink></entry>

<entry><para>
The Scheduler Event Generator component program provides the job monitoring capability for the WS-GRAM service. Plugin modules provide an interface between the Scheduler Event Generator and local schedulers.
</para></entry>
</row>

  <row><entry><ulink url="&docpath;execution/wsgram/developer/internal-components.html#forkstarter">Fork Starter</ulink></entry>

<entry><para>
The Fork Starter program starts and monitors job processes for WS-GRAM services which do not a local scheduler. The starter executes the user application and then waits for it to terminate. It records the start time, termination time, and exit status of each process it starts. This information is used by a Scheduler Event Generator plugin for triggering job state changes.  
</para></entry>
</row>
</tbody></tgroup>
</table>

</para>

</section>
</section>

<section id="execution-approach-security"><title>Security model</title>


<section><title>Secure operations</title>

<para>WS GRAM utilizes secure Web service invocation, as provided by the
WSRF core of the Globus Toolkit, for all job-management and
file-management messages. This security provides for authentication of
clients, tamper-resistant messaging, and optional privacy of message
content.</para>

</section>
<section><title>Local system protection domains</title>

<para>User jobs are executed within Unix user accounts. WS GRAM
authentication mechanisms allow the administrator to control to which
local accounts a Grid-based client may submit jobs.  WS GRAM uses the
Unix <computeroutput>sudo</computeroutput> command to access user accounts after determining
that the client has the right to access the account. Additionally, the
administrator may use access and allocation policy controls in the
local scheduler to further restrict the access of specific clients and
Unix users to local computing resources.</para>

</section>
<section><title>Credential delegation and management</title>

<para>A client may optionally delegate some of its rights to WS GRAM and
related services in order to facilitate file staging. Additionally,
the client may delegate rights for use by the job process itself. If
no delegation is performed, staging is disallowed and the job will
have no ability to request privileged Grid operations.</para>

</section>
<section><title>Audit</title>

<para>WS GRAM provides three types of logging or auditing support:
<table><title>TITLE</title>
<tgroup cols="2"><tbody>

<row><entry>WSRF core message logging</entry>

<entry><para>Detailed logging of the underlying client messages may be logged
  if such logging is enabled in the container configuration.  <link linkend="javawscore-developer-debugging">See Java WS Core debugging doc</link>.
</para></entry>
</row>

<row><entry>WS GRAM custom logging</entry>

<entry><para>WS GRAM generates domain-specific logging information about job
  requests and exceptional conditions.  <link linkend="wsgram-developer-debugging">See WS GRAM debugging doc</link></para></entry>
</row>

<row><entry>Local scheduler logging</entry>

<entry><para>For systems using a local batch scheduler, all of the
accounting and logging facilities of that scheduler remain available
for the administrator to track jobs whether submitted through WS GRAM
or directly to the scheduler by local users.</para></entry>
</row>

<row><entry>Local system logging</entry>

<entry><para>The use of <computeroutput>sudo</computeroutput> for all operations against target user
accounts allows the administrator to log the low-level system
operations requested by WS GRAM using <computeroutput>sudo</computeroutput>'s native auditing
support.</para></entry>
</row>


</tbody></tgroup>
</table>
</para>
</section>
<section><title>Protocol Overview</title>

<para>
As depicted above, the WS GRAM protocol is centered around the
creation of a stateful ManagedJob resource using the ManagedJobFactory
createManagedJob() operation. A simple batch job may involve nothing more
than this initial client creation step, with all other job life cycle
steps occurring automatically in the server. A number of optional
protocol elements are available for more complex scenarios.
</para>

<table><title>TITLE</title>
<tgroup cols="2"><tbody>

<row><entry>DelegationFactory::requestSecurityToken</entry>

<entry><para> This (optional) step allows a client to delegate credentials
that will be required for correct operation of WS GRAM, RFT, or the
user's job process. Such credentials are only used when referenced in
the subsequent job request and under the condition that WS GRAM or RFT
is configured to make use of the DelegationFactory, respectively.
</para></entry>
</row>

<row><entry>Delegation::refresh</entry>

<entry><para> This (optional) step allows a client to update the credentials
already established for use with the previous requestSecurityToken step.
</para></entry>
</row>

<row><entry>ManagedJobFactory::getResourceProperty and getMultipleResourceProperties</entry>

<entry><para> These (optional) steps allow a client to retrieve information about the
scheduler and the jobs associated with a particular factory resource before or
after job creation.  The delegationFactoryEndpoint and
stagingDelegationFactoryEndpoint resource properties are two examples of
information that may need to be obtained before job creation.
</para></entry>
</row>

<row><entry>ManagedJobFactory::createManagedJob</entry>

<entry><para> This required step establishes the stateful ManagedJob
resource which implements the job processing described in the input
request.
</para></entry>
</row>

<row><entry>ManagedJob::release</entry>

<entry><para>This (optional) step allows the ManagedJob to continue through
a state in its life cycle where it was previously held or scheduled to
be held according to details of the original job request.
</para></entry>
</row>

<row><entry>ManagedJob::setTerminationTime</entry>

<entry><para> This (optional) step allows the client to reschedule automatic
termination to be different than was originally set during creation of
the ManagedJob resource.
</para></entry>
</row>

<row><entry>ManagedJob::destroy</entry>

<entry><para> This (optional) step allows the client to explicitly abort a
job and destroy the ManagedJob resource in the event that the
scheduled automatic termination time is not adequate. If the job has already
completed (i.e. is in the Done or Failed state), this will simply destroy the
resource associated with the job.  If the job has not completed, appropriate
steps will be taken to purge the job process from the scheduler and perform
clean up operations before setting the job state to Failed.
</para></entry>
</row>

<row><entry>ManagedJob::subscribe</entry>

<entry><para> This (optional) step allows a client to subscribe for
notifications of status (and particularly life cycle status) of the
ManagedJob resource. For responsiveness, it is possible to establish
an initial subscription in the createManagedJob() operation without an
additional round-trip communication to the newly created job.
</para></entry>
</row>

<row><entry>ManagedJob::getResourceProperty and getMultipleResourceProperties</entry>

<entry><para> These (optional) steps allow a client to query the status (and
particularly life cycle status) of the ManagedJob resource.
</para></entry>
</row>

</tbody></tgroup>
</table>
</section>
</section>


<section id="execution-approach-languages"><title>Job Description Languages</title>
	
</section>

<section id="execution-approach-arch"><title>WS GRAM software architecture</title>


<section><title>Overview</title>
  
  <figure id="WS_GRAM_software"><title>WS GRAM Software</title>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="execution/key/WS_GRAM_software.png" format="PNG" align="center"  contentwidth="5.5in"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
  </figure>

</section>
<section><title>ManagedJob Resource Life Cycle Logic</title>

<para>
The ManagedJob resource has a complex life cycle. The generic behavior
is depicted in the following flowchart as a partially ordered sequence
of processes and decision points. The status of the ManagedJob
resource, including its "job state" is set as a side-effect of this
control flow.  The processes in the flowchart do not all directly
correspond to client-visible job states.
</para>
  
  <figure id="WS_GRAM_lifecycle"><title>WS GRAM Lifecycle</title>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="execution/key/WS_GRAM_lifecycle.png" format="PNG" align="center"  contentwidth="5.5in"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
  </figure>

</section>
<section><title>Software for local system interaction</title>

<table><title>TITLE</title>
<tgroup cols="2"><tbody>

<row><entry>Scheduler adapters</entry>

<entry><para>Support to control each local scheduler is provided in the form of
adapter scripts in the Perl programming language, following the
proprietary GRAM adapter plugin API. These adapters implement the
system-specific submission, job exit detection, job cancellation, and (optionally) job
exit status determination processes.</para></entry>
</row>

<row><entry>gridmap_authorize_and_exec</entry>

<entry><para>The <computeroutput>gridmap_authorize_and_exec</computeroutput> tool is a default, but
optional, program that is invoked in the target user account as a
wrapper around WS GRAM operations in order to make a final safety
check for whether WS GRAM should be allowed to operate in that
account. This tool provides reasonable privilege limits to guard
against service compromise without requiring additional system
administrator efforts to manage user policies.</para></entry>
</row>

</tbody></tgroup>
</table>
</section>
</section>

<section id="execution-approach-protocol"><title>Protocol Variations</title>

<para>
From a protocol perspective, the longest latency WS GRAM submission
scenario involves credential delegation, staging before and after the
job, and an explicit hold handshake on file cleanup after the job. The
credential refresh feature of WS GRAM can be repeated any number of
times, so by longest sequence we mean the longest fixed sequence with
at most one credential delegation. Explicit termination is not
necessary with WS GRAM so we will not consider that case further.
</para>

<para>
To understand the following figures which illustrate the protocol
sequence: the arrows show communication, signalling, or causal links
between tiers in the architecture and the vertical span indicates
elapsed time (with the start time at the top of the diagram). Due to
unpredictable implementation delays, client and job-observed times are
not necessarily ordered with respect to the WS GRAM observed times and
the WS GRAM generated state notification messages. The diagrams show
one possible ordering but applications (and our measurement methods)
must tolerate other orderings as well.
</para>

<section><title>Minimal Protocol Sequence</title>

<para>
The simplest WS GRAM scenario involves a job that requires neither
delegated credentials nor staging and that makes use of the automatic
termination of resources to avoid an explicit termination request.  In
this case, we can measure the latency and throughput for job
submission and notification alone.
</para>
  
  <figure id="WS_GRAM_sequence_minimal"><title>WS GRAM Minimal Sequence</title>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="execution/key/WS_GRAM_sequence_minimal.png" format="PNG" align="center"  contentwidth="5.5in"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
  </figure>

<para>
Note: Any difference between this case and the same measurement points in
the full scenario must be due to the additional overhead of the
delegation and staging services on the front-end node?
</para>

</section>
<section><title>Non-staging Delegation Sequence</title>

<para>
A slightly longer form of job than the minimal sequence is to include
credential delegation for use by the job itself, without any staging
directives. This sequence is comparable in functionality to previous
GRAM releases where delegation was mandatory but staging could be
omitted as per the client's request.
</para>
  
  <figure id="WS_GRAM_sequence_delegonly"><title>Non-staging Delegation Sequence</title>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="execution/key/WS_GRAM_sequence_delegonly.png" format="PNG" align="center"  contentwidth="5.5in"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
  </figure>

</section>
<section><title>Non-staging Delegation Sequence with Hold</title>

<para>
An optional protocol sequence allows the cleanup state to be held in
order to allow a client to safely access output files via the GridFTP
server after the job has finished writing them and before the cleanup
step deletes them. This variant adds the cleanup hold handshake to the
previous scenario.
</para>
  
  <figure id="WS_GRAM_sequence_delegonly_hold"><title>Non-staging Delegation Sequence with Hold</title>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="execution/key/WS_GRAM_sequence_delegonly_hold.png" format="PNG" align="center"  contentwidth="5.5in"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
  </figure>

</section>

<section><title>Staging Sequence</title>

<para>
This staging sequence uses almost all of the protocol elements.
</para>
  
  <figure id="WS_GRAM_sequence_staging"><title>Staging Sequence</title>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="execution/key/WS_GRAM_sequence_staging.png" format="PNG" align="center"  contentwidth="5.5in"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
  </figure>

</section>

<section><title>Staging Sequence with Hold</title>

<para>
This staging sequence adds the cleanup hold handshake to the staging
example to represent a job that has staged files as well as "streamed"
output.
</para>

  <figure id="WS_GRAM_sequence_staging_hold"><title>Staging Sequence with Hold</title>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="execution/key/WS_GRAM_sequence_staging_hold.png" format="PNG" align="center"  contentwidth="5.5in"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
  </figure>

</section>
</section>


<section id="execution-approach-perf"><title>Performance and scalability</title>

<para>
There are several optional parts to the WS GRAM job workflow and
protocol. To understand the performance and scalability
characteristics of WS GRAM, we must consider variations where
different parts of the protocol are used or omitted.
</para>

<section><title>Basic Client-visible Latency Measurements</title>

<para>
We report average performance for #TRIALS submissions of each of the
three variant sequences described above, using an instrumented version
of the <computeroutput>globusrun-ws</computeroutput> client command-line tool. Each trial is
an independent run with no other client load on the test WS GRAM
server.
</para>

<para>
The columns in the figure correspond to the three scenarios described
above, and the horizontal bands correspond to the distinct phases of
the protocol.
</para>

<para>
<emphasis>NOTE: these charts currently just illustrate the visualization
technique using fictional measurements and do not represent measured
data!!</emphasis>
</para>
  
  <figure id="sequence-times"><title>Sequence times</title>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="execution/key/sequence-times.png" format="PNG" align="center"  contentwidth="5.5in"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
  </figure>
  
  <figure id="sequence-times-manual"><title>Sequence times (manual)</title>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="execution/key/sequence-times-manual.png" format="PNG" align="center"  contentwidth="5.5in"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
  </figure>

<para>
The chart on the left is automatically generated from data files and
therefore up to date with any experiments.  The chart on the right has
been hand-retouched from a snapshot, to color the phases with the same
coloring as in the sequence diagrams. Final release documents will
include only the retouched chart with consistent coloring.
</para>

<para>
<emphasis>NOTE: these charts currently just illustrate the visualization
technique using fictional measurements and do not represent measured
data!!</emphasis>
</para>

</section>
<section><title>Methodology</title>

<para>
We use an instrumented version of our command-line client tool to
submit one dummy job at a time and log each relevant protocol event
with a timestamp. For each of the above scenarios, the protocol events
are mapped to the appropriate life cycle boundary for comparison,
taking into account the presence or absence of optional protocol
sequences in each scenario.  The instrumented client measures the
initial time by generating a timestamp <emphasis>before</emphasis> issuing the first
operation request.
</para>

<para>
The times from one thousand (1000) independent trials are converted to
intervals relative to the initiating protocol event and then these
intervals are averaged for all trials.  The raw timestamped event logs
are preserved in case other analysis methods are preferred in the
future.
</para>

<table frame="all"><title>Mapping of protocol events to life cycle boundaries for each
testing scenario</title>
<tgroup cols="6" align="center" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
<colspec colname="c1"/>
<colspec colname="c2"/>
<colspec colname="c3"/>
<colspec colname="c4"/>
<colspec colname="c5"/>
<colspec colname="c6"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry morerows="1">Boundary</entry>
<entry namest="c2" nameend="c6" align="center">Scenario</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Minimal</entry>
<entry>Delegating</entry>
<entry>Delegating w/ Hold</entry>
<entry>Staging</entry>
<entry>Staging w/ Hold</entry>
</row>
</thead>

<tbody>
<row>
<entry>0. Sequence Initiated</entry>
<entry>createManagedJob() invoked</entry>
<entry namest="c3" nameend="c6">requestSecurityToken() invoked</entry>
</row>

<row>
<entry>1. Delegation complete</entry>

<entry namest="c2" nameend="c6">requestSecurityToken() returns</entry>
</row>

<row>
<entry>2. Creation complete</entry>
<entry namest="c2" nameend="c6">createManagedJob() returns</entry>
</row>

<row>
<entry>3. Submission complete</entry>
<entry>Pending state notified</entry>
<entry namest="c3" nameend="c6">StageIn state notified</entry>
</row>

<row>
<entry>4. StageIn/Setup complete</entry>
<entry namest="c2" nameend="c6">Pending state notified</entry>
</row>

<row>
<entry>5. Pending/Start complete</entry>
<entry namest="c2" nameend="c6">Active state notified</entry>
</row>

<row>
<entry>6. Execution complete</entry>
<entry>Done state notified</entry>
<entry>Cleanup state notified</entry>
<entry>CleanupHold state notified</entry>
<entry namest="c5" nameend="c6">StageOut state notified</entry>
</row>

<row>
<entry>7. StageOut complete</entry>
<entry namest="c2" nameend="c4">&nbsp;</entry>
<entry>Cleanup state notified</entry>
<entry>CleanupHold state notified</entry>
</row>

<row>
<entry>8. Hold complete</entry>
<entry namest="c2" nameend="c3">&nbsp;</entry>
<entry>Cleanup state notified</entry>
<entry>&nbsp;</entry>
<entry>Cleanup state notified</entry>
</row>

<row>
<entry>9. Cleanup complete</entry>
<entry>&nbsp;</entry>
<entry namest="c3" nameend="c6">Done state notified</entry>
</row>

</tbody></tgroup>
</table>

</section>

<section><title>Pipelined Measurements</title>

<para>
For these measurements, we repeat the trials with differing numbers of
concurrent (pipelined) submissions from a single client, using a
customized test client tool. This leads to a relatively steady-state
measurement condition with a parameterized amount of concurrent load
on the WS GRAM server.
</para>

</section>
<section><title>Throughput</title>

<para>
The submission rate is reported for varying levels of concurrency.
</para>

</section>
<section><title>Concurrency Limits</title>
<para>[TODO]</para>
</section>
</section>
