<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">

<chapter id="archive-howto-basic">
<title>GT <replaceable role="entity">version</replaceable> Archive Service: How to configure the Archive
Service to Poll information from an WS MDS Index Service</title>

<titleabbrev>Configuring the Archive Service for storing an example
RP</titleabbrev>

<!-- 
<para> This howto was written by <ulink
url="http://www.thecodefactory.org/neillm">Neill Miller</ulink> under
the guidance of <ulink
url="http://www-unix.mcs.anl.gov/~schopf/">Jennifer
Schopf</ulink>.</para>
 -->
<section id="archive-howto-intro"><title>Introduction</title>

<para>
This document is intended to help a user understand how to configure
the Archive Service to retrieve information published as RPs from the
WS MDS Index Service.  In the end, we'll have a running Archive Service
that periodically pulls RP information from a running Index Service,
which in turn stores the data to disk in a Xindice Database.  At any
time, the information stored in the Archive Service can be queried by
a command line too (mds-archive-query) over a specified date range.
These actions may represent some typical use cases of the Archive
Service.
</para>

<section><title>Configure the registration file</title>

<para>
The first step in configuring the Archive Service is to make sure that
the information that you'd like to archive is already present in the
Index Service.  If you have not yet configured your Information
Providers to publish the desired information into the Index Service,
you should read the Index Service documentation, as that is outside
the scope of this document.  This document does cover an RP that
should always be present in the Index Service for the sake of
example.  Once you understand how to do what this document explains,
you should be able to trivially change the RP to any one of your
choosing (including custom RPs for your virtual organization).
</para>

<para>
Given that the above has been sorted out and your Information
Providers are configured, start the WS container.  For this example,
no external Information Providers need to be configured.
</para>

<para>
Knowing which RPs in the Index Service contain the desired data, the
next step of the Archive Service configuration is to create a
registration file.  There are many types of registrations that can
possibly occur, due to the flexibility of the <olink
targetdoc="aggregator"> Aggregator Framework </olink>.  You can view
several examples in the
<filename>$GLOBUS_LOCATION/etc/globus_wsrf_mds_aggregator/example-aggregator-registration.xml</filename>
file.
</para>

<para>
For this example, we'll use a custom registration
<ulink
url="../example-archive-registration.xml">file</ulink>
provided, which is specific to this example, but is easily editable
for your own needs.  The contents of this file are shown below.  After
downloading, open this file for viewing and editing.
<screen>
&lt;?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?&gt;
&lt;ServiceGroupRegistrations
    xmlns="http://mds.globus.org/servicegroup/client"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xmlns:wsa="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/ws/2004/03/addressing"
    xmlns:agg="http://mds.globus.org/aggregator/types"&gt;

&lt;!-- *************** [1] *************** --&gt;
  &lt;defaultServiceGroupEPR&gt;
    &lt;wsa:Address&gt;https://localhost:8443/wsrf/services/ArchiveService&lt;/wsa:Address&gt;
  &lt;/defaultServiceGroupEPR&gt;

  &lt;ServiceGroupRegistrationParameters
      xmlns="http://mds.globus.org/servicegroup/client"
      xmlns:wsa="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/ws/2004/03/addressing"
      xmlns:agg="http://mds.globus.org/aggregator/types"&gt;

&lt;!-- *************** [2] *************** --&gt;
    &lt;RegistrantEPR
        xmlns:wsa="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/ws/2004/03/addressing"&gt;
      &lt;wsa:Address&gt;https://localhost:8443/wsrf/services/DefaultIndexService&lt;/wsa:Address&gt;
    &lt;/RegistrantEPR&gt;

    &lt;RefreshIntervalSecs&gt;600&lt;/RefreshIntervalSecs&gt;
    &lt;Content xsi:type="agg:AggregatorContent"
             xmlns:agg="http://mds.globus.org/aggregator/types"&gt;
      &lt;agg:AggregatorConfig xsi:type="agg:AggregatorConfig"&gt;


&lt;!-- *************** [3] *************** --&gt;
        &lt;agg:GetResourcePropertyPollType 
             xmlns:lifetime="http://docs.oasis-open.org/wsrf/2004/06/wsrf-WS-ResourceLifetime-1.2-draft-01.xsd"&gt;
          &lt;agg:PollIntervalMillis&gt;600000&lt;/agg:PollIntervalMillis&gt;
          &lt;agg:ResourcePropertyName&gt;lifetime:CurrentTime&lt;/agg:ResourcePropertyName&gt;
        &lt;/agg:GetResourcePropertyPollType&gt;
      &lt;/agg:AggregatorConfig&gt;
      &lt;agg:AggregatorData /&gt;
    &lt;/Content&gt;
  &lt;/ServiceGroupRegistrationParameters&gt;
&lt;/ServiceGroupRegistrations&gt;
</screen>
</para>

<para>
A few fields need to be updated in this registration file and they are
indicated by the comment lines [1], [2], and [3].  The comment marked
with [1] is the defaultServiceGroupEPR.  This is the service that will
be contacted by default and in our case should be our running Archive
Service.  Edit this URL to match the Address of the Archive Service
running in the container.
</para>

<para>
The comment marked by [2] is the RegistrantEPR.  This value should be
changed to the Service from which data the desired data should be
retrieved from.  In our example, it's the Default Index Service since
our Archive Service will be pulling data from our Index Service.
</para>

<para>
The comment marked by [3] is the AggregatorConfig block that specifies
how the data should be retrieved from the RegistrantEPR Service.  In
this example, we will be polling periodically every 10 minutes
(which is every 600,000 milliseconds; see below) as specified in the
PollIntervalMillis field.  Also, as you can see below that, the
ResourcePropertyName field is specified as lifetime:CurrentTime.  Note
that the lifetime namespace is qualified near the top if section [3]
in the GetResourcePropertyPollType element declaration.  Modify both
the XML namespace and the RP to suit your needs.  This example will
use the above, since the CurrentTime RP is present in all default
default Index Service instantiations.
</para>

<para>
The other relevant fields in that file that you can configure are the following:
</para>

<para>
<emphasis>RefreshIntervalSeconds</emphasis> - the amount of that time
that should pass before the registration is renewed for you.  600
seconds (i.e. 10 minutes) is generally sufficient, and certainly is
for this example.  (Note: the mds-servicegroup-add utility will
perform these registrations for you automatically at these time
intervals).  This parameter's unit is in seconds.
</para>

<para>
<emphasis>PollIntervalMillis</emphasis> - this is the time interval
that we execute the specified poll action.  It's important to not set
this value too low, as there's little value in having it execute
extremely frequently given the overhead.  For our example, we'll set
it to 10 minutes (i.e. 600000 milliseconds).  This means, the Archive
Service will poll data from the Index Service once every 10 minutes.
This parameter's unit is in milliseconds.
</para>

<para>
If you have not done so already, download the example registration
file, <ulink
url="../example-archive-registration.xml">example-archive-registration.xml</ulink>.
</para>

</section>
   <section><title>Register with the Archive Service: run mds-servicegroup-add</title>
<para>
Finally, to make the registration of the Index Service to the Archive
Service, you need to run the <emphasis>mds-servicegroup-add</emphasis> program in
a similar mannner:
<screen>
neillm@macglob $ $GLOBUS_LOCATION/bin/mds-servicegroup-add -s \
https://localhost:8443/wsrf/servives/ArchiveService example archive-registration.xml                  
Processing configuration file...
INFO: Processed 1 registration entries
INFO: Successfully registered
https://localhost:8443/wsrf/services/DefaultIndexService to
servicegroup at https://localhost:8443/wsrf/services/ArchiveService
</screen>
Note that you will have to specify the proper URI location of your
Index Service on the command line and not the one specified above
(unless it's the same, of course).
</para></section>
</section>

<section id="archive-howto-example"><title>An Example Query (with no results)</title>

<para>
<screen>
neillm@macglob $ ./mds-archive-query -s \
https://localhost:8443/wsrf/services/ArchiveService -q \
"//*[local-name()='CurrentTime']" -from 2007-04-15T013:00:00.000Z -to \
2007-04-16T13:00:00.000Z \
xmlns:myns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/wsrf/2004/06/wsrf-WS-ResourceLifetime-1.2-draft-01.xsd"               
Querying archive...
&lt;ns1:QueryArchiveResponse xmlns:ns1="http://mds.globus.org/archive/2006/08"/&gt;
</screen>
</para>
</section>

<section id="archive-howto-example2"><title>An Example Query (with results)</title>

<para>
<screen>
neillm@macglob $ ./mds-archive-query -s \
https://localhost:8443/wsrf/services/ArchiveService -q \
"//*[local-name()='CurrentTime']" -from 2007-04-15T013:00:00.000Z -to \
2007-04-16T13:00:00.000Z \
xmlns:myns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/wsrf/2004/06/wsrf-WS-ResourceLifetime-1.2-draft-01.xsd"               
Querying archive...
&lt;ns1:QueryArchiveResponse
xmlns:ns1="http://mds.globus.org/archive/2006/08"&gt;&lt;ns1:value
xmlns:ns1="http://www.globus.org/namespaces/2004/06/core"&gt;&lt;item
xsi:type="xsd:anyType" xmlns=""
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"&gt;&lt;ns1:CurrentTime
src:col="/db/archive-service/127.0.0.1.8443.ArchiveService/2007.04.15"
src:key="18.59.49.901"
xmlns:ns1="http://docs.oasis-open.org/wsrf/2004/06/wsrf-WS-ResourceLifetime-1.2-draft-01.xsd"
xmlns:src="http://xml.apache.org/xindice/Query"&gt;2007-04-16T00:59:49.880Z&lt;/ns1:CurrentTime&gt;&lt;/item&gt;&lt;/ns1:value&gt;&lt;/ns1:QueryArchiveResponse&gt;
</screen>
</para>

<para>
This segment of the query output represents the data we've
configured for use, as pulled into the Archive Service from the Index
Service.</para>
</section>

<section id="archive-howto-contact"><title>Contact the author</title>
<para>Contact the author at <ulink url="mailto:neillm@mcs.anl.gov">neillm@mcs.anl.gov</ulink>.</para>
</section>
</chapter>