<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<title>GT &shortversion; MyProxy: System Administrator's Guide</title>
<titleabbrev>System Administrator's Guide</titleabbrev>


<section id="myproxy-admin-introduction"><title>Introduction</title>
<para>
This guide contains advanced configuration information for system administrators
  working with MyProxy. It provides references to information
  on procedures typically performed by system administrators, including installation,
  configuring, deploying, and testing the installation.</para>
  <important>
    <simpara> This information is in addition to the basic Globus Toolkit prerequisite, 
      overview, installation, security configuration instructions in the <xref linkend="gtadmin" />.  
      Read through this guide before continuing!</simpara>  
  </important>
<para>A typical MyProxy configuration has one dedicated myproxy-server for
  the site, with MyProxy clients installed on all systems where other
  Globus Toolkit client software is installed. </para>
</section>

<section id="myproxy-admin-installing"><title>Building and Installing</title>
  <para>MyProxy is built and installed as part of a default GT &shortversion; installation. For
    basic installation instructions, see the <xref linkend="gtadmin" />. No extra installation steps are required
  for this component.</para>

<section id="myproxy-admin-installing-myproxy-only"><title>Building and Installing only MyProxy</title>
<para>If you wish to install MyProxy without installing the rest
  of the Globus Toolkit, follow the instructions in the
  <xref linkend="gtadmin" /> 
  with the following changes.  First, you do not need Ant, a JDK, or a
  JDBC database to build only MyProxy.
  Second, instead of running "make",
  run:
</para>
<screen>globus$ make gsi-myproxy</screen>
<para>
  This will install the MyProxy client and server programs.
  For client-only installations, simply do not configure or use the installed server.
</para>
</section>

</section>
<section id="myproxy-admin-configuring"><title>Configuring </title>
&Cred_Mgmt_MyProxy_Interface_Config_Frag;
</section>

<section id="myproxy-admin-deploying"><title>Deploying</title>
<para>
A sample SysV-style
boot script for MyProxy is installed at
$GLOBUS_LOCATION/share/myproxy/etc.init.d.myproxy.
To install on Linux, copy the file to /etc/rc.d/init.d/myproxy and run
'chkconfig --add myproxy'.
You will need to edit the file to set the GLOBUS_LOCATION environment
variable correctly.
</para>

<para>
Alternatively, to run the myproxy server out of inetd or xinetd, you
need to do the following as root:
</para>
<itemizedlist>
<listitem><simpara>   Add the entries in
       $GLOBUS_LOCATION/share/myproxy/etc.services.modifications to the
       /etc/services or /etc/inet/services file.</simpara></listitem>
 
<listitem><simpara>   Add the entries in
       $GLOBUS_LOCATION/share/myproxy/etc.inetd.conf.modifications to
       /etc/inetd.conf or /etc/inet/inetd.conf, or copy
       $GLOBUS_LOCATION/share/myproxy/etc.xinetd.myproxy to
       /etc/xinetd.d/myproxy.  You'll need to modify the paths in the
       file according to your installation.</simpara></listitem>

<listitem><simpara>   Reactivate the inetd (or xinetd).
       This is typically accomplished by sending the SIGHUP signal to
       the daemon.  Refer to the inetd or xinetd man page for your system.</simpara></listitem>
</itemizedlist>

</section>
<section id="myproxy-admin-testing"><title>Testing</title>

<para>
To verify your myproxy-server installation and configuration, you can
run the myproxy-server directly from your shell.
  If using a <glossterm linkend="host-cert">host certificate</glossterm>, you will need to run the myproxy-server
as root.
First, make sure your Globus environment is setup in your shell.
Set the GLOBUS_LOCATION environment variable to the location of your
MyProxy installation.  
Then, depending on your shell, run one of the following commands.
</para>
<para>
For csh shells:
</para>
<blockquote><para>
<command>source $GLOBUS_LOCATION/etc/globus-user-env.csh</command>
</para></blockquote>
<para>
For sh shells:
</para>
<blockquote><para>
<command>. $GLOBUS_LOCATION/etc/globus-user-env.sh</command>
</para></blockquote>
<para>
Then, run <command>$GLOBUS_LOCATION/sbin/myproxy-server -d</command>.
The <option>-d</option> argument runs the myproxy-server in debug mode.
It will write debugging messages to the terminal and
exit after servicing a single request.
You'll need to start it once for each test request.
In another shell, you can run the MyProxy client programs to test the
server.
</para>

<para>
If run without the <option>-d</option> argument,
the myproxy-server program will start up and background itself.
It accepts connections on TCP port 7512, forking off a separate child
to handle each incoming connection.
It logs information via the syslog service under the daemon facility.
</para>

</section>

<section id="myproxy-admin-security_considerations"><title>Security Considerations </title>
&Cred_Mgmt_MyProxy_Security_Considerations_Frag;
</section>

<section id="myproxy-admin-troubleshooting"><title>Troubleshooting</title>
<para>
	Please refer to <link linkend="myproxy-user-troubleshooting">
		the MyProxy user manual</link>.
</para>
</section>



