<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd"
[

<!ENTITY % myents SYSTEM "../../entities">

%myents;

]>
<section>
<para>The Monitoring and Discovery System (MDS) is a suite of web services to monitor and discover resources and 
  services on Grids. This system allows users to discover what resources are considered part of a Virtual Organization (VO) 
  and to monitor those resources. MDS services provide query and subscription interfaces to arbitrarily detailed resource data 
  and a trigger interface that can be configured to take action when pre-configured trouble conditions are met.</para>
  
  <para>For more information about the information services concepts behind GT4, see <olink targetdoc="infoKey">Information Service: Key Concepts</olink>. </para>
  
<para>GT4&rsquo;s MDS includes:
<itemizedlist>
<listitem><para>WS MDS, the WSRF implementation of MDS, which consists of:
<itemizedlist>
  <listitem> <simpara><olink targetdoc="index">Index Service</olink>, , which collects monitoring and discovery information from 
    Grid resources, and publishes it in a single location.</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara><olink targetdoc="trigger">Trigger Service</olink>, which collects data from resources on the grid and, 
    if administrator defined rules match, can perform various actions.</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara><olink targetdoc="archive">Archive Service</olink>, which archives data from resources on the grid and, 
    allows users to retrieve that data based on XPath queries over specified date ranges.</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara><olink targetdoc="aggregator">Aggregator Framework</olink>, the software framework on which the 
    above WS MDS services are built.</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara><olink targetdoc="webmds">WebMDS</olink>, which enables end users to view monitoring information via 
    a standard web browser interface, without installing any additional software on their PC.</simpara></listitem>
</itemizedlist></para></listitem>
  <!-- 
  <listitem><simpara><olink targetdoc="prewsmds">Pre-WS MDS</olink> (which is now deprecated), the MDS implementation first introduced 
    in GT2.</simpara></listitem>
  -->
</itemizedlist>
</para></section>