<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd"
[

<!ENTITY % myents SYSTEM "../entities">

%myents;

]>
<article>
<title> GT &shortversion; FAQ for WS MDS</title>
<titleabbrev>FAQ for WS-MDS (MDS4)</titleabbrev>
<section id="wsmds-faq-DefaultIndexService"><title>WS-MDS (MDS4) FAQ</title>

<para>
This section is a loose collection of frequently asked questions about
the MDS4.  It includes mostly information about what the MDS4 is and
what Information Services are included in the Globus Toolkit 4+.  The
goal is to have it grow over time with common user questions and for
this to become a frequently used resource.
</para>
  
  <orderedlist>
  <listitem>
    <simpara>Q: What's the difference between Pre-WS MDS, MDS2, WS-MDS, and MDS4?</simpara>
    <simpara>
     A: MDS2 (also known as Pre-WS MDS) was the LDAP based
     monitoring/discovery/information publishing system implementation
     distributed with various Globus Toolkit versions starting with
     GT2.  GT4 also includes a deprecated release of MDS2, but its use
     is generally discouraged due to operational and scalability
     limitations as well as security issues.  WS-MDS (also know as
     MDS4) is the more recent WebService based Monitoring and
     Discovery Service that is fully integrated with the rest of GT4.

     You can view more information about MDS2 and MDS4 (respectively) here:
       <ulink url="http://www.globus.org/toolkit/docs/4.0/info/prewsmds/PreWSMDSFacts.html">http://www.globus.org/toolkit/docs/4.0/info/prewsmds/PreWSMDSFacts.html</ulink>
       and <ulink url="http://www.globus.org/toolkit/docs/4.0/info/">http://www.globus.org/toolkit/docs/4.0/info/</ulink>
    </simpara>
  </listitem>


  <listitem>
    <simpara>Q: What is the MDS4 Index Service?</simpara>
    <simpara>
     A: The Index Service collects monitoring and discovery
     information from Grid resources, and publishes it in a single
     location; generally, it is expected that a virtual organization
     will deploy one or more index services which will collect data on
     all of the Grid resources available within that virtual
     organization.  Read more information about it here:
     <ulink url="http://www.globus.org/toolkit/docs/4.0/info/index/">http://www.globus.org/toolkit/docs/4.0/info/index/</ulink>
    </simpara>
  </listitem>


  <listitem>
    <simpara>Q: What is the MDS4 Trigger Service?</simpara>
    <simpara>
     A: The Trigger Service collects data from resources on the grid
     and, if administrator defined rules match, can perform various
     actions. An example use is to send email when queue length on a
     compute resource goes over a threshold value.  Read more
     information about it here:
     <ulink url="http://www.globus.org/toolkit/docs/4.0/info/trigger/">http://www.globus.org/toolkit/docs/4.0/info/trigger/</ulink>
    </simpara>
  </listitem>


  <listitem>
    <simpara>Q: How do I query the MDS4 Index?</simpara>
    <simpara>
     A: There are a number of ways to access the information in the
     Index Service.  The most common is using the command line tools
     described here:

     <ulink url="http://www.globus.org/toolkit/docs/4.0/info/index/user-index.html">http://www.globus.org/toolkit/docs/4.0/info/index/user-index.html</ulink>

     Some common queries are also described here:

     <ulink url="http://www-unix.mcs.anl.gov/~robertm/xpath-queries.html">http://www-unix.mcs.anl.gov/~robertm/xpath-queries.html</ulink>

     You can also access the information programmatically using the
     Java based API

     See <ulink
     url="http://www.globus.org/api/javadoc-4.0/globus_java_ws_core/org/globus/wsrf/query/package-tree.html">http://www.globus.org/api/javadoc-4.0/globus_java_ws_core/org/globus/wsrf/query/package-tree.html</ulink>
     for some more detail.
    </simpara>
  </listitem>


  <listitem>
    <simpara>Q: I've already installed Ganglia/Hawkeye, but it isn't
    showing up in the MDS4 Index when I start it.  How do I configure
    the Index so that the Ganglia or Hawkeye data is in it?</simpara>
    <simpara>
     A: Read how to configure either of these here:
     <ulink url="http://globus.org/toolkit/docs/4.0/info/key/gluerp.html">http://globus.org/toolkit/docs/4.0/info/key/gluerp.html</ulink>
    </simpara>
  </listitem>


  <listitem>
    <simpara>Q: NEXT QUESTION?</simpara>
    <simpara>
     A: ANSWER ME!
    </simpara>
  </listitem>


  </orderedlist>
  
</section>




</article>