<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<para>No OGSA-DAI <emphasis>WSRF-specific</emphasis> changes have been made for this release.</para>
    
    <para>The following general OGSA-DAI changes have been made for this release:</para>
    
<itemizedlist>
    <listitem><simpara>Core OGSA-DAI functionality (the engine and data resource connection classes) has been abstracted out into a service-level independent module. OGSA-DAI OGSI, WSI and WSRF share exactly the same core code. Core OGSA-DAI functionality and activities are now Globus-independent.</simpara></listitem>
    <listitem><simpara>The namespaces of OGSA-DAI configuration, Perform and Response documents have been completely changed:</simpara>
    <itemizedlist>
        <listitem><simpara>Perform and response documents are now declared within the http://ogsadai.org.uk/namespaces/2005/03/types namespace.</simpara></listitem>
         <listitem><simpara>Data resource and activity configuration documents and roleMap documents are now declared within the http://ogsadai.org.uk/namespaces/2005/03/config namespace.</simpara></listitem>
    </itemizedlist></listitem>
    <listitem><simpara>The deliverToStream activity now delivers to a URL of form http://HOST:PORT/WEBAPP/servlet/DeliverToStreamServlet?url=http://HOST:PORT/WEBAPP/ogsadai/DataService&amp;streamId=NAME - gsh has been renamed to url.</simpara></listitem>
    <listitem><simpara>Control flow constraints can now be expressed within Perform documents. This means you can ensure that one activity will not start until another has completed e.g. ensuring that a new table is not filled with data until it has been created.</simpara></listitem>
    <listitem><simpara>Server-side exceptions outwith client control and authorisation failures have been refactored. The problems are logged in detail server-side and tagged with a unique ID. This ID, with a request to contract the service deployer, is returned to the client.</simpara></listitem>
    <listitem><simpara>All OGSA-DAI data services now provide a getVersion operation which returns the OGSA-DAI flavour and version number.</simpara></listitem>
    <listitem><simpara>GUI installation tools now allow required JARs to be selected via a file browser.</simpara></listitem>
    <listitem><simpara>GUI installation tools now render yes/no options as check boxes.</simpara></listitem></itemizedlist>
    

