<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<para>This section includes information for versions 2.0 and 2.1 of OGSA-DAI WSRF which is distributed with GT 4.0.2 
    (the GT4.0.1 release contained version 1.0 of the OGSA-DAI WSRF distribution). [TODO: update for changes since GT 4.0.2]</para>
    
<itemizedlist>
    <listitem>The documentation bundled with the OGSA-DAI distribution explicitly mentions GT4.0.1. Everything will work fine with GT4.0.2 too.</listitem>
    <listitem>The canonical documentation for the OGSA-DAI 2.1 release is contained in the release documentation so please use this for installation and usage.</listitem>
</itemizedlist>


  <section>  <title>Release 2.1</title>
    
    <para>OGSA-DAI WSRF 2.1 is a WSRF-compliant version of OGSA-DAI and runs upon Globus Toolkit 4.0.2. It is not compatible with Globus Toolkit 3. 
    The source release should still be compatible with Globus Toolkit 4.0. The main changes between this and the previous release are as follows:</para>
    
    <para>OGSA-DAI WSRF 2.1 is almost identical to OGSA-DAI WSRF 2.0 which was released just one week earlier. This release was motivated by:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>A need to allow data resource accessors to be notified whenever a session is terminated, so that session-related resource properties can be removed.</listitem>
    <listitem>A bug fix to ensure that a single block of data can flow through a pipeline containing an inputStream activity and an outputStream activity.</listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
      
    <para>If you have OGSA-DAI WSRF 2.0 and were not dependent on or concerned by these then there is no requirement for you to upgrade.</para>
    
<para>The additions / changes were as follows:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>In core/src/java/:
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>Changed uk.org.ogsadai.activity.ActivityRequest</listitem>
                <listitem>Changed uk.org.ogsadai.activity.CallThroughExternalPipe</listitem>
                <listitem>Changed uk.org.ogsadai.activity.CallThroughPipe</listitem>
                <listitem>Changed uk.org.ogsadai.service.resource.DataServiceResource</listitem>
                <listitem>Changed uk.org.ogsadai.sessions.SessionManagerFactory</listitem>
                <listitem>Changed uk.org.ogsadai.sessions.SessionConfigurationLoader</listitem>
                <listitem>Changed uk.org.ogsadai.sessions.impl.SessionConfiguration</listitem>
                <listitem>Changed uk.org.ogsadai.sessions.impl.TransientSessionManager</listitem>
                <listitem>Changed uk.org.ogsadai.sessions.impl.TransientSessionManagerFactory</listitem>
                <listitem>Added uk.org.ogsadai.dataresource.DataResourceListener</listitem>
                <listitem>Added uk.org.ogsadai.dataresource.DataResourceEvent</listitem>
                <listitem>Added uk.org.ogsadai.dataresource.DataResourceEventDispatcher</listitem>
                <listitem>Added uk.org.ogsadai.dataresource.TestDataResource</listitem>
                <listitem>Added uk.org.ogsadai.sessions.impl.TransientSessionConfiguration</listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </listitem>
    
    <listitem>In doc:
    <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>Changed tutorials/dataresource/howTo.html</listitem>
        <listitem>Changed clients/clienttoolkit/ObtainingMetaData.html</listitem>
        <listitem>Changed misc/HowToUpgrade.html</listitem>
        <listitem>Changed misc/KnownProblems.html</listitem>
        <listitem>Changed clients/clienttoolkit/index.html</listitem>
        <listitem>Changed clients/clienttoolkit/SecureServices.html</listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
  </section>
  <section><title>Release 2.0</title>
    
    <para>OGSA-DAI WSRF 2.0 is a WSRF-compliant version of OGSA-DAI and runs upon Globus Toolkit 4.0.1. It is not compatible with Globus Toolkit 3. The source release should still be compatible with Globus Toolkit 4.0.</para>
    
    <para>The major features of this release are as follows:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>OGSA-DAI WSRF 2.0 is compatible with Globus Toolkit 4.0.2 and the should still work with Globus Toolkit 4.0 (if you have the OGSA-DAI WSRF 2.0 binary distribution you'll need to get the source distribution and compile against Globus Toolkit 4.0).</listitem>
    <listitem>Data service resources support concurrent request execution and queueing of requests.</listitem>
    <listitem>All data service resources exposed by a specific service share the same settings for the number of concurrent requests that can be executed and the number that can be queued. These are specified at service deployment time.</listitem>
    <listitem>Sessions are now supported. Multiple perform documents can be submitted which operate within the context of the same session. State can be stored in session attributes. Data transport operations now operate within the scope of a session.</listitem>
    <listitem>Data service accessors have been provided. These manage access to a data resource on behalf of a data service resource. They each have their own specific configuration files.</listitem>
    <listitem>Configurable data services provide an undeploy operation so that a service can be instructed to no longer expose a specific data service resource. This is reflected in the client toolkit.</listitem>
    <listitem>There have been numerous performance improvements most notably in the refactoring of our java.sql.ResultSet to WebRowSet converters.</listitem>
    <listitem>Client and server-side now support transport-level security between clients and services.</listitem>
    <listitem>Client and server-side now support message-level security between clients and services.</listitem>
    <listitem>Services can be configured to register themselves with a Globus MDS Index service running in the same container.</listitem>
    <listitem>The OGSA-DAI data browser is now compatible with both OGSA-DAI WSRF 2.0 and OGSA-DAI WSI 2.0 services.</listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
      
    <para>The main changes between this and the previous release are as follows:</para>
    
 <itemizedlist>  
     <listitem>The date in all OGSA-DAI XML Schema namespaces have been updated i.e.:
    
    <filename>http://ogsadai.org.uk/namespaces/2005/03/...</filename>
    
    has been updated to:
    
    <filename>http://ogsadai.org.uk/namespaces/2005/10/...</filename>
     </listitem>
     
    <listitem>Data service resources now have a:
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>data resource class configuration file which specifies the data resource accessor to use.</listitem>
            <listitem>session configuration file which specifies the maximum and default timeouts for sessions.</listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>Files data service resources no longer have associated role map documents.</listitem>
    <listitem>Data resource configuration files dataResource element no longer has the implementation attribute.</listitem>
    <listitem>Data resource configuration files for file data resources now have a new XML Schema. This is in schema/ogsadai/xsd/data_resource_config_files.xsd. The main changes are:
        <itemizedlist>o The driver element has been replaced by a rootDirectory element.
            <listitem>The rolemap is no longer needed.</listitem>
            <listitem>The productInfo is no longer needed.</listitem></itemizedlist></listitem>
    <listitem>Service interfaces have been completely refactored.
    <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>A terminate operation has been added. This is a placeholder and currently does nothing. It will be used to support request termination in future releases.</listitem>
    <listitem>The updateRoleMaps operation for configurable data services no longer exists.</listitem>
    <listitem>All OGSA-DAI-specific service operations throw one of five new fault types. The client toolkit has been completely refactored to reflect these fault types as Java exceptions.</listitem>
    </itemizedlist></listitem>
    <listitem>SQL activities no longer implicitly convert java.sql.ResultSets to WebRowSet. A new activity - sqlResultsToXML - has been provided to make this explicit. Whereas in previous releases you would use a sqlQueryStatement activity, for example, you now use a sqlQueryStatement activity connected to a sqlResultsToXML activity.</listitem>
    <listitem>Encrypted role map files are no longer supported and ogsadai-startup-tomcat.jar is no longer provided.</listitem>
    <listitem>OGSA-DAI tutorial examples are compiled as part of a source distribution build and are distributed within ogsadai-examples.jar.</listitem>
    <listitem>The Client Toolkit APIs have been modified to support sessions and concurrency. Some methods such as the poll method are now parameterised with a SessionID object. A user may attach session requirements to an ActivityRequest before performing it.</listitem>
    <listitem>The request status resource property available in previous versions is no longer available. Instead a session request status resource property is created dynamically whenever a new session is created. This indicates the processing status of the request that is currently joined to the session.</listitem>
 </itemizedlist>   
    
</section>
