<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<para>The following are points to consider relative to security:</para>
<section ><title>Two ways to configure your <glossterm>server</glossterm></title>
<para>We now provide two ways to configuring your server:</para>
<itemizedlist>    
	<listitem><simpara>The classic installation.  This is equivalent to any FTP server you would normally install.  
    It is run as a root setuid process.  Once the user is authenticated, the process does a setuid to the 
    appropriate non-privileged user account.</simpara></listitem>
<listitem><para>A new split process installation.  In this configuration, the server consists of two processes:
<itemizedlist>    
	<listitem><simpara>The control channel (the process the external user connects to) runs as a non-privileged user (typically 
			the globus user).  </simpara></listitem>
    
	<listitem><simpara> The data channel (the process that access the file system and moves the data) runs 
    as a root setuid program as before but is only contacted by the control channel process from a local machine.  
    This means an external user is never connected to a root running process and thus minimizes the impact of 
    an exploit.  This does, however, require that a copy of the host cert and host key be owned by the non-privileged 
    user.      If you use this configuration, the non-privileged user should not have write permission to executables, 
    configuration files, etc.</simpara></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
</para>
</listitem>
</itemizedlist>
</section>
<section ><title>New authentication options</title>
    <para>There are new authentication options available for the server in GT &shortversion;:</para>
<itemizedlist>
    <listitem><simpara>Anonymous:  The server now supports anonymous access.  In order for this to work, a configuration switch must explicitly enable it, a list of acceptable usernames must be defined, and an account under which the anonymous user should run must be defined.  If the necessary configurations are in place, and the <glossterm>client</glossterm> presents a username that is in the list of acceptable anonymous users, then the session will be accepted and the process will setuid to the anonymous user account.  We do not support chroot in this version of the server.</simpara></listitem>

	<listitem><simpara>Username / Password:  This is standard FTP authentication.  It uses a separate password file, used only by the GridFTP server, *NOT* the system password file.</simpara></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
    
<warning><simpara>WE HIGHLY RECOMMEND YOU NOT USE THIS.  YOU WILL BE SENDING YOUR PASSWORD IN CLEAR 
    TEXT OVER THE NETWORK.</simpara></warning>

<para>We do, however, have some user communities who run only on internal networks for testing purposes and who do not wish to deal with obtaining GSI credentials.  If you are considering this, we would recommend that you look at Simple CA and set up your own testbed CA.  This can be done in less than an hour and then provides you full GSI security.</para>
</section>




