<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">

<section id="rls-security-considerations">
  <title>Replica Location Service (RLS) Security Considerations</title>
  <para>Security recommendations include: <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <simpara><emphasis>Dedicated User Account:</emphasis> It is recommended that users create a
          dedicated user account for installing and running the RLS service (e.g.,
            <computeroutput>globus</computeroutput> as recommended in the general GT installation
          instructions). This account may be used to install and run other services from the Globus
          Toolkit.</simpara>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <simpara><emphasis>Key and Certificate:</emphasis> It is recommended that users do not use
          their hostkey and hostcert for use by the RLS service. Create a containerkey and
          containercert with permissions <computeroutput>400</computeroutput> and
            <computeroutput>644</computeroutput> respectively and owned by the
            <computeroutput>globus</computeroutput> user. Change the
          <computeroutput>rlskeyfile</computeroutput> and
          <computeroutput>rlscertfile</computeroutput> settings in the RLS configuration file
            (<filename>$GLOBUS_LOCATION/etc/globus-rls-server.conf</filename>) to reflect the
          appropriate filenames.</simpara>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <simpara><emphasis><glossterm baseform="Local Replica Catalog (LRC)">LRC</glossterm> and
              <glossterm baseform="Replica Location Index">RLI</glossterm> Databases:</emphasis>
          Users must ensure security of the RLS data as maintained by their chosen database
          management system. Appropriate precautions should be made to protect the data and access
          to the database. Such precautions may include creating a user account specifically for RLS
          usage, encrypting database users' passwords, etc.</simpara>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <simpara><emphasis>RLS Configuration:</emphasis> It is recommended that the RLS
          configuration file (<filename>$GLOBUS_LOCATION/etc/globus-rls-server.conf</filename>) be
          owned by and accessible only by the dedicated user account for RLS (e.g.,
            <computeroutput>globus</computeroutput> account per above recommendations). The file
          contains the database user account and password used to access the LRC and RLI databases
          along with important settings which, if tampered with, could adversely affect the RLS
          service.</simpara>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </para>
</section>
