<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE para PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">

<para>OGSA-DAI provides a pure Java data service framework for accessing and integrating data resources - 
    such as files, relational and XML databases - on to Grids. Towards this end, OGSA-DAI:
<itemizedlist>
    <listitem><simpara>Exposes intrinsic data resource capabilities - such as the ability to perform SQL queries on relational resources or evaluate XPath statements on XML collections - through web service based interfaces, thus allowing data resources to be easily incorporated as first class citizens in grids.</simpara></listitem>
 <listitem><simpara>Allows additional functionality to be implemented at the service - such as transformation of data coming out of a data resource - so as to avoid unnecessary data movement.</simpara></listitem>
 <listitem><simpara>Provides a compact way of handling multiple potential interactions with a service within a single request via an XML document, called a perform document, where data is pipelined between different set of activities that operate on a data stream coming out of, or going into, a data resource.</simpara></listitem>
 <listitem><simpara>Allows developers to easily add or extend functionality within OGSA-DAI. The perform document, and underlying framework, are extensible allowing additional functionality to be added, or existing functionality to be customised, and still operate within the same framework.</simpara></listitem>
 <listitem><simpara>Allows metadata about data and the data resources in which it is found to be queried via a service interface.</simpara></listitem>
 <listitem><simpara>Facilitates the provision of data integration capabilities from various sources to obtain the required information.</simpara></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
 
This WS-RF distribution of OGSA-DAI has been designed to work with the Globus Toolkit 4 implementation of WS-RF; 
 a WS-I distribution is also available from the OGSA-DAI web site, which is designed to work with the UK OMII web 
 services infrastructure releases. Finally, an OGSI-based distribution of OGSA-DAI, designed to work with the GT3.2 
 releases, is also available from the project web site. Note: these releases are not designed to inter-operate. More 
 information about these and OGSA-DAI in general is available from the project website at <ulink url="http://www.ogsadai.org.uk">http://www.ogsadai.org.uk</ulink>.</para> 