<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">

<section id="rft-recovery-introduction">
    <title> RFT fault-tolerance and recovery </title>
    <para> RFT uses PostgreSQL to check-point transfer state in the form of restart markers and
        recover from transient transfer failures, using retry mechanism with exponential backoff,
        during a transfer. RFT has been tested to recover from source and/or destination server
        crashes during a transfer, network failures, container failures (when the machine running
        the container goes down), file system failures, etc. RFT Resource is implemented as a
        PersistentResource, so ReliableFileTransferHome gets initialized every time a container gets
        restarted. Please find a more detailed description of fault-tolerance and recovery in RFT
        below: <itemizedlist>

            <listitem>
                <simpara>Source and/or destination GridFTP failures: In this case RFT retries the
                    transfer for a configurable number of maximum attempts with exponential backoff
                    for each retry (the backoff time period is configurable also). If a failure
                    happens in the midst of a transfer, RFT uses the last restart marker that is
                    stored in the database for that transfer and uses it to resume the transfer from
                    the point where it failed, instead of restarting the whole file. This failure is
                    treated as a container-wide backoff for the server in question. What this means
                    is that all other transfers going to/from that server, across all the requests
                    in a container, will be backed off and retried. This is done in order to prevent
                    further failures of the transfers by using knowledge available in the
                database.</simpara>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
                <simpara>Network failures: Sometimes this happens due to heavy load on a network or
                    for any other reason packets are lost or connections get timed out. This failure
                    is considered a transient failure and RFT retries the transfer with exponential
                    backoff for that particular transfer (and not the whole container, as with the
                    source and/or destination GridFTP failures).</simpara>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
                <simpara>Container failures: These type of failures occur when the machine running
                    the container goes down or if the container is restarted with active transfers.
                    When the container is restarted, it restarts ReliableTransferHome, which looks
                    at the database for any active RFT resources and restarts them.</simpara>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </para>
    <section id="rft-recovery-unaddressed">
        <title>Failure modes that are not addressed: </title>
        <para>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <simpara>Running out of disk space for the database.</simpara>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </para>
    </section>
</section>
