<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE itemizedlist PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd"
[

<!ENTITY % myents SYSTEM "../../entities">

%myents;

]>

<itemizedlist>
    <listitem><simpara><computeroutput>OverallStatus</computeroutput>: This is a complex type providing the overall status of an RFT resource by providing the number of transfers pending, active, finished, retrying, failed, and cancelled. Each of these values can be obtained by invoking getTransfers(Finished/Active/Failed/Restarted/Pending/Cancelled) on OverallStatus Resource Property. Note that this Resource Property gets updated every time one of the transfers changes state, so there can be and will be more than one update in the life time of a RFT resource if you subscribe to this RP. This Resource Property also includes the last fault (if thrown) from a transfer and can be accessed by invoking getFault on OverallStatus. This will indicate why a transfer has failed.</simpara></listitem>
    <listitem><simpara><computeroutput>RequestStatus</computeroutput>: This is a complex type resource property providing the status of an RFT resource in the form of Pending/Active/Done/Failed. The status can be obtained from RequestStatusType by invoking getRequestStatus(). This will result in one of four status strings (Pending/Active/Done/Failed/Cancelled). This RP also contains a fault that denotes the last fault in a RFT resource and can be accessed by invoking getFault(). If a client is subscribed to this RP, there will be only be 2 updates in the life time of an RFT resource (Pending->Active->Done, Pending->Active->Failed, Pending->Active->Cancelled, and Pending->Cancelled).</simpara></listitem>
    <listitem><simpara><computeroutput>TotalBytes</computeroutput>: This provides the total number of bytes transferred by the resource.</simpara></listitem>
    <listitem><simpara><computeroutput>TotalTime</computeroutput>: This provides the total time taken to transfer the above-mentioned total bytes.</simpara></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
