<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">

  <chapter id="gram5-migrating-gt3">
    <title>Migrating GRAM from GT3</title>
        <indexterm type="gram5"><primary>migrating</primary><secondary>from 3.2.x</secondary></indexterm>
<para>Migrating to GT <replaceable role="entity">version</replaceable> from GT version 3.2:</para>

<itemizedlist>
      <listitem><simpara>The <replaceable role="entity">version</replaceable> protocol has been changed to be WSRF compliant.  There is no backward compatibility between <replaceable role="entity">version</replaceable> and 3.2.</simpara></listitem>
</itemizedlist>

<para>API changes since GT 3.2:</para>
<itemizedlist>
      <listitem><simpara>The <glossterm baseform="Managed Job Factory Service">MJFS</glossterm> <computeroutput>create</computeroutput> operation has become
    <computeroutput>createManagedJob</computeroutput> and, now provides the option to send a
            <glossterm baseform="Universally Unique Identifier">uuid</glossterm>. A client can use this uuid to recover a job EPR
    in the event that the reply message is not received. Given this new scheme,
    the <computeroutput>start</computeroutput> operation was removed. The createManagedJob()
    operation also allows a notification subscription request to be specified.
    This is the only way to reliably get all job state notifications.</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara>The MJS <computeroutput>start</computeroutput> operation has been removed.  Its purpose was
    to ensure that the client had received the job EPR prior to the job being
    executed (and thus consuming resources), and is redundant with the uuid
    functionality.</simpara></listitem>
</itemizedlist>


<para>New GRAM Client Submission Tool: </para>
<itemizedlist>
  <listitem>
	<simpara>
	      <glossterm>globusrun-ws</glossterm> has replaced managed-job-globusrun as the GRAM5 client submission program.  The main reason was performance.  The cost of JVM startup for each job submission through <command>managed-job-globusrun</command> was too much.  <command>globusrun-ws</command> is written in C and thus avoids the JVM startup cost.  <command>globusrun-ws</command> is very similar in functionality to <command>managed-job-globusrun</command>, but you will need to become familiar with the arguments and options.
	</simpara>
  </listitem>
 </itemizedlist>

<para><glossterm baseform="Resource Specification Language">RSL</glossterm> Schema Changes Since GT 3.2: </para>
<itemizedlist>
  <listitem><simpara>RSL Substitutions
        RSL substitution syntax has changed to allow for a simpler RSL schema that can be parsed by standard tools.  In GT 3.2, applications could define arbitrary RSL substitutions within an RSL document and rely on the GRAM service to resolve them.  In GT5 GRAM5, this feature is no longer present.  In GT <replaceable role="entity">version</replaceable> there are 5 RSL variables:
        ${GLOBUS_USER_HOME}, ${GLOBUS_USER_NAME}, ${GLOBUS_SCRATCH_DIR}, and ${GLOBUS_LOCATION}.</simpara></listitem>
        <!--
        ${GLOBUS_JOB_ID}, ${GLOBUS_USER_HOME}, ${GLOBUS_USER_NAME}, ${GLOBUS_SCRATCH_DIR}, and ${GLOBUS_LOCATION}.</simpara></listitem>
        -->
  <listitem><simpara>executable
        is now a single local file path. Remote URLs are no longer allowed.
        If executable staging is desired, it should be added to the
        fileStageIn directive.</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara>stdin
        is now a single local file path. Remote URLs are no longer allowed.
        If stdin staging is desired, it should be added to the fileStageIn
        directive.</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara>stdout
        is now a single local file path, instead of a list of remote URLs. If
        stdout staging is desired, it should be added to the fileStageOut
        directive.</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara>stderr
        is now a single local file path, instead of a list of remote URLs. If
        stderr staging is desired, it should be added to the fileStageOut
        directive.</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara>scratchDirectory
        has been removed.</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara>gramMyJobType
        has been removed.  &quot;Collective&quot; functionality
        is always available if a job chooses to use it.</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara>dryRun
        has been removed. This is obsolete given the addition of the holdState
        attribute.  setting holdState to "StageIn" should prevent the job from
        being submitted to the local <glossterm>scheduler</glossterm>.  It can then be canceled
        once the StageIn-Hold state notification is received.</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara>remoteIoUrl
        has been removed.  This was a hack for GRAM2 involved with staging
        via GASS, and has no relevancy in the current implementation.</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara>File Staging related RSL
        attributes have been replaced with RFT file transfer
        attributes/syntax.</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara>RSL substitution definitions and substitution references
        have been removed in order to be able to use standard XML
        parsing/serialization tools.</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara>RSL variables
        have been added. These are keywords denoted in the form of
        ${variable name} that can be found in certain RSL attributes.</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara>Explicit credential references
        have been added, which, along with use of the
        new DelegationFactory service, replace the old implicit delegation
        model.</simpara></listitem>
</itemizedlist>


<para>Fault changes since GT version 3.2:</para>
<itemizedlist>
  <listitem><simpara>CacheFaultType
        was removed since there is no longer a GASS cache.</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara>RepeatedlyStartedFaultType
        was removed since there is no longer a <computeroutput>start</computeroutput> operation.
        Repeat creates with the same submission ID simply return the job
        EPR.</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara>SLAFaultType
        was changed to ServiceLevelAgreementFaultType for clarification.</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara>StreamServiceCreationFaultType
        was removed since there is no longer a stream service.</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara>UnresolvedSubstitutionReferencesFaultType
        was removed since there is no longer support for substitution
        definitions and references in the RSL.</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara>DatabaseAccessFaultType
        was removed since a database is no longer used to save job data.</simpara></listitem>
</itemizedlist>

</chapter>