<para>Features new in release Globus Toolkit 4.0 </para>
<itemizedlist>
  <listitem><simpara> Access to data is provided via an "OGSA-DAI data service". For those that
    have previously used the OGSI version of OGSA-DAI, this service amalgamates
    the capabilities of the <emphasis>Grid Data Service Factory</emphasis> (GDSF) and <emphasis>Grid
    Data Service</emphasis> (GDS) services (the metadata and configuration roles of
    the GDSF and the metadata and perform document processing aspects of the
    GDS). </simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara> Allows multiple data resources to be accessed through a single service.
    Data resource identifiers, available from the data service's WS-Addressing
    endpoint reference, allow a client to target a specific data resource. </simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara> A <emphasis>listResources()</emphasis> operation is provided for a data service to
    list all the identifiers of the data resources exposed by that service. </simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara> The data resource identifiers returned by a data service can subsequently
    be used by a client to obtain metadata and other information, about the data
    resources corresponding to that identifier. </simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara> Access to service metadata (such as database schemas, request status,
    etc.) is provided by an implementation of the <emphasis>WS-ResourceProperties</emphasis> specification.
    In particular support for using the <emphasis>QueryResourceProperties</emphasis>,<emphasis> GetResourceProperties</emphasis> and <emphasis>GetMultipleResourceProperties</emphasis> portTypes
    is provided. </simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara> Access to version information about the OGSA-DAI Data Service is available
    through the <emphasis>getVersion()</emphasis> operation. </simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara> A WSRF version of the OGSA-DAI <emphasis>GridDataTransport</emphasis> portType supports
    asynchronous data delivery between data services. </simpara></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
<para> Features that continue to be supported from previous versions: </para>
<itemizedlist>
  <listitem><simpara>Perform documents.</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara>Extensible activity framework.</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara>Statement, delivery and transformation activities.</simpara></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
<para>Other Supported Features</para>
<itemizedlist>
  <listitem><simpara>n/a</simpara></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
<para>Deprecated Features</para>
<itemizedlist>
  <listitem><simpara> The OGSA-DAI Client Toolkit has not been updated yet to support interaction
    with WSRF-enabled OGSA-DAI services. This will be made available in a future
    version. </simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara> The OGSA-DAI registry service, DAISGR, has not been updated for WS-RF.
    This will be addressed in a future version or provided via a third party
    component. </simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara> The old graphical demonstrator no longer works with this version of OGSA-DAI. </simpara></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
