<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd"
[

<!ENTITY % xinclude SYSTEM "../../xinclude.mod" >
%xinclude;

]>
    <section id="ogsadai-knownproblems">
        <title>Known Problems</title>
<para>The following problems are known to exist for OGSA-DAI at the time of the 4.0.1 release:</para>
<section><title>Limitations</title>
<itemizedlist>
<listitem><simpara><emphasis>Problems retrieving BLOBS</emphasis></simpara>

<para>When trying to retrieve BLOBs from a
        relational database you will get zero rows returned (or an error). The
        following error message will be logged:
    <screen>Base64Provider has not been set up with a Base64 implementation</screen></para>
        
<para>This will be fixed in the next release. In the meantime if you have
        the source version of the release, you can correct this bug by
        changing two files and rebuilding OGSA-DAI. 
    See <olink targetdoc="ogsadaiDeveloper" targetptr="ogsadai-blob-error-workaround">BLOB Error Workaround</olink> for details.</para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<simpara><emphasis>DeliverToStream activity is broken.</emphasis></simpara>
    
    <simpara>The DeliverToStream activity has a bug in the WSRF implementation. The
    service URL passed to the servlet is 'null' rather than the correct
    URL.</simpara>
    
    <simpara>Thus where the documentation says the data will be available from a
    URL of the form:</simpara>
    
<simpara><filename>http://host:port/ogsa/servlet/DeliverToStreamServlet?url=</filename>
    <filename>http://host:port/ogsa/ogsadai/DataService&amp;streamId=NAME</filename></simpara>
    
    <simpara>It will actually be available from a URL in the form:</simpara>
    
    <simpara><filename>http://host:port/ogsa/servlet/DeliverToStreamServlet?url=null&amp;streamId=NAME</filename></simpara>
    
   <simpara> This will be fixed for the next release.</simpara>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<simpara><emphasis>Client toolkit asynchronous result set broken.</emphasis></simpara>
   
   <simpara>The ResultSet object returned by the OutputStreamActivity class'
   getResultSet methods do not work for WSRF 1.0. This is because the
   code attempts to use the getNBlocks service operation which is not
   implemented in WSRF 1.0. This will be fixed in our next release.</simpara>
   
  <simpara> There are two possible work arounds to this problem:</simpara>
   
<orderedlist>
    <listitem><simpara>Use synchronous delivery. The ResultSet returned by the SQLQuery
        activity's getResultSet() method does work.</simpara></listitem>
   
   <listitem><simpara> Alter the client toolkit code to use the
   getBlock() service operation. Unfortunately this option will be
   very slow as only one row will be retrieved at a time.</simpara></listitem>
   </orderedlist>
   </listitem>
</itemizedlist>
</section>

      <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="OGSA_DAI_Known_Bugs_Frag.xml"
         />
 </section>