<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">

  <section id="ogsadai-features"><title>Feature summary</title>
<para>Features new in release GT <replaceable role="entity">version</replaceable>: </para>
<itemizedlist>
  <listitem><simpara>Access to data is provided via an "OGSA-DAI data service". For those that have previously used the OGSI version of OGSA-DAI, this service amalgamates the capabilities of the Grid Data Service Factory (GDSF) and Grid Data Service (GDS) services (the metadata and configuration roles of the GDSF and the metadata and perform document processing aspects of the GDS).</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara>Each data service exposes zero or more data service resources. A data service resource manages exposure of and interaction with a data resource. A single data service resource can be viewed as offering capabilities analogous to a single GDS in the OGSI version of OGSA-DAI.</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara>Allows multiple data resources to be accessed through a single service. Data service resource identifiers, available from the data service's WS-Addressing endpoint reference, allow a client to target a specific data service resource.</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara>A listResources() operation is provided for a data service to list all the identifiers of the data service resources exposed by that service.</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara>The data service resource identifiers returned by a data service can subsequently be used by a client to obtain metadata and other information, about the data service resources corresponding to that identifier.</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara>Access to data service resource metadata (such as database schemas, request status, etc.) is provided by an implementation of the WS-ResourceProperties specification. In particular support for using the QueryResourceProperties, GetResourceProperties and GetMultipleResourceProperties portTypes is provided.</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara>Access to version information about the OGSA-DAI Data Service is available through the getVersion() operation.</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara>A WSRF version of the OGSA-DAI GridDataTransport portType supports asynchronous data delivery between data services.</simpara></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
<para>Other Supported Features (features that continue to be supported from previous versions):</para>
<itemizedlist>
  <listitem><simpara>Perform documents.</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara>Extensible activity framework.</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara>Statement, delivery and transformation activities.</simpara></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
<para>Deprecated Features</para>
<itemizedlist>
  <listitem><simpara>The OGSA-DAI Client Toolkit has not been updated yet to support interaction with WSRF-enabled OGSA-DAI services. This will be made available in a future version.</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara>The OGSA-DAI registry service, DAISGR, has not been updated for WSRF. This will be addressed in a future version or provided via a third party component.</simpara></listitem>
  <listitem><simpara>The old graphical demonstrator no longer works with this version of OGSA-DAI.</simpara></listitem>
</itemizedlist>

    </section>